[
  {
    "id": "66ecff43-bf0a-481c-b5da-db3ca64fed39",
    "front": "**Def**: put your name on an official list (enrol = register to join a course, school, etc.).\n**Farsi**: ثبت نام کردن",
    "back": "register (at/for/with sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "5480e495-ac93-4216-9da9-b9122bbef543",
    "front": "نفرت‌انگیز",
    "back": "Abomination \nCruelty to animals is an abomination"
  },
  {
    "id": "58821cf8-9e6a-4082-a59e-4a8465604121",
    "front": "**Def**: An expression of sympathy (formal).\n**Farsi**: تسلیت، همدردی",
    "back": "condolences"
  },
  {
    "id": "03567875-85a3-4f8a-bd74-1c239b159a9f",
    "front": "**Def**: To ask for information (formal).\n**Farsi**: استعلام کردن، پرسیدن",
    "back": "enquire"
  },
  {
    "id": "95c2de90-e4fa-4187-b05b-8cbaeadfcc0b",
    "front": "**Def**: in the process of being discussed.\n**Farsi**: در دست بحث",
    "back": "under discussion"
  },
  {
    "id": "e6547f2a-13cb-433a-922a-3d302798dffb",
    "front": "**Def**: If you need more details (formal opening phrase).\n**Farsi**: چنانچه به اطلاعات بیشتری نیاز دارید (رسمی)",
    "back": "Should you require further information"
  },
  {
    "id": "865aa7d2-a455-46fa-a817-b6877d54f1d7",
    "front": "**Def**: To be sorry to tell someone something (formal).\n**Farsi**: متأسفیم اطلاع دهیم (رسمی)",
    "back": "regret, inform"
  },
  {
    "id": "b5475b4d-7ad3-45f5-9b6b-f903539cef12",
    "front": "**Def**: To formally end something, such as a contract or job.\n**Farsi**: فسخ کردن، پایان دادن",
    "back": "terminate (intention to)"
  },
  {
    "id": "6dda8a39-8f9c-4966-b3ed-e7937c7fd86e",
    "front": "**Def**: the noise became weaker.\n**Farsi**: سر و صدا کم شد",
    "back": "noise died down"
  },
  {
    "id": "82dded13-871d-49d3-a84c-199272b8174b",
    "front": "**Def**: very heavy rain.\n**Farsi**: باران شدید/سیل‌آسا",
    "back": "torrential rain"
  },
  {
    "id": "dcf56bf2-5cc4-4286-ab66-f07eeb7b035b",
    "front": "**Def**: a written statement by a political party saying what they believe in and what they intend to do.\n**Farsi**: مرام‌نامه، بیانیه انتخاباتی",
    "back": "manifesto"
  },
  {
    "id": "1819ed4b-95bd-4323-a82c-133cbf91d844",
    "front": "**Def**: be in charge of (a meeting).\n**Farsi**: ریاست (جلسه) را بر عهده داشتن",
    "back": "chair (a meeting) V"
  },
  {
    "id": "b990e83d-6b83-4ed3-8eae-2681bfdf601d",
    "front": "**Def**: I would appreciate it, regarding (formal).\n**Farsi**: ممنون خواهم بود، در رابطه با",
    "back": "I would be grateful, concerning"
  },
  {
    "id": "359374f3-c7e1-477e-8b58-8c9b6d38aede",
    "front": "**Def**: As a direct answer or reaction to (formal).\n**Farsi**: در پاسخ به، در جواب",
    "back": "in response to/in reply to"
  },
  {
    "id": "9725c9c2-9f4b-4dd3-9ba2-935ec82fc95f",
    "front": "**Def**: To drive or force (an attack or attacker) away; to resist.\n**Farsi**: دفع کردن، مبارزه کردن",
    "back": "repel/fight"
  },
  {
    "id": "509b2cfd-0907-4a64-9b77-d8c9b82dbba3",
    "front": "**Def**: arrive at a time or stage at which sth happens.\n**Farsi**: به نقطه‌ای رسیدن که",
    "back": "reach the point (where/when)"
  },
  {
    "id": "efdc4e1a-c2de-40f0-81f0-4816a1afdc01",
    "front": "**Def**: crime committed by professional criminals working in large groups.\n**Farsi**: جرم سازمان‌یافته",
    "back": "organized crime"
  },
  {
    "id": "09f13a8f-8619-41ee-ba0e-6d98bdb319c9",
    "front": "**Def**: A large amount of experience.\n**Farsi**: تجربه گسترده",
    "back": "extensive experience"
  },
  {
    "id": "9d5ab72f-48a1-40c9-953b-bf4bf00db8bc",
    "front": "**Def**: Before (formal).\n**Farsi**: قبل از، پیش از",
    "back": "Prior to"
  },
  {
    "id": "8aaa696b-4d42-40ae-b149-8b79645599cb",
    "front": "**Def**: About; relating to (formal).\n**Farsi**: در رابطه با، پیرامون",
    "back": "With regard to/Regarding/Concerning"
  },
  {
    "id": "ee67888b-3a84-4aa4-b61e-5e0c15501b25",
    "front": "**Def**: As a result or consequence of this; therefore (formal).\n**Farsi**: بنابراین، از این رو",
    "back": "thus/hence"
  },
  {
    "id": "0e1e087b-01f3-4e54-8fb1-cefc64834742",
    "front": "**Def**: FML hide sth.\n**Farsi**: پنهان کردن، مخفی کردن",
    "back": "conceal sth (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "7bdc14e7-65f8-4aea-9905-460d95bd2203",
    "front": "\nمعنی: موانع، چیزهایی که جلوی پیشرفت یا حرکت را می‌گیرند (در فارسی)\nMeaning: things that block one’s way or make progress difficult (in English)",
    "back": "Obstacles /ˈɒb.stə.kəlz/ — Example: “Despite many obstacles, she achieved her goals.” — Neutral"
  },
  {
    "id": "e043b666-f8db-404e-9bb9-3c08aca92ee9",
    "front": "**Def**: information that can help you, e.g. to make a decision.\n**Farsi**: دستورالعمل، راهنما",
    "back": "guideline (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "021af7b0-b5e8-44a6-b69b-2a2e9cde80d1",
    "front": "**Def**: a lawyer who gives legal advice and prepares documents.\n**Farsi**: وکیل دادگستری",
    "back": "solicitor"
  },
  {
    "id": "057fa96a-fa0a-4e83-8fc4-548c1e014691",
    "front": "**Def**: in a way that others will not notice. discreet ADJ. OPP indiscreet.\n**Farsi**: محتاطانه، به طور پنهانی",
    "back": "discreetly (ADV)"
  },
  {
    "id": "6ede22be-63c2-44d2-b7ef-a1771112449d",
    "front": "**Def**: make sth which is false appear true.\n**Farsi**: توهم ایجاد کردن",
    "back": "create an illusion (PHR)"
  },
  {
    "id": "3f19846f-7881-4475-814e-61ccded7ba23",
    "front": "**Def**: making sb look more attractive. OPP unflattering.\n**Farsi**: جذاب‌کننده، برازنده",
    "back": "flattering (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "24b45add-6d31-40aa-ab5f-4f229fe905fe",
    "front": "**Def**: make sth seem bigger, better, worse, or more important than it really is. exaggeration N.\n**Farsi**: اغراق کردن، بزرگنمایی کردن",
    "back": "exaggerate sth (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "ef2137e7-bfd4-4515-9be2-3a5d35904af3",
    "front": "**Def**: send sb away from court until their trial (remanded in custody = sent to prison until the trial).\n**Farsi**: بازداشت موقت کردن، به زندان فرستادن (تا محاکمه)",
    "back": "remand sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "c756d576-f713-4581-88fa-c676a49239cf",
    "front": "**Def**: commonly used in reference to things within a country (syn domestic).\n**Farsi**: خارجی (یا داخلی در متون اقتصادی و سیاسی)",
    "back": "external"
  },
  {
    "id": "fa00fb8c-741d-4714-86eb-8c4477be0550",
    "front": "**Def**: A standard by which something is judged (pl. criteria).\n**Farsi**: معیار، ملاک",
    "back": "criterion"
  },
  {
    "id": "165829ec-c6cb-4982-9e3f-9ef8ca2ae9ed",
    "front": "**Def**: to make someone notice something.\n**Farsi**: جلب توجه کردن",
    "back": "draw attention to (PHR)"
  },
  {
    "id": "c19a4179-fd8e-4c58-b7fe-c8c672fc5db9",
    "front": "**Def**: He never listens to or considers what I say.\n**Farsi**: توجه کردن به، دقت کردن به",
    "back": "pay attention to (PHR)"
  },
  {
    "id": "3cd5d88e-00bd-4013-8d0b-d2956ddad0b9",
    "front": "**Def**: Do sth to make the waiter notice you.\n**Farsi**: جلب توجه کردن",
    "back": "attract attention (PHR)"
  },
  {
    "id": "a4cafc78-0f0d-461e-9a89-3885bb9c1d65",
    "front": "مقدم‌بودن بر",
    "back": "Preceded by\nEx:This is why the value test is always Preceded by a usability test."
  },
  {
    "id": "fe270e3a-7bc4-404a-9447-f570bba14983",
    "front": "**Def**: a body movement you make to show a particular meaning.\n**Farsi**: ژست، حرکت بدن",
    "back": "gesture (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "36ed151e-e101-492a-9a3a-546e1dd669e4",
    "front": "**Def**: If you misinterpret sth. you understand it wrongly.\n**Farsi**: بد تعبیر کردن، اشتباه فهمیدن",
    "back": "misinterpret sth (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "5d68d6bf-ae9b-4375-81f8-729d08eb2205",
    "front": "**Def**: not needing or depending on other people or things.\n**Farsi**: خودکفا، مستقل",
    "back": "self-contained"
  },
  {
    "id": "bd4f7b0a-5400-4274-b817-6af707ea6eb4",
    "front": "خرابکاری یا صدمه‌زدن از عمد",
    "back": "Sabotage "
  },
  {
    "id": "58ca8832-9645-422f-9124-7271995fb08d",
    "front": "**Def**: the action or moment of looking into another person's eyes.\n**Farsi**: ارتباط چشمی",
    "back": "eye contact (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "d7c6f967-0e32-473b-818f-31329d6b6fde",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say that sth is possibly true but is not always true.\n**Farsi**: لزوماً نه، نه الزاما",
    "back": "not necessarily (ADV)"
  },
  {
    "id": "5a3f0fc8-6591-4ffd-9f5b-240040913ad0",
    "front": "**Def**: FML see or notice sth; an observant person is good at noticing things. observation N.\n**Farsi**: مشاهده کردن، دیدن",
    "back": "observe sth (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "207e8859-94f6-441a-818c-175968125faa",
    "front": "**Def**: (AME) the practice of ordering people to serve in the armed forces (syn conscription).\n**Farsi**: سربازی اجباری (بیشتر آمریکایی)",
    "back": "the draft"
  },
  {
    "id": "701ce627-740e-4a88-b5cf-82ebc2f49400",
    "front": "پس دادن پول",
    "back": "Reimburse "
  },
  {
    "id": "35689392-5efc-430b-af0e-9a164b36af99",
    "front": "**Def**: a mix of two or more things. combine v.\n**Farsi**: ترکیب، مجموعه",
    "back": "combination (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "8a5c3377-b51e-4545-a9b7-f71ac23d08cb",
    "front": "**Def**: show signs of sth, often a quality or a feeling. display N.\n**Farsi**: نمایش دادن، ابراز کردن",
    "back": "display sth (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "712d902a-8815-423e-b17c-c84f2c91be77",
    "front": "**Def**: An investigation (probe) into an agreement to sell weapons (arms deal).\n**Farsi**: تحقیق در مورد معامله تسلیحاتی",
    "back": "Arms deal probe"
  },
  {
    "id": "546d6994-2753-4448-b100-317698037ec2",
    "front": "آزاردهنده",
    "back": "Irritant\nSth that is irritating "
  },
  {
    "id": "eb74f661-e8f2-49e1-af15-ec4548d2229c",
    "front": "**Def**: The act of judging or determining the value or quality of something.\n**Farsi**: ارزیابی، سنجیدن",
    "back": "assessment/evaluate"
  },
  {
    "id": "9817903d-5648-4b98-b12e-ffb19bc9fe0d",
    "front": "**Def**: look and try to see or find sth/sb.\n**Farsi**: مراقب چیزی/کسی بودن، دنبال چیزی گشتن",
    "back": "look out for sth/sb (PHR V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "ca9b1f67-dfdd-4f14-bb61-dde8a0d92e6a",
    "front": "**Def**: become red in the face, often when you're angry or embarrassed.\n**Farsi**: سرخ شدن (از خجالت یا عصبانیت)",
    "back": "go red (PHR)"
  },
  {
    "id": "781dff63-d82e-46cd-8057-54c6f4d8e7e7",
    "front": "**Def**: If you sweat, water appears on the surface of your skin because you are hot. SYN perspire FML.\n**Farsi**: عرق کردن",
    "back": "sweat (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "38d22f92-d815-4f6d-9afa-63cb37916403",
    "front": "مساعد ",
    "back": "Conducive "
  },
  {
    "id": "feffef3f-307b-4df6-8986-02920ebfdb78",
    "front": "**Def**: prove that somebody is innocent of doing something wrong.\n**Farsi**: تبرئه کردن",
    "back": "clear sb of sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "3452d60d-0121-4698-814a-e9d6122860cb",
    "front": "**Def**: more than is reasonable or necessary. excess N. exceed v.\n**Farsi**: بیش از حد، مفرط",
    "back": "excessive (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "bcb9f755-3666-4a7e-8d27-41687c672d9a",
    "front": "**Def**: remember to consider sth.\n**Farsi**: در نظر داشتن، به خاطر سپردن",
    "back": "bear sth in mind (PHR)"
  },
  {
    "id": "ab9a7cb3-9af5-4785-8818-4dcce0db0462",
    "front": "**Def**: make general statements about sth that may only be based on a few examples. generalize v.\n**Farsi**: کلی‌گویی کردن",
    "back": "make generalizations about sth (PHR)"
  },
  {
    "id": "aaae480e-4315-4ee4-8238-6bae24f06685",
    "front": "**Def**: an extra and usually bad effect that a drug has on you.\n**Farsi**: عارضه جانبی",
    "back": "side effect"
  },
  {
    "id": "a71be133-e425-4634-8cba-dc90253dc418",
    "front": "**Def**: a building or object that is very unpleasant to look at.\n**Farsi**: بسیار زشت، منظره نازیبا",
    "back": "a real eyesore"
  },
  {
    "id": "854343c4-d113-41da-94df-9fe40ac55d1a",
    "front": "**Def**: to calculate the total number of people, things, etc. in a particular group.\n**Farsi**: محاسبه کردن، حساب کردن (تعداد کل)",
    "back": "count (2) (FIND TOTAL)"
  },
  {
    "id": "23710e33-60d9-4b19-815f-506ab846fbe7",
    "front": "**Def**: unfairly changing the agreed rules or conditions during a course of action.\n**Farsi**: تغییر ناعادلانه قوانین (در میانه بازی)",
    "back": "moving the goalposts"
  },
  {
    "id": "35ed0130-d594-4bec-9b51-f36258ef9366",
    "front": "همه فکر می‌کنن حرفی برای گفتن دارن تو دیزاین ",
    "back": "Everyone thinks they have a say in design"
  },
  {
    "id": "651c695d-265e-4cff-a35d-1782302bdc01",
    "front": "**Def**: suggest that you feel or think sth without saying so directly. implication N.\n**Farsi**: اشاره ضمنی کردن، دلالت داشتن",
    "back": "imply sth (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "4f244358-96bb-417c-8614-62440692999c",
    "front": "**Def**: a determination not to change your opinion or attitude. SYN obstinacy.\n**Farsi**: لجبازی، سرسختی",
    "back": "stubbornness (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "34ad10df-df20-4b9a-b949-b2a0167a461e",
    "front": "**Def**: INF be attracted to sb.\n**Farsi**: کسی را دوست داشتن، از کسی خوش آمدن (جذب شدن)",
    "back": "fancy sb (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "456b9d20-542c-4835-99ab-7467423e70f8",
    "front": "**Def**: fixed or stuck in something.\n**Farsi**: گیر کردن، جاسازی شدن",
    "back": "lodge (in sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "4003ac0e-9b5f-4191-942a-fc2b6dded4cc",
    "front": "آزادی عمل",
    "back": "Latitude "
  },
  {
    "id": "18a70bab-ab55-4565-9760-07189d8401fa",
    "front": "**Def**: keep moving or touching sth with your hands.\n**Farsi**: ور رفتن با چیزی، دستکاری کردن",
    "back": "fiddle with sth (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "566a740e-76f3-42bf-868a-84a431225636",
    "front": "**Def**: move your hand or fingers gently over the surface of sth.\n**Farsi**: نوازش کردن، دست کشیدن",
    "back": "stroke sth (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "7e304650-781e-4588-9c99-6c737710b109",
    "front": "**Def**: if something happens against all odds, it happens or succeeds although it seemed impossible or very unlikely.\n**Farsi**: با وجود تمام مشکلات و شانس‌های کم",
    "back": "against all (the) odds"
  },
  {
    "id": "ff0b4d9e-6fca-4e81-a9f1-d1f73d18acfa",
    "front": "آگاه و مطلع",
    "back": "Apprised\nKeep the apprised"
  },
  {
    "id": "04a3de63-49b2-4a8d-81d3-c9f79d8ade5f",
    "front": "**Def**: move slowly and quietly so you are not seen or heard. (also tiptoe).\n**Farsi**: خزیدن، دزدکی رفتن",
    "back": "creep (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "10aaafbb-3048-440c-8ba9-789b85fb8776",
    "front": "**Def**: try to find information about people's private lives.\n**Farsi**: سرک کشیدن، فضولی کردن",
    "back": "pry into sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "848acc74-d066-4f9f-82e3-624fb0c14f36",
    "front": "**Def**: Saw something briefly or partially.\n**Farsi**: نگاه اجمالی کردن، لحظه‌ای دیدن",
    "back": "caught a glimpse of"
  },
  {
    "id": "66cf7f4c-ccc1-45f1-87dd-c5058273700a",
    "front": "واژگون شدن قایق",
    "back": "Capsize "
  },
  {
    "id": "2f993c9a-2bb5-490c-840a-67d1e22c1e44",
    "front": "جزر و مد",
    "back": "High and low tide"
  },
  {
    "id": "7f28775b-7e7a-4acb-ae11-881b70e2bb56",
    "front": "**Def**: walk casually for pleasure.\n**Farsi**: قدم زدن، گشت زدن",
    "back": "stroll (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "010590f1-8c69-41e9-b6e9-faf44b520ca0",
    "front": "**Def**: walk slowly and with difficulty because one leg or foot is injured.\n**Farsi**: لنگیدن",
    "back": "limp (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "6f6fb772-a0f2-448b-8316-b2cb150b6d21",
    "front": "**Def**: the conditions and facts that are connected with and affect a situation, an event or an action.\n**Farsi**: شرایط، اوضاع",
    "back": "circumstance (1) (usually pl.)"
  },
  {
    "id": "7f09e845-bd24-449a-b5a1-8b89d4691e08",
    "front": "**Def**: if somebody allegedly does something, another person says they have done it, even though this has not been proved.\n**Farsi**: به ادعای، ظاهراً",
    "back": "allegedly"
  },
  {
    "id": "a76a5bab-03b3-49dc-adc9-ff8646ba0d7b",
    "front": "**Def**: walk long distances in the country.\n**Farsi**: پیاده‌روی طولانی کردن (در طبیعت)",
    "back": "hike (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "5baf4080-2192-45c6-a427-5e0b3a540656",
    "front": "**Def**: walk with stiff regular steps.\n**Farsi**: رژه رفتن، با قدم‌های منظم راه رفتن",
    "back": "march (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "4f9be05a-6795-470f-bb98-25afee4efc60",
    "front": "**Def**: making a certain situation or outcome likely or possible; helpful.\n**Farsi**: مفید، منجر شونده (به)",
    "back": "conducive (ADJ) (to)"
  },
  {
    "id": "55f44f82-1716-4b7d-b184-d4c0210726e5",
    "front": "**Def**: complete the last part of a plan/an arrangement.\n**Farsi**: نهایی کردن، تمام کردن",
    "back": "finalize (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "9a0be74b-e8ca-4c40-ad9e-917e44a390e1",
    "front": "**Def**: Used in addresses when the recipient is staying at someone else's house.\n**Farsi**: به نشانی، به توجه (در آدرس)",
    "back": "c/o (care of)"
  },
  {
    "id": "d2c46c4f-d2a3-43aa-8b34-c9a983ea846f",
    "front": "**Def**: run, drive, etc. after sb/sth to catch them.\n**Farsi**: تعقیب کردن",
    "back": "chase sb/sth (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "3af5ece5-f3b0-4093-b359-4aef894173bc",
    "front": "**Def**: run quickly and suddenly.\n**Farsi**: با سرعت دویدن",
    "back": "dash (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "4c9fece7-b00e-410c-81cf-fbae1f3ee573",
    "front": "**Def**: (of a horse or rider) run quickly.\n**Farsi**: تاختن، چهارنعل رفتن (اسب)",
    "back": "gallop (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "8818b0a5-d821-43c1-99ae-910a153996db",
    "front": "**Def**: be very good at sth.\n**Farsi**: برتری داشتن، عالی بودن",
    "back": "excel (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "0acd1930-bc32-42d3-a3fd-bc43fb58863a",
    "front": "**Def**: I promise not to tell anyone (informal idiom).\n**Farsi**: لب‌هایم بسته است (راز نگه می‌دارم)",
    "back": "My lips are sealed"
  },
  {
    "id": "81ecbcdf-ffca-47e7-8c34-416ab8b1954a",
    "front": "**Def**: the way sb deals with sth/sb.\n**Farsi**: اداره کردن، مدیریت",
    "back": "handling (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "2012d70a-ee56-4c1e-9f1a-201de07ab690",
    "front": "**Def**: move quickly in a particular direction, often to attack sb/sth.\n**Farsi**: یورش بردن، حمله کردن",
    "back": "charge (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "30380380-cdf3-455b-be71-2239eefe2982",
    "front": "**Def**: be faced with a new and difficult task that you're not prepared for.\n**Farsi**: با کار دشوار و ناگهانی روبرو شدن",
    "back": "deep end (thrown in at the deep end)"
  },
  {
    "id": "bb75a76f-5eeb-4f63-8983-bb80edc84aab",
    "front": "**Def**: show that sth exists or is likely to be true. indication N.\n**Farsi**: نشان دادن، حاکی بودن",
    "back": "indicate sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "69fa2bce-80fc-439d-8d5e-57e2885af3ba",
    "front": "**Def**: look at sth for a long time because you are interested in it or are thinking about sth else. gaze N.\n**Farsi**: خیره شدن، با دقت نگاه کردن",
    "back": "gaze at sth (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "7f39c7f8-34cd-4464-8b69-0375221b8bbe",
    "front": "**Def**: a period of physical exercise you do to keep fit. work out v.\n**Farsi**: تمرین ورزشی",
    "back": "workout (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "5bdd0b30-14b0-41d1-9594-7011ba01afcd",
    "front": "**Def**: INF very beautiful and attractive. SYN lovely.\n**Farsi**: زیبا، خیره‌کننده",
    "back": "gorgeous (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "9aceb02d-6843-4d60-b8f2-351d5a4351a6",
    "front": "**Def**: If your mouth waters, you produce saliva and want to eat. mouth-watering ADJ.\n**Farsi**: آب دهان راه افتادن، هوس کردن",
    "back": "mouth water (PHR)"
  },
  {
    "id": "1ed7c94a-1f56-4ca9-8d4d-c7765e7e1bc0",
    "front": "**Def**: an illness in a part of the body.\n**Farsi**: اختلال/عارضه",
    "back": "disorder"
  },
  {
    "id": "f01d7149-3be7-4ffa-9fbe-05f669d36321",
    "front": "**Def**: able to bend and move parts of your body easily.\n**Farsi**: نرم، منعطف",
    "back": "supple (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "59bcb0ee-255e-4cf5-9400-d11161d980e3",
    "front": "**Def**: able to move quickly and easily. agility N.\n**Farsi**: چابک، فرز",
    "back": "agile (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "7770cff2-fd96-45c9-a9f4-eb5a6a578531",
    "front": "**Def**: continue to exist (used especially about sth unpleasant). persistent ADJ.\n**Farsi**: ادامه یافتن/باقی ماندن",
    "back": "persist (v)"
  },
  {
    "id": "ef1a8fca-af55-4379-a2ea-8f175fad8787",
    "front": "**Def**: a quality that makes other people like you and be attracted to you. charismatic ADJ.\n**Farsi**: جذابیت/کشش",
    "back": "charisma"
  },
  {
    "id": "7c3fea71-f16b-4f7c-afbd-6ab28073355a",
    "front": "**Def**: tell sb personal information because you trust them.\n**Farsi**: راز دل گفتن/اعتماد کردن",
    "back": "confide in sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "18c83666-4954-4979-a232-4d6450f61f7e",
    "front": "**Def**: feeling some pain and unable to move easily. stiffness N.\n**Farsi**: خشک، سفت (بدن)",
    "back": "stiff (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "d3ebb973-eccb-404c-bbb1-50c9ff243d4a",
    "front": "**Def**: moving slowly, below your normal activity level. sluggishness N.\n**Farsi**: کند، تنبل",
    "back": "sluggish (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "c4540f93-9b0c-4871-a096-9ba1800e1fd4",
    "front": "**Def**: make sb suffer because it will be good for them later.\n**Farsi**: سخت‌گیری به نفع شخص (نوعی ضرب‌المثل)",
    "back": "be cruel to be kind (SAYING)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f232bb54-31f5-47c6-b338-93ff68201e43",
    "front": "**Def**: give sb information about sth, especially sth that has been secret.\n**Farsi**: افشا کردن/فاش ساختن",
    "back": "disclose sth (to sb) (SYN reveal sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "714b22f0-c1c6-4c26-81e6-08b5d2f6a269",
    "front": "**Def**: feel anger about sth, often when it seems unfair. resentment N.\n**Farsi**: رنجیدن/ناراحت بودن (به دلیل ناعادلانه بودن)",
    "back": "resent sth (v)"
  },
  {
    "id": "ac6fc36e-1828-45f0-9d5a-5e137e6e622d",
    "front": "**Def**: invent a method or plan of doing sth. SYN think sth up.\n**Farsi**: ابداع کردن، طرح ریختن",
    "back": "devise sth (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "a79e1373-9e91-4097-8fdf-3a11962274d3",
    "front": "**Def**: do physical activities to prepare the muscles for exercise. SYN warm up.\n**Farsi**: بدن را گرم کردن، نرمش کردن",
    "back": "loosen up (PHR V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "df888d4f-7d82-4850-a203-45142f565d4a",
    "front": "**Def**: lean over at the waist (also bend your knee, elbow, etc.).\n**Farsi**: خم شدن",
    "back": "bend (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "743ccaae-07ae-4eba-bbdc-fb27764d0dbe",
    "front": "**Def**: needing effort and energy. SYN arduous.\n**Farsi**: سخت، طاقت‌فرسا",
    "back": "strenuous (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "eda71cb6-8da4-4871-b41b-c625991aa096",
    "front": "حسی که نسبت به چیزی داریم\n",
    "back": "Sentiment "
  },
  {
    "id": "15f6b397-4fc6-46fe-9f53-02f37aff831e",
    "front": "**Def**: the hard work and effort that sb puts into an activity because they care about it. dedicate sth/yourself to sth/sb v. dedicated ADJ.\n**Farsi**: فداکاری/تعهد",
    "back": "dedication (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "e275249b-ccd2-4753-a72d-ca682fdb99ee",
    "front": "**Def**: does her fair share of the work or effort (implies she is competent).\n**Farsi**: وظیفه‌اش را به طور کامل انجام می‌دهد، سهم خود را ادا می‌کند",
    "back": "pulls her weight"
  },
  {
    "id": "5d548ec5-5a60-44dd-8daf-8bad052de5eb",
    "front": "**Def**: A thing that is relentless never seems to stop or get any easier.\n**Farsi**: بی‌وقفه، سخت و بی‌امان",
    "back": "relentless (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "1a9cc6cb-ffd1-4383-8590-1e8d69cc9cf2",
    "front": "**Def**: happening or appearing again and again. recur v.\n**Farsi**: مکرر، عودکننده",
    "back": "recurrent (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "42d161a1-063a-4ce6-bde6-47256d72c721",
    "front": "**Def**: do A. then B, then do A again, and so on.\n**Farsi**: بین دو چیز متناوب عمل کردن",
    "back": "alternate between A and B (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "352e3f53-553a-45b0-9dfd-ec8f84c4b48c",
    "front": "**Def**: run a short distance very fast.\n**Farsi**: با حداکثر سرعت دویدن",
    "back": "sprint (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "00425c1c-0414-4c33-891c-d66a39f815fe",
    "front": "**Def**: happening all the time or a lot of the time.\n**Farsi**: ثابت، دائم، پیوسته",
    "back": "constant (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "3d8cd02a-b4af-4a41-8603-0f8a43fb925b",
    "front": "**Def**: advantages a company offers in addition to the salary. SYN perks INF.\n**Farsi**: مزایا، منافع",
    "back": "benefits"
  },
  {
    "id": "6f2d2403-64c7-4a42-a165-dfd3be31e43d",
    "front": "محافظه‌کار",
    "back": "Conservative "
  },
  {
    "id": "feddb988-ac3a-49ba-a8e4-8118bd4395bb",
    "front": "**Def**: be involved and influential in developing sth.\n**Farsi**: نقش داشتن/مؤثر بودن",
    "back": "play a part (in sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "a985249c-adc7-4817-9e57-37e203eddf20",
    "front": "**Def**: think about something in a particular way (used passively).\n**Farsi**: دیدن/تلقی کردن",
    "back": "view (v, FML)"
  },
  {
    "id": "22322435-7af0-472d-bc7d-f70728374f22",
    "front": "**Def**: encourage someone to behave badly.\n**Farsi**: به بیراهه کشاندن، منحرف کردن",
    "back": "lead sb astray"
  },
  {
    "id": "015d7041-8e09-45e6-a65c-a5f7bc031843",
    "front": "**Def**: The person who tells the story.\n**Farsi**: راوی، گوینده",
    "back": "narrator"
  },
  {
    "id": "bf928ac5-c531-4d4a-9f03-a580080a511a",
    "front": "**Def**: make or cause sth to make short, loud sounds. rattle N.\n**Farsi**: تق‌تق کردن، به صدا درآوردن",
    "back": "rattle (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "06f7bc57-6860-414f-956d-9eca70880fae",
    "front": "**Def**: a long, deep sound or series of sounds. rumble v.\n**Farsi**: غرولند، صدای عمیق و طولانی",
    "back": "rumble (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "ef18f91d-35a5-4ba4-912a-5effc2c6d2d3",
    "front": "**Def**: make or cause sth to make a noise like paper, leaves, etc. rubbing together. rustle N.\n**Farsi**: خش‌خش کردن",
    "back": "rustle (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "dcb6d3ac-087c-4072-bd70-09cd8070b04c",
    "front": "**Def**: The way in which something is shown or offered.\n**Farsi**: نحوه نمایش، ارائه",
    "back": "presentation"
  },
  {
    "id": "4ac7f231-2b11-49ff-90f2-b371b053c180",
    "front": "**Def**: (of a liquid) fall onto sth in large drops and make it wet. splash N.\n**Farsi**: پاشیدن (مایع)، صدای چلپ چلوپ دادن",
    "back": "splash on/onto sth (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "d6cabff6-9f0a-4b96-884b-688a9ef744fb",
    "front": "**Def**: an effect or influence on sth.\n**Farsi**: تأثیر/نفوذ",
    "back": "impact (on sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "9f564ce1-71de-490a-beac-097d42b01c83",
    "front": "شرور/شرورانه",
    "back": "Nefarious \nNefariously"
  },
  {
    "id": "578acc58-d535-4263-bda3-e99bf0747615",
    "front": "**Def**: the system of rules and acceptable behaviour in a formal situation.\n**Farsi**: تشریفات، آیین‌نامه، دستورالعمل",
    "back": "protocol"
  },
  {
    "id": "22e1d901-1850-409c-9076-7f95a2a74868",
    "front": "**Def**: cook quickly by stirring in a small amount of hot oil.\n**Farsi**: تفت دادن (با حرارت بالا و روغن کم)",
    "back": "stir-fry"
  },
  {
    "id": "fcc4e92c-3226-41a8-a4ff-1ccb29964da5",
    "front": "**Def**: a negative response to something because you're angry you can't have it.\n**Farsi**: حسادت، انگور ترش (انتقاد از چیزی که نمی‌توانید داشته باشید)",
    "back": "sour grapes (idiom)"
  },
  {
    "id": "a67edfb0-3d25-4229-b7af-aa752eba28c7",
    "front": "**Def**: Expressed in an unclear or confusing way.\n**Farsi**: نامنسجم، آشفته",
    "back": "incoherent"
  },
  {
    "id": "6ec7d70f-53f4-42d2-86f1-44de987c348f",
    "front": "**Def**: Moving from topic to topic without order; lengthy and analytical.\n**Farsi**: تحلیلی، گسترده، پر و پیمان",
    "back": "discursive"
  },
  {
    "id": "1cf0e89c-2557-472a-bfc2-53d036a4027f",
    "front": "**Def**: If a car horn beeps it makes a short high or loud sound. beep N.\n**Farsi**: بوق زدن، صدای بوق دادن",
    "back": "beep (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b71fb0ef-1b75-48ef-8208-08bd25f9ecd5",
    "front": "**Def**: a loud, high, unpleasant sound. screech v.\n**Farsi**: جیغ، صدای بلند و ناخوشایند",
    "back": "screech (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "eb22f2de-7fb7-455f-ae8a-98dffa9fdd39",
    "front": "**Def**: shut sth with a lot of force so that it makes a loud noise.\n**Farsi**: محکم بستن (در)",
    "back": "slam sth (shut) (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "bde68238-34c1-4083-b68e-fdfac31f9017",
    "front": "**Def**: make a wet, sucking sound, e.g. when you walk through mud.\n**Farsi**: صدای چلپ و چلوپ کردن (در گل)",
    "back": "squelch (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "c6f8ab32-095e-4a9b-b56f-68fb22c149c2",
    "front": "**Def**: be very interested in sth as a hobby.\n**Farsi**: شدیداً به چیزی علاقه داشتن",
    "back": "be into sth (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "440ec442-50ee-4268-9a8d-2d8117674245",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who feels uneasy and out of place in their surroundings.\n**Farsi**: ماهی بیرون از آب (احساس ناراحتی و بی‌جایی)",
    "back": "a fish out of water (idiom)"
  },
  {
    "id": "3b5dd35a-94dc-458f-9c0b-a3b85131a2a9",
    "front": "**Def**: relax.\n**Farsi**: راحت بودن، سخت نگرفتن",
    "back": "take it easy (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "9f839aa5-f1f7-43a8-8b24-e9f4996393c3",
    "front": "**Def**: make the sound that an old door or floor makes. creak N.\n**Farsi**: جیرجیر کردن",
    "back": "creak (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "a9f8abbd-6d9d-4171-8f39-e7a9a38cf801",
    "front": "**Def**: (of sounds) very high in the register of sound. OPP low-pitched.\n**Farsi**: زیر، با صدای نازک",
    "back": "high-pitched (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "3ff93036-1e67-4662-938c-6b984e6901bb",
    "front": "**Def**: (dogs) make a short loud sound. (Human behavior: boss's bark is worse than his bite = He's not really as angry or aggressive as he sounds.)\n**Farsi**: پارس کردن (سگ)",
    "back": "bark (N/V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "defbdfe8-5a61-465a-ab52-c2334fdfa709",
    "front": "ورشکست‌شدن\nبه خاک سیاه نشستن",
    "back": "Going bust"
  },
  {
    "id": "b5f9da67-91f3-400b-b4ba-27852891f0da",
    "front": "**Def**: take a break or holiday to get your energy back.\n**Farsi**: شارژ شدن (انرژی گرفتن)",
    "back": "recharge your batteries (idiom)"
  },
  {
    "id": "7e693633-f5f4-4b45-80af-f45d1486017d",
    "front": "**Def**: be beaten and can no longer take part. SYN knock sb out of sth (usually passive).\n**Farsi**: حذف شدن (از مسابقات)",
    "back": "eliminate sb from sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "754f9c66-271c-4b45-8e87-219b860b9da5",
    "front": "**Def**: make sth happen. SYNS create sth, cause sth.\n**Farsi**: موجب شدن، به وجود آوردن",
    "back": "bring sth about"
  },
  {
    "id": "17e0c92f-dce6-4b92-b493-be24efc52d28",
    "front": "**Def**: (wolves) make a long loud cry. (Human behavior: howling in pain, howled with laughter.)\n**Farsi**: زوزه کشیدن (گرگ)، با صدای بلند گریه/خندیدن",
    "back": "howl (N/V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "cc61c2a0-d32a-4518-a043-18c328690ad7",
    "front": "**Def**: (dogs) make a deep, angry sound. (Human behavior: said in a low, angry voice. SYN snarl.)\n**Farsi**: غرولند کردن (سگ)، با صدای خشمگین حرف زدن",
    "back": "growl (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "71776a02-8d17-4047-be01-e421e9d5c73b",
    "front": "**Def**: (bees) make a continuous low sound. (Human behavior: head was buzzing = thinking about it continuously, buzzing about = moving around continuously.)\n**Farsi**: وِزوِز کردن (زنبور)، فکر در سر چرخیدن",
    "back": "buzz (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "3bcb435f-2686-4630-bfa4-009ad9b7896c",
    "front": "**Def**: Able to be cured. OPP incurable.\n**Farsi**: قابل درمان",
    "back": "curable ADJ."
  },
  {
    "id": "5c6e38df-706c-48cd-a9f9-3fc436dabc27",
    "front": "احتمال موفقیتمون یک در ده میلیونه",
    "back": "It is a 10 million to 1 shot"
  },
  {
    "id": "63abbd28-95ed-4eb2-994a-d833b77ec894",
    "front": "**Def**: (of an actor) not suitable for the role they have been given.\n**Farsi**: انتخاب نامناسب بازیگر (برای نقش)",
    "back": "miscast"
  },
  {
    "id": "dc82a570-c245-4d73-ab16-4a47a3a0be2d",
    "front": "**Def**: become very nervous or upset and unable to perform.\n**Farsi**: از هم پاشیدن، دستپاچه شدن",
    "back": "go to pieces (idiom, INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "e28614b7-2c3c-4a86-9758-c8046f4481e9",
    "front": "**Def**: (lions) make a very loud deep sound. (Human behavior: a huge roar when Drogba scored, roared with laughter.)\n**Farsi**: غرش کردن (شیر)، فریاد/خنده بلند کردن",
    "back": "roar (N/V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "214b62d6-054a-4c5b-b9d2-4bc01a75444c",
    "front": "**Def**: (mice) make a short high but not loud sound. (Human behavior: squeaked down the phone = spoke in a high-pitched, excited voice. squeaky ADJ.)\n**Farsi**: جیرجیر کردن (موش)، با صدای زیر هیجان‌زده صحبت کردن",
    "back": "squeak (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "ecd7ca24-3d94-4af7-bf17-6b6f7b7a122a",
    "front": " کار نشد نداره(ریسکشو می‌پذیرم)",
    "back": "Those are my kind of odds "
  },
  {
    "id": "979c48d4-7b11-4caa-9d17-b3aadd1464d5",
    "front": "**Def**: doing things that are necessary to achieve something.\n**Farsi**: در حال انجام کاری بودن، در فرآیند",
    "back": "in the process of doing sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "d449399d-e1f6-4d07-ac88-03973ca55343",
    "front": "**Def**: a line of bushes growing close together around a garden or field.\n**Farsi**: پرچین، شمشاد",
    "back": "hedge"
  },
  {
    "id": "c01143d0-3a44-4d96-9dd2-cb0f9a3ef8ad",
    "front": "**Def**: (cocks) make repeated loud sounds especially in the morning. (Human behavior: crowing about = talking too proudly about. SYN boast.)\n**Farsi**: قوقولی‌قوقو کردن (خروس)، لاف زدن (با غرور حرف زدن)",
    "back": "crow (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b40ed67b-b965-432a-a9ac-c27123ebcd01",
    "front": "**Def**: (owls) make a long 'oo' sound. (Human behavior: hooted at me = sounded her car horn, hots of derision.)\n**Farsi**: هو کردن (جغد)، بوق زدن (ماشین)، هو کردن (تمسخر)",
    "back": "hoot (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "964bec77-ba56-4a2c-ac86-3cd5c876065c",
    "front": "**Def**: the ability to see. SYN sight.\n**Farsi**: بینایی، قدرت دید",
    "back": "eyesight (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "10e831c7-26d0-4b5d-88c6-aa47c20460d9",
    "front": "**Def**: a slight pain in your eyes, e.g. from reading a lot.\n**Farsi**: خستگی چشم",
    "back": "eye strain (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "935b7b1d-a3ac-4989-9a34-a9669eba036b",
    "front": "**Def**: a sudden desire to do something without thinking about the results (buy sth on impulse).\n**Farsi**: انگیزه ناگهانی، تصمیم آنی",
    "back": "impulse (to do sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "71c47f42-7f81-45ab-bfda-238764974129",
    "front": "**Def**: a feeling of slight pain.\n**Farsi**: ناراحتی، عدم آسایش",
    "back": "discomfort (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "dc0cb545-a226-45eb-b8bd-5755f501a8e3",
    "front": "**Def**: Not able to be cured.\n**Farsi**: لاعلاج",
    "back": "incurable ADJ."
  },
  {
    "id": "094680de-9f03-4d98-a7b8-8e7311376d44",
    "front": "**Def**: very serious (crippling debts/disease).\n**Farsi**: فلج‌کننده، بسیار سنگین",
    "back": "crippling"
  },
  {
    "id": "e62a9c6a-498a-4be5-8ec3-7bbed0140046",
    "front": "**Def**: forming a small group and not letting others join in. clique N.\n**Farsi**: باندباز، گروه گرا",
    "back": "cliquey (adj, INF, DISAPPROVING)"
  },
  {
    "id": "81bb653c-35e7-48f4-a5f1-1748562012db",
    "front": "**Def**: motionless; without movement.\n**Farsi**: بی‌حرکت، ثابت",
    "back": "still (motionless)"
  },
  {
    "id": "807453bd-744d-4a03-8bbf-7f3e83a13b1b",
    "front": "**Def**: even; yet (used to emphasize a comparison).\n**Farsi**: هنوز، کماکان، حتی",
    "back": "still (even/yet)"
  },
  {
    "id": "37574f2f-49ac-4abd-a975-83eb8d0e4e69",
    "front": "**Def**: nevertheless; even so (used to introduce a contrasting idea).\n**Farsi**: با این حال، با وجود این",
    "back": "Still (nevertheless)"
  },
  {
    "id": "dc5a1e1d-c745-427c-bfb1-f3e85fa8d8ec",
    "front": "**Def**: change sth so it is the opposite of what it was before (reverse a decision/trend/policy, etc.).\n**Farsi**: معکوس کردن، تغییر جهت دادن",
    "back": "reverse sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "407adc3a-ca8e-408a-84c4-d478f1cf5a61",
    "front": "**Def**: make sth that has been decided start to happen. SYNS carry out sth, put sth into practice.\n**Farsi**: اجرا کردن، به کار بستن",
    "back": "implement sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "df9cc182-98e1-4647-aabb-7097e6cb749c",
    "front": "**Def**: secretly revealed information before the official time.\n**Farsi**: لو رفتن، درز کردن (اطلاعات)",
    "back": "leaked"
  },
  {
    "id": "555383c4-d6a3-4733-a5aa-c0f20f508f8f",
    "front": "**Def**: arriving in large numbers (figurative).\n**Farsi**: سیل‌آسا وارد شدن، هجوم آوردن",
    "back": "flooding"
  },
  {
    "id": "a1129913-9470-486d-af64-8ab89faa8ef6",
    "front": "**Def**: subject to intense scrutiny or investigation (figurative).\n**Farsi**: زیر ذره‌بین، تحت بررسی دقیق",
    "back": "under the microscope"
  },
  {
    "id": "854e1695-5150-4536-ad7e-c961508c88df",
    "front": "**Def**: using new methods or making new discoveries.\n**Farsi**: پیشگام، بدیع، نوآورانه",
    "back": "groundbreaking"
  },
  {
    "id": "18847fff-f2f6-4978-acc8-ab252da9bce1",
    "front": "**Def**: 1. (of animals) have sex and produce young. 2. keep animals in order for them to produce young.\n**Farsi**: تولید مثل کردن، پرورش دادن",
    "back": "breed V"
  },
  {
    "id": "871ebb8e-9b1d-4636-8c26-a767074f5163",
    "front": "**Def**: The expression of very strong disapproval.\n**Farsi**: محکومیت، تقبیح",
    "back": "condemnation"
  },
  {
    "id": "3c69fbfb-3e40-4cce-835a-cc5e246b6fd8",
    "front": "**Def**: a friend I have known for a long time.\n**Farsi**: دوست قدیمی",
    "back": "old friend"
  },
  {
    "id": "64894ce6-5130-4b19-aad6-37c1b5f6ee67",
    "front": "**Def**: wasn't able to catch the bus.\n**Farsi**: جا ماندن از اتوبوس",
    "back": "missed the bus"
  },
  {
    "id": "bd878fe5-5033-4f3c-b7b9-11de3b125d7d",
    "front": "**Def**: it's very unlikely he'll come.\n**Farsi**: بسیار بعید",
    "back": "highly unlikely"
  },
  {
    "id": "6e8dc356-4d63-4c55-b412-85ab942db3b5",
    "front": "**Def**: very heavy rain.\n**Farsi**: بارش سیل‌آسا",
    "back": "torrential rainfall"
  },
  {
    "id": "e678ed77-3efb-441d-9ee8-fcdf6a37887c",
    "front": "**Def**: A confident and forceful statement of fact or belief.\n**Farsi**: ادعا، اظهار قاطع",
    "back": "assertion"
  },
  {
    "id": "91cef3ea-8a28-47ff-a4e7-7197091051ad",
    "front": "**Def**: used with nouns, adjectives, and adverbs to mean 'helping a person or thing; not harming them'. (e.g., eco-friendly, user-friendly)\n**Farsi**: دوستدار، سازگار (مانند کاربرپسند)",
    "back": "-friendly"
  },
  {
    "id": "467657aa-5ea2-4462-80ab-c31e76a521b0",
    "front": "**Def**: destroy or get rid of sth (bad) completely. SYN wipe sth out.\n**Farsi**: ریشه کن کردن، از بین بردن",
    "back": "eradicate sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "cd41cf5d-a020-4658-b52d-78b3d189da4e",
    "front": "**Def**: unwanted email advertisements; you block spam (= prevent it) with anti-spam filters.\n**Farsi**: هرزنامه، اسپم",
    "back": "spam"
  },
  {
    "id": "191386a3-95ab-45b4-8a13-0eadfc788aa7",
    "front": "**Def**: Gave a general description or framework of something.\n**Farsi**: کلیات را بیان کرد",
    "back": "outlined"
  },
  {
    "id": "b922958d-f9e4-4f4a-911d-5ed26367d353",
    "front": "**Def**: combine our assets/effort.\n**Farsi**: منابع خود را روی هم ریختن",
    "back": "pool our resources"
  },
  {
    "id": "241d0372-a020-44ff-b966-523c18eb7cf2",
    "front": "**Def**: end an inability to agree or move forward.\n**Farsi**: شکستن بن‌بست",
    "back": "break the deadlock"
  },
  {
    "id": "95623bfc-6f02-4d9a-a0a4-3a50d01cbf00",
    "front": "**Def**: a tiny amount compared to what is needed.\n**Farsi**: قطره‌ای در اقیانوس، مقدار ناچیز",
    "back": "a drop in the ocean"
  },
  {
    "id": "e5431ced-6800-407f-a3f6-00a4a19d0165",
    "front": "**Def**: To accept and allow (behavior that is considered morally wrong or offensive) to continue.\n**Farsi**: چشم‌پوشی کردن از (اشتباه یا خطا)",
    "back": "condone"
  },
  {
    "id": "12f82455-194f-4fda-9db5-4b25a6c96cd5",
    "front": "**Def**: limit the size, number, or amount of sth.\n**Farsi**: محدود کردن، منحصر کردن",
    "back": "restrict sth (to sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "e5ef57fc-6cb6-40ce-8e80-4f340311fcc7",
    "front": "**Def**: a substance which is put into the blood and protects the body from disease.\n**Farsi**: واکسن",
    "back": "vaccine"
  },
  {
    "id": "0f5b1726-69ab-44c0-9e8d-2d1a0c94a999",
    "front": "**Def**: use a computer to connect secretly to sb else's computer and find or change information on it.\n**Farsi**: نفوذ کردن (هک کردن)",
    "back": "hack into sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "4962520e-5ab8-459e-bb81-182c38fc66bb",
    "front": "**Def**: be made to leave the place where you live and go somewhere else.\n**Farsi**: ریشه‌کن شدن، آواره شدن",
    "back": "be uprooted"
  },
  {
    "id": "53f1fc8e-84fe-4a1a-a312-09769a113a0f",
    "front": "**Def**: a result that is obvious before it happens.\n**Farsi**: نتیجه از پیش معلوم",
    "back": "a foregone conclusion"
  },
  {
    "id": "555f11b2-eca4-4ec6-8ba0-5afc979d678f",
    "front": "**Def**: most importantly.\n**Farsi**: اول و مهمتر از همه",
    "back": "First and foremost"
  },
  {
    "id": "ff6639a7-7f8f-43d2-a082-32a125a4457f",
    "front": "**Def**: become worse. deterioration N.\n**Farsi**: بدتر شدن، وخیم‌تر شدن",
    "back": "deteriorate"
  },
  {
    "id": "45d4ee42-6ef9-44eb-a1a3-17a3e3e8f8d7",
    "front": "**Def**: the process of asking sb a lot of questions, especially in an aggressive way. interrogate sb v.\n**Farsi**: بازجویی، استنطاق",
    "back": "interrogation"
  },
  {
    "id": "a7cf21f1-13f3-4a37-9ffe-cf75a981a240",
    "front": "**Def**: comprehensive including everything or almost everything (comprehensive car/travel/health insurance). healthcare the service of providing medical care (also childcare = the care and supervision of small children). provision the act of providing sth (here, private health insurance).\n**Farsi**: تأمین جامع مراقبت‌های بهداشتی",
    "back": "comprehensive healthcare provision"
  },
  {
    "id": "c3566ff4-473e-4e9a-8410-ab19b07a9b52",
    "front": "**Def**: spend less money because there will be less available.\n**Farsi**: صرفه‌جویی کردن، کمربندها را بستن",
    "back": "tighten your belt"
  },
  {
    "id": "3b087686-5f4a-4571-9525-6c45e294e31d",
    "front": "**Def**: likely to happen.\n**Farsi**: محتمل، در شرف وقوع",
    "back": "on the cards"
  },
  {
    "id": "b78dc0e0-a5f0-41ec-8c21-856fecfd5a2f",
    "front": "**Def**: (of a person or policy) creating or controlling a situation by making things happen, rather than waiting for things to happen.\n**Farsi**: کنش‌گرا، پیشگیرانه",
    "back": "proactive"
  },
  {
    "id": "671133bc-1223-487e-8cb2-934339b7609e",
    "front": "**Def**: To examine a concept more thoroughly and in detail.\n**Farsi**: یک ایده را با عمق بیشتر بررسی کردن",
    "back": "explore the idea in more depth"
  },
  {
    "id": "5e492662-0ff6-499c-a1b1-34c295611f97",
    "front": "**Def**: Avoided making a decision or stating a clear opinion (idiom).\n**Farsi**: موضع نگرفتن، بی‌طرف ماندن",
    "back": "sat on the fence"
  },
  {
    "id": "f0c8d95f-765a-43a7-a73f-52eb1b753729",
    "front": "**Def**: make sb make a mistake which shows they have been lying.\n**Farsi**: مچ کسی را گرفتن، به دام انداختن",
    "back": "catch sb out"
  },
  {
    "id": "07f38894-2546-4246-bc46-e382740b4123",
    "front": "**Def**: obviously.\n**Farsi**: ناگفته پیداست، معلوم است که",
    "back": "needless to say"
  },
  {
    "id": "f409d87b-b6ce-4ac5-b182-d4fc9f18aa6b",
    "front": "**Def**: The way in which someone or something is represented or described.\n**Farsi**: تصویر، توصیف",
    "back": "portrayal"
  },
  {
    "id": "cabb1c51-ea0b-4e09-8a22-9fc0ba6233c6",
    "front": "**Def**: means 'it doesn't matter what (when, etc.)' or 'it isn't important what (when, etc.)'.\n**Farsi**: مهم نیست چه چیزی، هر آنچه که",
    "back": "no matter what/whatever"
  },
  {
    "id": "778a6349-b2b5-4b76-b21c-03dd5accbf02",
    "front": "**Def**: with the ability to understand a situation only after it has happened (with the benefit of hindsight).\n**Farsi**: با در نظر گرفتن نتیجه/با نگاه عقل پس از واقعه",
    "back": "with hindsight"
  },
  {
    "id": "a276aaef-8128-4449-b07a-c19049c9432b",
    "front": "حریف‌های دیرینه",
    "back": "Rivals"
  },
  {
    "id": "e43c8df5-5d07-42c6-a386-7b81f1f1c185",
    "front": "**Def**: relating to the treatment of illness (adjective form of THERAPY).\n**Farsi**: درمانی، شفابخش",
    "back": "therapeutic"
  },
  {
    "id": "85e2e739-9e2c-4192-b848-a066b69bbb09",
    "front": "**Def**: Open resistance; bold disobedience.\n**Farsi**: سرپیچی، نافرمانی",
    "back": "defiance"
  },
  {
    "id": "76abcebf-d45f-4261-907f-e96ab3fb6dde",
    "front": "**Def**: examine carefully (verb form of SCRUTINY).\n**Farsi**: به دقت بررسی کردن",
    "back": "scrutinize"
  },
  {
    "id": "fcf81480-7a04-4749-a752-0d06ff3fed5f",
    "front": "**Def**: intended to cause argument or reaction (adjective form of PROVOKE).\n**Farsi**: تحریک‌آمیز",
    "back": "provocative"
  },
  {
    "id": "798c07fe-cc67-478f-962e-72957eb61328",
    "front": "**Def**: The representation or expression of an idea, quality, or concept in a visible form.\n**Farsi**: تجسم، مظهر",
    "back": "embodiment"
  },
  {
    "id": "390b8640-71ef-40f8-b473-df1e75e656b2",
    "front": "**Def**: do sth harmful to sb because they harmed you first. retaliation N.\n**Farsi**: تلافی کردن، مقابله به مثل کردن",
    "back": "retaliate"
  },
  {
    "id": "f8b75852-9e2d-4e00-9f93-ef8f259edb8c",
    "front": "**Def**: twist or change facts, etc. so that they are no longer true.\n**Farsi**: چیزی را تحریف کردن/دگرگون کردن",
    "back": "distort sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "0bad23cf-e5f8-49f1-957b-e8e35ff532be",
    "front": "**Def**: accept and deal with a difficult situation without letting it worry you.\n**Farsi**: با آرامش با چیزی کنار آمدن/مواجه شدن",
    "back": "take sth in your stride"
  },
  {
    "id": "234459d4-1b48-475f-8a33-9785846027ba",
    "front": "**Def**: Behaving perfectly (usually children); well-behaved (simile).\n**Farsi**: بسیار مؤدب، مثل دسته گل",
    "back": "good as gold"
  },
  {
    "id": "b80e68fe-b5ee-4ee7-9cf0-ee6abe86c2ee",
    "front": "**Def**: Able to quickly recover from difficult conditions or misfortune.\n**Farsi**: انعطاف‌پذیر، مقاوم در برابر سختی",
    "back": "resilient"
  },
  {
    "id": "869b9136-6cea-40a2-b8e7-b054a4496fa9",
    "front": "**Def**: the state of being unknown to most people (noun form of ANONYMOUS).\n**Farsi**: گمنامی، بی‌نامی",
    "back": "anonymity"
  },
  {
    "id": "2f2478d0-6038-4d2f-934e-3d35a0d2e4ae",
    "front": "**Def**: having the same, or nearly the same, meaning. synonym N.\n**Farsi**: هم‌معنی، مترادف",
    "back": "synonymous"
  },
  {
    "id": "a618ab2e-0226-4c0d-bd0c-b790bb1c8d7c",
    "front": "**Def**: the meaning of a word or phrase.\n**Farsi**: معنی، مفهوم",
    "back": "sense (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f4f66824-c31b-4f59-901d-5e438b02adab",
    "front": "**Def**: if two things are interchangeable you can use one instead of the other and the effect will be the same.\n**Farsi**: قابل تعویض، جایگزین‌پذیر",
    "back": "interchangeable"
  },
  {
    "id": "1590e105-84af-4413-b915-3ff68377bb59",
    "front": "**Def**: not clear: able to be explained in different ways. ambiguity N.\n**Farsi**: مبهم، دوپهلو",
    "back": "ambiguous"
  },
  {
    "id": "a43f0ec3-67e4-45f7-b8ba-afeb006bb4ef",
    "front": "**Def**: qualities that exist and can be developed (fulfil/realize your potential = use your natural abilities to achieve what you hoped to achieve).\n**Farsi**: پتانسیل/استعداد",
    "back": "potential"
  },
  {
    "id": "32518fef-413d-4031-8fcb-a52df4b7b76b",
    "front": "**Def**: an annoying person or situation. (SYN a pain in the neck).\n**Farsi**: مایه عذاب/مزاحم",
    "back": "a (real) pain (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "874feea2-f035-4bca-8fe8-e66502e845cf",
    "front": "**Def**: decide that sth has a particular meaning. interpretation N.\n**Farsi**: تفسیر کردن، تعبیر کردن",
    "back": "interpret sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "18a1e871-bd6b-4964-a5c4-3bd657b85b15",
    "front": "**Def**: (of language) easy to understand. OPP opaque.\n**Farsi**: شفاف، واضح",
    "back": "transparent"
  },
  {
    "id": "21f417ac-0ae8-4ef9-b694-dc1c0aca698a",
    "front": "**Def**: easy to understand and not needing more explanation.\n**Farsi**: خودتوضیح، واضح",
    "back": "self-explanatory"
  },
  {
    "id": "798dd82a-5f58-462f-881e-fdb03f606154",
    "front": "**Def**: clear and accurate. SYN exact. precision N.\n**Farsi**: دقیق، مشخص",
    "back": "precise"
  },
  {
    "id": "50c511d9-26be-45b8-a2bd-255be7c19456",
    "front": "**Def**: almost; very nearly (virtually the same/impossible/certain).\n**Farsi**: تقریباً، عملاً",
    "back": "virtually"
  },
  {
    "id": "934de6f4-5b48-4ab4-90ac-96091b4f60e9",
    "front": "منسجم",
    "back": "Coherent "
  },
  {
    "id": "211e7bb3-83c9-4d14-9c2f-0bea3bae1437",
    "front": "**Def**: used to express doubts about a surprisingly good situation.\n**Farsi**: باور نکردنی (از خوشحالی زیاد)/خیلی خوب است که واقعی باشد",
    "back": "too good to be true"
  },
  {
    "id": "00c05970-6ccf-420b-a1c1-aea1e2c2a1f7",
    "front": "**Def**: the use of words to say the opposite of what you mean, often humorously (a trace/hint of irony = a little irony).\n**Farsi**: کنایه، وارونه‌گویی",
    "back": "irony (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b110732a-afcf-4fb5-b4b9-b51a3a096b44",
    "front": "**Def**: adjective form of irony.\n**Farsi**: کنایه‌آمیز",
    "back": "ironic (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f6ffd594-03c6-4be9-9326-1223f6f3b2a9",
    "front": "**Def**: the use of words to say the opposite of what you mean in order to be unpleasant to sb or make fun of sb.\n**Farsi**: طعنه، ریشخند",
    "back": "sarcasm (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "6ea73df1-2264-4292-8764-6e58769ce148",
    "front": "**Def**: adjective form of sarcasm.\n**Farsi**: طعنه‌آمیز",
    "back": "sarcastic (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "4dd58d8f-5ece-4372-83c0-a16b5763c548",
    "front": "**Def**: (of words) not used with their literal (= usual) meaning.\n**Farsi**: مجازی، استعاری",
    "back": "figurative"
  },
  {
    "id": "317febed-0834-4c09-ab8e-346055578ab1",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say that you think sth cannot be true and must be a joke. (SYNS You're joking, You can't be serious).\n**Farsi**: شوخی می‌کنی/جدی نمی‌گویی",
    "back": "You're kidding"
  },
  {
    "id": "355d1b3b-fc6a-424e-a210-e3a917482cea",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say that you can never be certain about future events, so anything is possible.\n**Farsi**: هیچ وقت معلوم نیست",
    "back": "you never know"
  },
  {
    "id": "1ebb14b8-0f9e-4e01-801c-0e22e0d80e50",
    "front": "**Def**: Showing/not showing kindness and forgiveness.\n**Farsi**: رحیم، دلسوز / بی‌رحم",
    "back": "merciful/merciless"
  },
  {
    "id": "80fb85b6-e4d7-4a31-9b4d-d8349cf96d84",
    "front": "**Def**: used of the kind of language you find in stories and poems.\n**Farsi**: ادبی",
    "back": "literary"
  },
  {
    "id": "78852559-96aa-4fb9-946b-4dc6c1f2a32b",
    "front": "**Def**: (often used in dictionaries) showing that sth is bad or wrong.\n**Farsi**: ناپسند، حاکی از عدم تأیید",
    "back": "disapproving"
  },
  {
    "id": "eccccdcc-a59f-4456-b786-077be98606d7",
    "front": "**Def**: no longer modern or fashionable. SYN dated. OPP in current use.\n**Farsi**: قدیمی، از مد افتاده",
    "back": "old-fashioned"
  },
  {
    "id": "67d8cc04-5c2d-4cbe-9ed9-ddb410fe9f4f",
    "front": "**Def**: the offering of money or another incentive to sb to persuade them to take part in an activity, usually something dishonest.\n**Farsi**: رشوه و فساد",
    "back": "bribery and corruption"
  },
  {
    "id": "20bfe6ca-cf40-4583-b71a-6e1d26c9b30f",
    "front": "**Def**: persuade them to do it.\n**Farsi**: کسی را برای انجام کاری متقاعد کردن",
    "back": "talk someone into doing something"
  },
  {
    "id": "a767331a-1409-4f91-9ca7-2c02645f14dc",
    "front": "**Def**: Having a high rank.\n**Farsi**: ارشد",
    "back": "senior OPP"
  },
  {
    "id": "832ae589-33ad-4a62-93fb-21b1933c8442",
    "front": "**Def**: taken there and treated.\n**Farsi**: بستری شدن در بیمارستان",
    "back": "admitted to hospital"
  },
  {
    "id": "cd21331f-1290-48e6-abe8-15343c5fb26f",
    "front": "**Def**: given permission to leave (hospital).\n**Farsi**: مرخص شدن",
    "back": "discharged"
  },
  {
    "id": "d31a5c88-91cd-424d-873c-06dd480ff46f",
    "front": "**Def**: spend time recovering. SYN recuperate.\n**Farsi**: نقاهت کردن، بهبودی یافتن",
    "back": "convalesce V"
  },
  {
    "id": "4ff055b1-f5f3-4091-8be6-ecf97560fbb0",
    "front": "**Def**: The process of recovering.\n**Farsi**: دوران نقاهت",
    "back": "convalescence N"
  },
  {
    "id": "7ceb1976-81fd-4b21-8938-8245a18e94ad",
    "front": "**Def**: To recover from illness.\n**Farsi**: بهبودی یافتن",
    "back": "recuperate V SYN"
  },
  {
    "id": "1bfd685e-b8f4-4501-be8b-a87a1cb23aab",
    "front": "**Def**: Provides with a quality, ability, or asset.\n**Farsi**: بخشیدن، اعطا کردن",
    "back": "endows (with)"
  },
  {
    "id": "19058da4-4ed1-4fc5-9c5f-4b0224bdffd2",
    "front": "**Def**: a bad memory.\n**Farsi**: حافظه ضعیف/مثل آبکش (ذهن)",
    "back": "mind like a sieve"
  },
  {
    "id": "f08bc237-f78a-4349-920c-934e25030f4a",
    "front": "**Def**: It is better to be careful than to take a risk or act too quickly and later regret it.\n**Farsi**: احتیاط شرط عقل است، پیشگیری بهتر از پشیمانی است",
    "back": "better safe than sorry"
  },
  {
    "id": "ac7f9d49-5cf8-4338-a01e-c9ae81b710bf",
    "front": "**Def**: uncomplicated and easy to understand. OPP convoluted.\n**Farsi**: رک و راست، صریح، ساده",
    "back": "straightforward"
  },
  {
    "id": "a2933d11-b361-4f9c-95ee-d2f3c1d2dadc",
    "front": "**Def**: very informal words which are not suitable in formal situations.\n**Farsi**: زبان عامیانه، کلام محاوره‌ای",
    "back": "slang"
  },
  {
    "id": "76ff569d-e5f5-40e9-be4a-9378b0d9d087",
    "front": "در نظر داشتن\nتامل‌کردن در...",
    "back": "Contemplate"
  },
  {
    "id": "8941f4a9-3269-4039-91b7-af15af8f138a",
    "front": "**Def**: FML expressing disapproval or criticism. SYN derogatory.\n**Farsi**: توهین‌آمیز، تحقیرکننده",
    "back": "pejorative"
  },
  {
    "id": "3fd64c4a-e627-4652-876e-9922d8605d83",
    "front": "**Def**: rude or offensive (deliberately/highly insulting). insult sb v\n**Farsi**: اهانت‌آمیز",
    "back": "insulting"
  },
  {
    "id": "0597a9d4-79b5-4e8f-bb60-f3a01429f444",
    "front": "**Def**: Represented or shown in a picture, story, or description.\n**Farsi**: به تصویر کشیده شده",
    "back": "depicted"
  },
  {
    "id": "5295ae4e-8f8c-4e29-98e2-17dd0a446a2e",
    "front": "به دوش کشیدن\nهمراه خود کشیدن",
    "back": "Drag along"
  },
  {
    "id": "bad7249d-b359-4691-9744-fab1009df3e0",
    "front": "**Def**: make jokes about them in an unkind way.\n**Farsi**: مسخره کردن کسی",
    "back": "make fun of someone"
  },
  {
    "id": "0d90b80a-9d1b-4f3e-a004-b11bde26843f",
    "front": "**Def**: make jokes about them in an unkind way.\n**Farsi**: شوخی کردن با، دست انداختن",
    "back": "poke fun at"
  },
  {
    "id": "c7b03e0b-1386-42fa-aa4e-a970c914f34a",
    "front": "**Def**: make fun of them, often by copying what they say or do.\n**Farsi**: تمسخر کردن، تقلید کردن برای ریشخند",
    "back": "mock"
  },
  {
    "id": "50aa84ce-700d-45c7-bf9b-0a5430b04581",
    "front": "**Def**: (of a vehicle) move very slowly.\n**Farsi**: خزیدن، بسیار آهسته حرکت کردن",
    "back": "crawl"
  },
  {
    "id": "4d8e46ad-cae7-4f5f-977c-355a72cb2a20",
    "front": "**Def**: Not influenced by personal feelings or opinions in considering and representing facts; impartiality.\n**Farsi**: عینی، عینیت",
    "back": "objective, objectivity"
  },
  {
    "id": "5d12ed8f-798b-4499-99a2-9ecda75c97a1",
    "front": "**Def**: Showing an unfair tendency or prejudice toward one side or group.\n**Farsi**: مغرض، سوگیری",
    "back": "biased, bias"
  },
  {
    "id": "1ee15531-aebb-4bdf-b15b-186fd8a4d678",
    "front": "**Def**: used to add a further comment which is usually a contrast or a surprise, but can also be an explanation. SYN still. (INF)\n**Farsi**: البته، با این حال، اما یادت باشد",
    "back": "mind you"
  },
  {
    "id": "4c52dc1f-5d38-4eb8-a1c4-122c9ebfb15c",
    "front": "**Def**: start having doubts about a decision you have made.\n**Farsi**: دچار تردید شدن، منصرف شدن",
    "back": "have second thoughts"
  },
  {
    "id": "e3d29585-44a5-47f1-bd52-4fb146b07ee3",
    "front": "**Def**: be unable to decide what to do about sth.\n**Farsi**: دودل بودن، مردد بودن",
    "back": "be in two minds about sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "ebc28578-1de0-4a83-bcd7-84122f8a9613",
    "front": "**Def**: kind (of sb).\n**Farsi**: مهربانانه، از روی لطف",
    "back": "sweet (of sb)"
  },
  {
    "id": "e586ba74-11bc-4c8a-8c6d-b15d40d64704",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say what you really think, or to introduce information which is not what the listener expects to hear. SYNS actually, to be honest, to tell you the truth.\n**Farsi**: در حقیقت، راستش را بخواهید، اتفاقاً",
    "back": "as a matter of fact"
  },
  {
    "id": "61dbdc82-3eaa-4592-886b-8c37c93e482a",
    "front": "**Def**: you can never be sure about sth because things are not always what they appear to be.\n**Farsi**: هیچ‌وقت نمی‌شود مطمئن بود",
    "back": "you can never tell"
  },
  {
    "id": "6649a510-8299-4a03-9b35-39fba7a905a8",
    "front": "معنی: طرفداری کردن، دفاع کردن از کسی یا چیزی (در فارسی)\nMeaning: to publicly support or recommend a particular cause or policy (in English",
    "back": "Advocate /ˈæd.və.keɪt/ — Example: “She advocates for equal rights for all people.” — Formal"
  },
  {
    "id": "f8b7350c-ac0b-438b-aaf7-6730d6be8e6a",
    "front": "**Def**: be busy and unable to do other things.\n**Farsi**: گرفتار بودن، سرش شلوغ بودن",
    "back": "be tied up"
  },
  {
    "id": "e9b46b7a-ee0a-4177-b182-692447cca70b",
    "front": "**Def**: a reason for doing sth that you keep hidden.\n**Farsi**: انگیزه پنهان",
    "back": "ulterior motive"
  },
  {
    "id": "76e477c3-8a2c-4235-a3bb-aeaf56ad9408",
    "front": "**Def**: INF stupid.\n**Farsi**: احمق، کودن",
    "back": "thick (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "6f91d69f-5e2a-4842-b719-463c4a69a0b6",
    "front": "**Def**: be the thing that sb is least likely to be thinking about.\n**Farsi**: اصلاً به فکرش نبودن",
    "back": "be the last thing on sb's mind"
  },
  {
    "id": "d0311de6-f6b6-4dbd-bf3a-1fd4ca23f5bb",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely dry.\n**Farsi**: مثل استخوان خشک",
    "back": "as dry as a bone"
  },
  {
    "id": "2769a685-a646-45ea-a473-38abec73fed6",
    "front": "**Def**: avoid doing sth.\n**Farsi**: قسر در رفتن، از زیر کاری در رفتن",
    "back": "get out of sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "79c592c4-783f-469d-8433-2f64fc35192e",
    "front": "**Def**: make sth/sb move quickly and without control.\n**Farsi**: به هوا پرتاب کردن، پرت کردن",
    "back": "send sth/sb flying"
  },
  {
    "id": "0c564784-38ae-4cbb-8f4f-424897e503a7",
    "front": "**Def**: used to introduce surprising and often unwelcome news (gonna INF = going to).\n**Farsi**: باور نخواهی کرد",
    "back": "you're not gonna believe this"
  },
  {
    "id": "d0b8fad3-3f6a-4de4-ba3d-f2051fe9e9e3",
    "front": "**Def**: used to introduce the reason for a decision. SYN considering sth.\n**Farsi**: به دلیل، با توجه به",
    "back": "in view of sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "b02693ad-e91a-4db5-910d-d02fa12a1bf0",
    "front": "نهادینه شده",
    "back": "Institutionalised "
  },
  {
    "id": "a175f012-4f5f-43fc-87cb-a87d161e1aaa",
    "front": "**Def**: make or persuade sb/sth to do sth.\n**Farsi**: متقاعد کردن، وادار کردن",
    "back": "get sth/sb to do sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "5b503175-7e75-4ed6-9ad2-89b13713fda0",
    "front": "**Def**: remain fresh.\n**Farsi**: تازه ماندن، خراب نشدن",
    "back": "keep (remain fresh)"
  },
  {
    "id": "1aed3780-ac46-4f3e-99a0-e4ee2e5c760c",
    "front": "**Def**: be enough for sb until a later time.\n**Farsi**: کافی بودن برای ادامه دادن",
    "back": "keep sb going"
  },
  {
    "id": "8c457157-ef07-40ec-a667-ba5931b9e1ca",
    "front": "**Def**: say or write sth in a particular way.\n**Farsi**: بیان کردن، به زبان آوردن",
    "back": "put sth (into words)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f80a4f3a-eaa4-4e53-ad97-7c4098a30511",
    "front": "**Def**: make sb work harder.\n**Farsi**: فشار آوردن، تشویق به تلاش بیشتر کردن",
    "back": "push sb/oneself"
  },
  {
    "id": "417c9b10-fc70-40a2-ad52-30ee657f5869",
    "front": "**Def**: allow sb to take care of sth.\n**Farsi**: سپردن کاری به کسی، واگذار کردن",
    "back": "leave sth to/with sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "e53f6d7d-5b4f-461e-81c1-82b146a08e1f",
    "front": "**Def**: think or calculate sth to be a particular time or number.\n**Farsi**: محاسبه کردن، تخمین زدن (زمان یا عدد)",
    "back": "make sth sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "a9245df5-b9d3-4c5f-a41b-7d7c8aa33e59",
    "front": "**Def**: cause sb to reach a particular condition or place.\n**Farsi**: باعث شدن، کشاندن",
    "back": "bring sb somewhere"
  },
  {
    "id": "3ae74a6c-9091-4721-834c-37d160253314",
    "front": "**Def**: be sold or produced with a particular feature.\n**Farsi**: به همراه داشتن، شامل بودن",
    "back": "come with"
  },
  {
    "id": "4aba9429-7199-4f9a-87be-74ba45d5cd76",
    "front": "**Def**: be sold or produced in different variations (colours, sizes, etc).\n**Farsi**: در دسترس بودن در (رنگ یا اندازه)",
    "back": "come in (colours/sizes)"
  },
  {
    "id": "889258eb-c788-4a4b-a500-f14643fb9347",
    "front": "**Def**: be enough or be acceptable in a particular situation.\n**Farsi**: کافی بودن، مناسب بودن",
    "back": "do (for sb/sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "e31b4a9b-b900-4dfe-843c-a197340a4266",
    "front": "**Def**: an official document that shows you are qualified to drive.\n**Farsi**: گواهینامه رانندگی",
    "back": "driving licence"
  },
  {
    "id": "18f4db3e-f594-4823-9c79-439fddb63a5f",
    "front": "**Def**: an official document showing when and where you were born.\n**Farsi**: شناسنامه، گواهی تولد",
    "back": "birth certificate"
  },
  {
    "id": "43b2b321-7900-4940-80ce-cd1007a19cec",
    "front": "**Def**: a part for a car or machine to replace an old or broken part.\n**Farsi**: قطعه یدکی",
    "back": "spare part"
  },
  {
    "id": "2457991f-cfcc-4f98-a2fe-23aa47035fb8",
    "front": "**Def**: a person walking past a place by chance.\n**Farsi**: رهگذر",
    "back": "passer-by"
  },
  {
    "id": "e9556cc3-c9dc-414a-8c74-e70a49a4b6d1",
    "front": "**Def**: a short holiday from Friday to Sunday, or Saturday to Monday.\n**Farsi**: آخر هفته طولانی (تعطیلی چند روزه)",
    "back": "long weekend"
  },
  {
    "id": "bc85408b-5624-4ece-9caf-3a931f87c80e",
    "front": "**Def**: the number of years that a person is likely to live.\n**Farsi**: امید به زندگی",
    "back": "life expectancy"
  },
  {
    "id": "7bf90e53-fa9b-4acf-a036-a4c607c41e23",
    "front": "**Def**: a path or route that is quicker than the normal way.\n**Farsi**: میان‌بُر",
    "back": "short cut / shortcut"
  },
  {
    "id": "f7ec5f7b-3290-4407-9b2e-620ce31ff717",
    "front": "**Def**: clothes that you wear to a party to make you appear a different character.\n**Farsi**: لباس مبدل، لباس فانتزی",
    "back": "fancy dress"
  },
  {
    "id": "5b222a7f-75c0-4050-8a48-750fc87cd6ec",
    "front": "**Def**: a short and usually very old song or poem for young children.\n**Farsi**: شعر کودکانه، لالایی",
    "back": "nursery rhyme"
  },
  {
    "id": "841cf609-1526-49b2-b876-5c36033c7ab9",
    "front": "**Def**: The process of recovering.\n**Farsi**: بهبودی، نقاهت",
    "back": "recuperation N"
  },
  {
    "id": "3f624e59-5a4a-43d3-8363-76d0c8e8440a",
    "front": "**Def**: If sth is inherent in sth, it is a natural part of it. SYN intrinsic.\n**Farsi**: ذاتی، درونی، جدایی‌ناپذیر",
    "back": "inherent (in sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "3bebed1b-f986-4989-a72b-9a63ba637d36",
    "front": "**Def**: a machine into which you put money in the hope of winning more back.\n**Farsi**: ماشین قمار، دستگاه اسلات",
    "back": "fruit/slot machine"
  },
  {
    "id": "9811bd83-de5b-4097-b12e-6d4f72d5c813",
    "front": "**Def**: your closest living relative (often used on official documents).\n**Farsi**: نزدیکترین خویشاوند",
    "back": "next of kin"
  },
  {
    "id": "05133aa7-2da6-4442-b673-64a955571a66",
    "front": "**Def**: happening at the last possible moment.\n**Farsi**: لحظه آخری",
    "back": "last-minute"
  },
  {
    "id": "c7eec3dd-6d64-4d1f-82e0-ef71e0ed5a9b",
    "front": "**Def**: A built-up area has a lot of houses and not many open spaces.\n**Farsi**: پرساختمان، توسعه‌یافته",
    "back": "built-up"
  },
  {
    "id": "2e83173f-ca8c-4908-a820-20ae24b79daa",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely anxious about sth.\n**Farsi**: وحشت‌زده، دستپاچه",
    "back": "panic-stricken"
  },
  {
    "id": "4ebbcdf6-4119-419a-b98c-8e2ea01c83d1",
    "front": "**Def**: not easily upset by unkind or critical comments.\n**Farsi**: پوست‌کلفت، بی‌تفاوت (به انتقاد)",
    "back": "thick-skinned"
  },
  {
    "id": "b3834b32-552b-48e3-98fc-101ee18bc54c",
    "front": "**Def**: (of behaviour) irritating or unattractive.\n**Farsi**: آزاردهنده، دافع",
    "back": "off-putting"
  },
  {
    "id": "6dc9e9c5-0cab-4fb6-b130-cbeedaac4a79",
    "front": "**Def**: unable to speak easily because of nerves or shyness.\n**Farsi**: زبانم بند آمده، قادر به سخن گفتن نبودن",
    "back": "tongue-tied"
  },
  {
    "id": "6c8b14b1-24bc-41f3-9954-6bc47d8d6bbb",
    "front": "**Def**: (of a thing) no longer useful because it has been used so much.\n**Farsi**: فرسوده، مستعمل",
    "back": "worn out (thing)"
  },
  {
    "id": "31d6c13b-8433-49b5-af7e-06701af47a37",
    "front": "**Def**: refuse to obey a law or rule, or a person. defiance N. defiant ADJ.\n**Farsi**: سرپیچی کردن، به مبارزه طلبیدن (قوانین)",
    "back": "defy sth/sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "cab3af05-5536-4437-9dd8-b88a59fac658",
    "front": "**Def**: the smallest unit (of two or more atoms) that a substance can be divided into, without changing its chemical nature.\n**Farsi**: مولکول (کوچکترین واحد (دو یا چند اتم) که یک ماده می‌تواند به آن تقسیم شود، بدون تغییر ماهیت شیمیایی آن)",
    "back": "molecule"
  },
  {
    "id": "fcda0e58-4435-4d85-8d57-5f5b4058fd1d",
    "front": "**Def**: Based on, concerned with, or verifiable by observation or experience rather than theory.\n**Farsi**: تجربی، مبتنی بر تجربه",
    "back": "empirical, empiricism"
  },
  {
    "id": "363aabef-3861-421e-8f66-00be59242c1b",
    "front": "**Def**: To check or prove that something is true or accurate.\n**Farsi**: راستی‌آزمایی، تأیید صحت",
    "back": "verify, verification"
  },
  {
    "id": "5381a191-3b72-4a9d-bdb4-383a679a1438",
    "front": "**Def**: To suggest an explanation for a group of facts or phenomena (a hypothesis).\n**Farsi**: فرضیه سازی کردن، فرضیه",
    "back": "hypothesize, hypothesis"
  },
  {
    "id": "c80344e1-e804-4633-bb41-c388bf7b8ae2",
    "front": "**Def**: To examine or inspect closely and thoroughly.\n**Farsi**: موشکافی کردن، بررسی دقیق",
    "back": "scrutinize, scrutiny"
  },
  {
    "id": "fba9d777-3cfc-474e-8c2e-7a3d57928dbe",
    "front": "**Def**: An aspect or side of something.\n**Farsi**: جنبه، وجه",
    "back": "facet"
  },
  {
    "id": "9e31f276-907d-423a-af5a-1b2a2b2babee",
    "front": "**Def**: Showing no prejudice for or against something; impartial.\n**Farsi**: بی‌طرف، غیرمغرضانه",
    "back": "unbiased"
  },
  {
    "id": "a3e9c716-c995-4752-ba54-bb4400540399",
    "front": "**Def**: (of a person) exhausted from work or exercise.\n**Farsi**: خسته و کوفته",
    "back": "worn out (person)"
  },
  {
    "id": "d66e82f2-2846-48a9-ab4f-252b3e48a067",
    "front": "**Def**: (of a product) remaining in good condition for a long time.\n**Farsi**: بادوام، مقاوم",
    "back": "hard-wearing"
  },
  {
    "id": "39b94a9a-077d-46ad-97ce-61ee86fa3430",
    "front": "**Def**: (especially of sth unpleasant) seeming to last for ever.\n**Farsi**: بی‌پایان",
    "back": "never-ending"
  },
  {
    "id": "ab6a09a6-f043-4dfe-8d3a-a5e58db02d4b",
    "front": "**Def**: often angry and easily annoyed.\n**Farsi**: بدخلق، کج‌خلق",
    "back": "bad-tempered"
  },
  {
    "id": "38983629-c47e-4152-89b6-a2723cc2ffa2",
    "front": "**Def**: not willing to listen to the ideas and opinions of others, SYN bigoted. OPPS broad-minded, open-minded.\n**Farsi**: کوته‌فکر، متحجر",
    "back": "narrow-minded"
  },
  {
    "id": "378e2447-5319-42f1-b96f-e6bef5b9a34e",
    "front": "**Def**: forgetful.\n**Farsi**: حواس‌پرت، فراموشکار",
    "back": "absent-minded"
  },
  {
    "id": "9677e456-e1f8-4ba9-a9fc-d368315994d1",
    "front": "**Def**: thinking in a concentrated way about sth and determined to achieve it.\n**Farsi**: هدفمند، مصمم",
    "back": "single-minded"
  },
  {
    "id": "354ad7e1-573c-436c-9b2f-296fe3acf6e8",
    "front": "**Def**: a disappointment. let sb down v.\n**Farsi**: ناامیدی، سرخوردگی",
    "back": "let-down (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "32bf5902-b422-4947-995f-202572c2212b",
    "front": "**Def**: leave school, college, a course, etc. without finishing your studies. dropout N.\n**Farsi**: ترک تحصیل کردن، انصراف دادن",
    "back": "drop out (of sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b3796de8-1fd2-4418-8c0f-7738e71ae196",
    "front": "**Def**: To reproduce or make an exact copy of.\n**Farsi**: تکرار کردن، کپی کردن",
    "back": "replicate"
  },
  {
    "id": "2a8bfef4-5482-495c-b0b0-019baac6faa1",
    "front": "**Def**: A collection of historical documents or records providing information about a place, institution, or group of people.\n**Farsi**: آرشیو، بایگانی",
    "back": "archive"
  },
  {
    "id": "d9746a17-cfb4-4ca8-9f7c-bac5fa5eb7e2",
    "front": "**Def**: the act or process of moving (sth can be in motion).\n**Farsi**: حرکت (عمل یا فرآیند جابجایی)",
    "back": "motion"
  },
  {
    "id": "2e3fe667-4ee7-4877-8623-dbb9e9acbd7a",
    "front": "**Def**: Protected against a particular disease or condition.\n**Farsi**: مصون، ایمن",
    "back": "immune"
  },
  {
    "id": "2dad1730-4f28-4260-af76-4b587d704f77",
    "front": "**Def**: the number of people who attend an event. turn out v.\n**Farsi**: تعداد شرکت‌کنندگان، حضور",
    "back": "turnout (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "90b99f40-1941-429c-8337-549c8aa5bf55",
    "front": "**Def**: large changes made in an organization to improve it. shake sth up v.\n**Farsi**: تحول بزرگ، دگرگونی",
    "back": "shake-up (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b384c30c-caa9-4b8e-acd6-3bec6d0d33e8",
    "front": "**Def**: (of a vehicle or machine) stop working. breakdown N.\n**Farsi**: خراب شدن (ماشین)",
    "back": "break down (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b4720f59-fca8-413d-9009-109c2663988c",
    "front": "**Def**: delay sth/sb. hold-up N.\n**Farsi**: معطل کردن، به تأخیر انداختن",
    "back": "hold sth/sb up (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "602599c4-541e-4d5d-a3f9-706acdcaa70c",
    "front": "**Def**: a long line of traffic, moving very slowly. tail back v.\n**Farsi**: ترافیک سنگین، صف طولانی ماشین",
    "back": "tailback (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "2abfbbdb-1320-4ba6-96ca-01c1291c118b",
    "front": "**Def**: a vehicle that is so badly damaged that it is not worth repairing. write sth off v.\n**Farsi**: اسقاطی، چیزی که ارزش تعمیر ندارد",
    "back": "write-off (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "d7fbce1c-87d3-49dc-8ee0-89ec0c7095f9",
    "front": "**Def**: the ending of a relationship or association. break up v.\n**Farsi**: جدایی، قطع رابطه",
    "back": "break-up (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f5af0018-8deb-41ba-9068-e0dc66aecea0",
    "front": "**Def**: a problem that delays or prevents progress, or makes a situation worse for sb. set sth/sb back v.\n**Farsi**: مشکل، مانع، شکست",
    "back": "setback (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "44447b1f-88a5-4cbd-8bf8-352c2e892ea4",
    "front": "**Def**: the start of something bad (e.g. war, disease).\n**Farsi**: شیوع، آغاز ناگهانی",
    "back": "outbreak (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "d548e28f-2063-4c2d-98a1-65a348824eab",
    "front": "**Def**: the amount of money spent.\n**Farsi**: هزینه، مخارج اولیه",
    "back": "outlay (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "1a7cacdd-6da7-4111-8ffb-963b98c39f12",
    "front": "**Def**: INF spend (money).\n**Farsi**: خرج کردن، هزینه کردن",
    "back": "lay out (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "83efaf44-2f17-4069-a3a4-3904915db89c",
    "front": "**Def**: made it start burning.\n**Farsi**: آتش زدن",
    "back": "set fire to"
  },
  {
    "id": "2473f714-682d-4738-9e25-5da81ff8dd3d",
    "front": "**Def**: start to burn.\n**Farsi**: آتش گرفتن",
    "back": "catch fire"
  },
  {
    "id": "67956932-626c-4f40-ab65-79303b340aa1",
    "front": "**Def**: the fire started.\n**Farsi**: آتش‌سوزی شروع شد",
    "back": "fire broke out"
  },
  {
    "id": "5a132410-8765-48c3-a1fc-df4971bdd201",
    "front": "**Def**: burning.\n**Farsi**: در حال سوختن بودن",
    "back": "be on fire"
  },
  {
    "id": "f81d53e4-de85-4c70-b21b-64dd6e665758",
    "front": "**Def**: the fire moved and covered a larger area.\n**Farsi**: آتش گسترش یافت",
    "back": "fire spread"
  },
  {
    "id": "e01bc564-14ff-4cbd-acc7-f2408ff95766",
    "front": "**Def**: suddenly began burning strongly.\n**Farsi**: شعله‌ور شدن ناگهانی",
    "back": "burst into flames"
  },
  {
    "id": "cf1c8510-4d46-49c6-9a8f-9e01f1020b97",
    "front": "**Def**: was destroyed by fire.\n**Farsi**: سوختن و نابود شدن در آتش",
    "back": "go up in flames"
  },
  {
    "id": "1c200d0a-3a26-4d7d-b771-cb299fe2633a",
    "front": "**Def**: To place, fit, or thrust (something) into another thing.\n**Farsi**: وارد کردن، جای دادن",
    "back": "insert/inserted"
  },
  {
    "id": "350c62a7-d795-49db-abe8-d05313b9dd9a",
    "front": "**Def**: fix sth firmly in position so that it cannot move.\n**Farsi**: محکم کردن، لنگر انداختن (چیزی را محکم در جای خود ثابت کردن تا نتواند حرکت کند)",
    "back": "anchor sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "04f87292-2b12-4764-bd3c-48a919385ddc",
    "front": "**Def**: the fire/flames became weak.\n**Farsi**: فروکش کردن، آرام شدن (آتش)",
    "back": "die down"
  },
  {
    "id": "2f3ee084-bb5a-44a2-8cfb-8cf19b5f3b13",
    "front": "**Def**: stop the fire burning. SYN extinguish the fire FML.\n**Farsi**: خاموش کردن آتش",
    "back": "put out the fire"
  },
  {
    "id": "3ea6d8cc-c04a-48f4-9fb8-56ad3b22fff3",
    "front": "**Def**: fires that occur in forests during hot summer months.\n**Farsi**: آتش‌سوزی جنگل",
    "back": "forest fires"
  },
  {
    "id": "986b1489-0d4e-4379-844b-92cd389b65e4",
    "front": "**Def**: started a fire for a purpose (e.g. in a fireplace or garden).\n**Farsi**: آتش روشن کردن",
    "back": "lit a fire"
  },
  {
    "id": "e69bfaeb-6767-4163-93dc-f325be8aa40c",
    "front": "**Def**: the fire stopped burning.\n**Farsi**: خاموش شدن (آتش)",
    "back": "went out (fire)"
  },
  {
    "id": "efa98bc9-62da-4a73-9958-f8a3cb180d01",
    "front": "**Def**: postscript (written at the end of a letter to add extra information)\n**Farsi**: پی‌نوشت (نوشته شده در پایان نامه برای اضافه کردن اطلاعات بیشتر)",
    "back": "PS"
  },
  {
    "id": "476164cd-ceb3-4b49-b37f-08f51f02d4af",
    "front": "**Def**: suddenly the lights stopped working.\n**Farsi**: برق رفت",
    "back": "lights went out"
  },
  {
    "id": "a89987b8-e45c-4033-aa4f-bca247afb680",
    "front": "**Def**: stop something from burning.\n**Farsi**: خاموش کردن (سیگار)",
    "back": "put out (a cigarette)"
  },
  {
    "id": "8c0c24f5-b365-4d74-9d89-381a0b18a16f",
    "front": "**Def**: an argument/conflict started.\n**Farsi**: دعوا شروع شد",
    "back": "fight broke out"
  },
  {
    "id": "c95c8e43-d6fb-4197-b31a-6ca490cce397",
    "front": "**Def**: suddenly started crying.\n**Farsi**: بنای گریه گذاشتن، ناگهان گریه کردن",
    "back": "burst into tears"
  },
  {
    "id": "abff8caa-687b-492e-a262-6f1755e9cc2e",
    "front": "**Def**: closed-circuit television, often used in a building to prevent crime.\n**Farsi**: تلویزیون مداربسته (اغلب در ساختمان برای جلوگیری از جرم استفاده می‌شود)",
    "back": "CCTV"
  },
  {
    "id": "cf992637-ea31-4292-b1cb-62fe33d51875",
    "front": "**Def**: very strong winds.\n**Farsi**: بادهای بسیار شدید/طوفانی",
    "back": "gale-force winds"
  },
  {
    "id": "a8632ad6-ac7b-4cad-ba13-62a87fa8a436",
    "front": "**Def**: a lot of difficulty. SYN great difficulty.\n**Farsi**: مشکل قابل توجه",
    "back": "considerable difficulty"
  },
  {
    "id": "21747eb6-8aba-4ce5-90a1-53194f0fa4c8",
    "front": "**Def**: a lot of damage. SYN widespread damage.\n**Farsi**: آسیب گسترده",
    "back": "extensive damage"
  },
  {
    "id": "abf06d71-57b4-4a93-a773-45287c4c1180",
    "front": "**Def**: a very noticeable accent. OPP slight accent.\n**Farsi**: لهجه قوی/غلیظ",
    "back": "strong accent"
  },
  {
    "id": "c076cc62-f8b8-43c7-b759-2e8d65f1a113",
    "front": "**Def**: an action or occasion that creates a feeling of pride.\n**Farsi**: افتخار بزرگ",
    "back": "great honour"
  },
  {
    "id": "e8b0b0f6-69a9-4894-9e9a-10addba24e68",
    "front": "**Def**: a big effort. SYNS special/concerted effort.\n**Farsi**: تلاش واقعی/زیاد",
    "back": "real effort"
  },
  {
    "id": "cf493427-fbb9-4ae3-b96d-ad02303c068b",
    "front": "**Def**: biggest worry. SYN principal concern (also growing concern = an increasing concern).\n**Farsi**: نگرانی اصلی",
    "back": "main concern"
  },
  {
    "id": "dbf4448d-75d9-4166-8399-3b8fb0b750c1",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who you recognize and know.\n**Farsi**: چهره آشنا",
    "back": "familiar face"
  },
  {
    "id": "343b2c54-8034-42fb-ba45-4a5ece29ea06",
    "front": "**Def**: a short statement giving the main points of sth.\n**Farsi**: خلاصه کوتاه",
    "back": "brief summary"
  },
  {
    "id": "1528ff9f-4139-4323-bb12-e0bfa749522f",
    "front": "**Def**: a very typical example of sth. SYN perfect example.\n**Farsi**: مثال کلاسیک/نمونه بارز",
    "back": "classic example"
  },
  {
    "id": "d0bdc740-4b7d-4554-9039-5457ef03c811",
    "front": "**Def**: a lot of disapproval from others. SYN fierce criticism (also widespread criticism).\n**Farsi**: انتقاد شدید",
    "back": "strong criticism"
  },
  {
    "id": "16fa5676-fb90-413a-b21c-6a1b4dd4098e",
    "front": "**Def**: a state of complete confusion. SYN total chaos.\n**Farsi**: هرج و مرج مطلق",
    "back": "utter chaos"
  },
  {
    "id": "97607856-1c84-4ffc-8e36-7cf91b53f469",
    "front": "**Def**: they were lucky to get away safely.\n**Farsi**: نجات یافتن به سختی، قسر در رفتن",
    "back": "narrow escape"
  },
  {
    "id": "6070c807-dbfd-4253-9939-88d178acfb13",
    "front": "**Def**: related to the inside of something, including the body.\n**Farsi**: داخلی",
    "back": "internal"
  },
  {
    "id": "97199627-68da-47d9-bf6b-87a0357dcb46",
    "front": "**Def**: Used to indicate that you are speaking frankly and sincerely.\n**Farsi**: راستش را بخواهی، صادقانه بگویم",
    "back": "to be honest"
  },
  {
    "id": "4428d17a-eb12-40be-b94a-401cd3eac29f",
    "front": "**Def**: To set up or found something; to prove (a fact or connection).\n**Farsi**: تأسیس کردن، اثبات کردن",
    "back": "establish"
  },
  {
    "id": "c4d1d94b-231e-4287-bc6d-478b79307d43",
    "front": "**Def**: Moving slowly and rhythmically backward and forward or from side to side.\n**Farsi**: تاب خوردن، نوسان کردن",
    "back": "swaying"
  },
  {
    "id": "38a4ea1e-6ec0-4655-866e-bc7b1896d48f",
    "front": "**Def**: To remain undamaged or unaffected by; to stand up against.\n**Farsi**: مقاومت کردن، تاب آوردن",
    "back": "withstand/resist"
  },
  {
    "id": "69d5ffc5-3a04-43d7-80f5-bb098ee20909",
    "front": "**Def**: show you are angry or upset about sth, or feeling insulted by it.\n**Farsi**: رنجیدن، به خود گرفتن",
    "back": "take offence (at sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "c84d0e98-9e62-411f-ab85-2098bc3c55ab",
    "front": "**Def**: say sth to make sb understand a situation.\n**Farsi**: واضح ساختن",
    "back": "make it clear (that)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b2e91966-918e-4ebd-bbc7-341b492b2228",
    "front": "**Def**: refuse to do the thing you have been asked to do.\n**Farsi**: چنین کاری را انجام ندادن",
    "back": "do no such thing"
  },
  {
    "id": "94c27115-b71d-490e-b6a0-f8639cbac931",
    "front": "**Def**: successfully arrive at an agreement (reach a conclusion/compromise/verdict).\n**Farsi**: به توافق رسیدن",
    "back": "reach (an) agreement"
  },
  {
    "id": "d0f92d18-2d7b-45af-b081-24581ad1f6d1",
    "front": "**Def**: recognize the possibility that sth may happen.\n**Farsi**: مواجه شدن با چشم‌انداز/احتمال",
    "back": "face the prospect (of/that...)"
  },
  {
    "id": "08d6099e-b9d7-48f2-a9af-9f1061ff29de",
    "front": "**Def**: end an argument between people (settle an argument).\n**Farsi**: حل اختلاف",
    "back": "settle a dispute"
  },
  {
    "id": "4e32672f-2bdb-44fa-9a04-e4e218a5a657",
    "front": "**Def**: think that sb should be blamed for sth.\n**Farsi**: مسئول دانستن کسی",
    "back": "hold sb responsible (for sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "71a1d43a-8166-4ba5-9e8c-726867b5293a",
    "front": "**Def**: accept responsibility for sth.\n**Farsi**: تقصیر را به گردن گرفتن",
    "back": "take the blame (for sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "639474b4-b90e-4846-86ea-df20e1bd2cc3",
    "front": "**Def**: the activity of being with and talking to people; the way that people react to each other. interact (with sb) v.\n**Farsi**: تعامل (فعالیت بودن و صحبت کردن با مردم؛ نحوه واکنش مردم نسبت به یکدیگر)",
    "back": "interaction"
  },
  {
    "id": "22879e76-8168-4dea-88de-2aecea2545bd",
    "front": "**Def**: stop asking for sth, or stop saying you will do sth.\n**Farsi**: عقب‌نشینی کردن، کوتاه آمدن",
    "back": "back down"
  },
  {
    "id": "0e52b35b-3f01-41ab-9877-a4bceb759e84",
    "front": "**Def**: completely.\n**Farsi**: کاملاً، به طور کامل",
    "back": "entirely"
  },
  {
    "id": "c27de8c2-889e-4dd8-bdfd-0f844fdcc005",
    "front": "**Def**: A limitation or restriction.\n**Farsi**: محدودیت‌ها، اجبارات",
    "back": "constraints"
  },
  {
    "id": "154be361-3b6b-4a21-b16d-c97313700d1a",
    "front": "**Def**: Flat sections forming part of a door, wall, or window.\n**Farsi**: پانل، صفحه",
    "back": "panels (glass or metal)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f0698b3c-023a-43f7-9c0f-fcce96423e5e",
    "front": "**Def**: To fasten securely so as to prevent movement.\n**Farsi**: محکم کردن، لنگر انداختن",
    "back": "anchor"
  },
  {
    "id": "4b9b20c9-33cb-489b-b26d-d727b3f69280",
    "front": "**Def**: examples of words using un- or under-.\n**Farsi**: نپخته/نیم‌پز، توسعه نیافته/توسعه نیافته، پرداخت نشده/حقوق کم داده شده، فروخته نشده/زیر قیمت فروخته شده",
    "back": "uncooked/undercooked, undeveloped/underdeveloped, unpaid/underpaid, unsold/undersold"
  },
  {
    "id": "c1ba3587-fc4d-4dad-a3ce-b72850f94324",
    "front": "**Def**: agree completely.\n**Farsi**: کاملاً موافق بودن",
    "back": "agree entirely"
  },
  {
    "id": "fc0d690f-87af-49b9-b0f7-bea7fb287ef0",
    "front": "**Def**: completely different.\n**Farsi**: کاملاً متفاوت",
    "back": "entirely different"
  },
  {
    "id": "b6899f11-b1d8-4c5d-88de-ee916685887a",
    "front": "**Def**: not completely (used to soften speech).\n**Farsi**: نه کاملاً، تا حدی",
    "back": "not entirely"
  },
  {
    "id": "bfa3b944-878d-43be-93f0-626beb076108",
    "front": "**Def**: to show the image of sb/sth on the surface of sth such as a mirror, water or glass.\n**Farsi**: منعکس کردن، بازتاباندن (تصویر)",
    "back": "reflect (1)"
  },
  {
    "id": "9eba14fe-4c52-4de3-99e5-f337bf71d3dd",
    "front": "**Def**: to think carefully and deeply about sth.\n**Farsi**: تفکر کردن، تأمل کردن (درباره چیزی)",
    "back": "reflect (4) (on/upon sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "c6ed975f-a87d-4092-8343-a9744f20773e",
    "front": "**Def**: to say numbers in the correct order.\n**Farsi**: شمردن (اعداد)",
    "back": "count (1) (SAY NUMBERS)"
  },
  {
    "id": "155bed0a-3f37-41fa-8cb0-9a1cd96c64a5",
    "front": "**Def**: People who reside or occupy a place.\n**Farsi**: ساکنین، اشغال‌کنندگان",
    "back": "occupants/residents"
  },
  {
    "id": "99eb7bef-2362-49ed-bd01-e563d5947ee2",
    "front": "**Def**: Large iron or steel beams used in construction to support structures.\n**Farsi**: تیرآهن، حائل",
    "back": "girders/supports"
  },
  {
    "id": "37ef312e-c5ed-4707-976e-9c177ffce708",
    "front": "**Def**: To act against something in order to reduce its force or neutralize it.\n**Farsi**: خنثی کردن، مقابله کردن",
    "back": "counteract"
  },
  {
    "id": "66f84681-5523-404e-b7fe-6b84d82cef9f",
    "front": "**Def**: If your vision is blurred you cannot see clearly.\n**Farsi**: تاری دید",
    "back": "blurred vision (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "fa5cfd91-f55d-4347-968d-53492afebfb8",
    "front": "**Def**: shut and open your eyes quickly.\n**Farsi**: پلک زدن",
    "back": "blink (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "446b1bb5-e6e6-4ba7-9b94-d40d232155fe",
    "front": "**Def**: a drop of liquid that comes out of your eye when you cry.\n**Farsi**: اشک",
    "back": "tear (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "165b031f-e67f-4bce-8738-9e4c3284f3bf",
    "front": "**Def**: painful, red, or swollen. irritation N.\n**Farsi**: تحریک شده، ملتهب",
    "back": "irritated (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "57945cf6-3057-4c0f-98da-bf5707573c95",
    "front": "**Def**: to include sb/sth when you calculate a total.\n**Farsi**: در شمار آوردن، محسوب کردن",
    "back": "count (3) (INCLUDE)"
  },
  {
    "id": "4d41d17f-a131-494c-a371-fd662b4cfeac",
    "front": "**Def**: to take in a liquid, gas or other substance from the surface or space around.\n**Farsi**: جذب کردن، فرو بردن (مایع/گاز)",
    "back": "absorb (1) (LIQUID/GAS)"
  },
  {
    "id": "84dbc6be-7a5b-4240-88ca-c94318aa3320",
    "front": "**Def**: to take sth into the mind and learn or understand it. SYN take in.\n**Farsi**: یاد گرفتن، درک کردن (اطلاعات)",
    "back": "absorb (3) (INFORMATION)"
  },
  {
    "id": "a0eaad51-78c6-4666-95bf-c1f37620e1af",
    "front": "**Def**: a thing that you do to help sb.\n**Farsi**: لطف، محبت",
    "back": "favour (1) (HELP)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b2de050a-a6dd-4a2d-b657-e6ff2acb0d05",
    "front": "**Def**: (formal) to suggest a plan, an idea, etc. for people to think about and decide on.\n**Farsi**: پیشنهاد کردن، طرح کردن (طرح یا ایده)",
    "back": "propose (1) (SUGGEST PLAN)"
  },
  {
    "id": "d5029f33-c337-42ef-8a59-e4f6528cda0c",
    "front": "**Def**: action expressing shame.\n**Farsi**: سر به زیر انداختن (از خجالت)",
    "back": "hang head"
  },
  {
    "id": "8f32f4f8-f216-4e5e-852c-3f3c500fd2f2",
    "front": "**Def**: action expressing anticipation or nervousness.\n**Farsi**: لب زدن (از انتظار یا نگرانی)",
    "back": "lick lips"
  },
  {
    "id": "6b94cbaf-3a7d-4cc5-b483-43ffa6e6b56f",
    "front": "**Def**: action expressing agreement.\n**Farsi**: سر تکان دادن (به نشانه موافقت)",
    "back": "nod head"
  },
  {
    "id": "51c1f8ce-0c78-4c05-b642-9725cd4e14d5",
    "front": "**Def**: action expressing inquiry or surprise.\n**Farsi**: ابرو بالا انداختن (از تعجب یا پرسش)",
    "back": "raise eyebrows"
  },
  {
    "id": "c055baca-b530-47d1-8a11-88bf23fa518e",
    "front": "**Def**: action expressing doubt or indifference.\n**Farsi**: شانه بالا انداختن (از بی‌تفاوتی یا تردید)",
    "back": "shrug shoulders"
  },
  {
    "id": "c889d72f-9148-4898-8aab-c9c1ded99594",
    "front": "**Def**: Strengthened by adding material (like steel bars to concrete).\n**Farsi**: تقویت شده، مستحکم شده",
    "back": "reinforced (concrete)"
  },
  {
    "id": "5dbcd39b-dbfa-48c2-8a1a-f83205e7b1dc",
    "front": "**Def**: Funny/Modest (often contrasted in meaning).\n**Farsi**: شوخ‌طبع/فروتن",
    "back": "humorous/humble"
  },
  {
    "id": "ad97cca6-97fe-4b72-a19a-6b8dd95e31ea",
    "front": "**Def**: action expressing anger.\n**Farsi**: پا کوبیدن (از عصبانیت)",
    "back": "stamp foot"
  },
  {
    "id": "ea923c7f-1b92-489d-bdf2-b4eeaa6d2f1b",
    "front": "**Def**: filled with or likely to result in (something undesirable).\n**Farsi**: آکنده از، پر از (معمولاً مشکلات)",
    "back": "fraught (ADJ) (with)"
  },
  {
    "id": "e28cf61e-eb19-4678-86a7-510b6fa31c04",
    "front": "**Def**: entirely lacking or free from.\n**Farsi**: فاقد، عاری از",
    "back": "devoid (ADJ) (of)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f44c22f0-5f52-4b49-89f7-f5d0f7516761",
    "front": "**Def**: protected against a specific disease or exempt from something unpleasant.\n**Farsi**: مصون، ایمن (در برابر)",
    "back": "immune (ADJ) (to)"
  },
  {
    "id": "1c48300f-c003-45e0-9aba-ad6a4981a5c4",
    "front": "**Def**: wrongly think that sb/sth is sb/sth else.\n**Farsi**: اشتباه گرفتن کسی/چیزی با کس/چیز دیگر",
    "back": "mistake sb/sth for sb/sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "de3f28bf-b183-47f2-847d-b8a5a9674033",
    "front": "**Def**: the thin pointed end of something.\n**Farsi**: نوک، سر",
    "back": "tip (of sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b1bf2e4d-d423-49b9-964e-243b8a58ee99",
    "front": "**Def**: having no purpose.\n**Farsi**: بی‌هدف، بی‌معنی",
    "back": "pointless (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "e86af2c5-2477-4d8d-9dc5-63837faf0b42",
    "front": "**Def**: a group of supporters.\n**Farsi**: طرفداران، پیروان",
    "back": "following (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "cc8d2e85-b2d3-4b9a-b501-ad6069799733",
    "front": "**Def**: showing no kindness or consideration. SYN cruel.\n**Farsi**: بی‌رحم، سنگدل",
    "back": "heartless (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "795f739a-5be3-4824-8279-975769816ef0",
    "front": "**Def**: Annoyed or dissatisfied.\n**Farsi**: ناراضی، ناخشنود",
    "back": "displeased"
  },
  {
    "id": "41464af0-3f78-4e6f-b07e-d6d43b70100e",
    "front": "**Def**: To bring back a memory or fact.\n**Farsi**: به یاد آوردن",
    "back": "remember/recall"
  },
  {
    "id": "c7114536-79a2-4a9e-a421-dd30c28e84cc",
    "front": "**Def**: Textspeak for great.\n**Farsi**: عالی (مخفف پیامکی)",
    "back": "gr8 (great)"
  },
  {
    "id": "02af8703-c9ac-4ca7-b9e5-44cd68294d17",
    "front": "**Def**: Textspeak for thanks.\n**Farsi**: مرسی (مخفف پیامکی)",
    "back": "thx (thanks)"
  },
  {
    "id": "e3365e2f-0e78-4ee6-8d2a-ec7986abac5f",
    "front": "**Def**: Textspeak for see you later.\n**Farsi**: بعداً می‌بینمت (مخفف پیامکی)",
    "back": "cul8r (see you later)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b603462d-3187-447d-b952-d60a7e9f8deb",
    "front": "**Def**: causing people to have strong emotions.\n**Farsi**: احساسی، برانگیزاننده احساسات",
    "back": "emotive (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "3e1572ac-30df-4e55-acad-c40decb18719",
    "front": "**Def**: showing you are sorry.\n**Farsi**: عذرخواه، متأسف",
    "back": "apologetic (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "03d8fff8-ed5a-41bb-9793-519fcf15fd1f",
    "front": "**Def**: so bad it cannot be forgiven. SYN inexcusable.\n**Farsi**: نابخشودنی، غیرقابل بخشش",
    "back": "unforgivable (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "0f852192-6ef5-4d97-b17d-77abd90be19f",
    "front": "**Def**: so extreme it is impossible to describe.\n**Farsi**: وصف‌ناپذیر، غیرقابل توصیف",
    "back": "indescribable (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "bf039f91-f047-44b5-97e5-b49567e3a83d",
    "front": "**Def**: easily noticed.\n**Farsi**: قابل توجه، آشکار",
    "back": "noticeable (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "8a421565-46f6-43f2-bec9-8f988b123fff",
    "front": "**Def**: (of a price or cost) including everything.\n**Farsi**: فراگیر، شامل همه چیز (همه خدمات)",
    "back": "inclusive (ADJ) (fully inclusive)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b4d8f8b2-323b-4aeb-a974-13478798b832",
    "front": "**Def**: similar; able to be compared.\n**Farsi**: قابل مقایسه، مشابه",
    "back": "comparable (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "fe3ae072-5a09-49c4-aea4-091b3d0a3f05",
    "front": "**Def**: having a good reputation; known to be good.\n**Farsi**: معتبر، خوشنام",
    "back": "reputable (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b210402c-0e71-4b40-8bc6-cbde2638a30f",
    "front": "**Def**: put furniture in a place.\n**Farsi**: مبله کردن، اثاثیه دادن",
    "back": "furnish (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f90c5d5c-dc0a-40d5-8aa6-5716298d94db",
    "front": "**Def**: containing furniture. OPP unfurnished.\n**Farsi**: مبله، اثاثیه‌دار",
    "back": "furnished (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "39e17da2-8b59-4362-93d5-c84daf3fd694",
    "front": "**Def**: not containing furniture.\n**Farsi**: بدون اثاثیه، غیرمبله",
    "back": "unfurnished (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "81648ad7-71a0-478c-a968-e7fc6a76f532",
    "front": "**Def**: make sth less unpleasant or painful. SYN alleviate sth.\n**Farsi**: تسکین دادن، کاهش دادن",
    "back": "ease sth (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "9d00181d-2088-458a-b548-9a88a4b91a70",
    "front": "**Def**: change sth slightly to make it more suitable. adjustment N.\n**Farsi**: تنظیم کردن، تطبیق دادن",
    "back": "adjust sth (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "0cd8fce3-a05b-47c0-90a6-ae1d3a7e3f92",
    "front": "**Def**: remove or get rid of sth. elimination N.\n**Farsi**: حذف کردن، از بین بردن",
    "back": "eliminate sth (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "8b885223-6454-4274-9ee0-8607d1cd9b16",
    "front": "**Def**: a bright, unpleasant light.\n**Farsi**: تابش خیره‌کننده، نور آزاردهنده",
    "back": "glare (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "50edfecf-b648-493d-b04f-03021a642615",
    "front": "**Def**: Textspeak/initialism used to state an opinion modestly.\n**Farsi**: به نظر حقیر من (مخفف پیامکی)",
    "back": "imho (in my humble opinion)"
  },
  {
    "id": "5128230d-3c9b-422d-b7d6-37a6fcc3dde2",
    "front": "**Def**: Textspeak for excellent.\n**Farsi**: عالی (مخفف پیامکی)",
    "back": "xlnt (excellent)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f3ab9bc8-5cad-41bd-b890-31912f941e89",
    "front": "**Def**: Textspeak/initialism for without.\n**Farsi**: بدون (مخفف پیامکی)",
    "back": "w/o (without)"
  },
  {
    "id": "d88d7463-cf17-4db8-8b66-84d440d3c094",
    "front": "**Def**: Textspeak for tomorrow.\n**Farsi**: فردا (مخفف پیامکی)",
    "back": "2moro (tomorrow)"
  },
  {
    "id": "53a0adc8-cc99-42f5-ad50-98f72efefd19",
    "front": "**Def**: slightly wet, often in a way that is useful or pleasant.\n**Farsi**: مرطوب",
    "back": "moist (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "eabbe0b3-ecb2-405c-9d9d-b97ab66dab54",
    "front": "**Def**: only able to see things if they are near you. OPP long-sighted.\n**Farsi**: نزدیک‌بین",
    "back": "short-sighted (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "a5812bcf-66de-480a-b316-44522c92ffec",
    "front": "**Def**: A person who can see very little.\n**Farsi**: کم‌بینا",
    "back": "partially sighted (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "2eb0c789-cb1f-49ac-a938-3caa5290b25d",
    "front": "**Def**: A short message added after the signature in a letter or email.\n**Farsi**: پی‌نوشت",
    "back": "PS (Postscript)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f2df3cde-8f47-4f06-b285-7e0bdb1068be",
    "front": "**Def**: Used to indicate the specific person or department a letter or message is intended for.\n**Farsi**: به توجه (رسمی)",
    "back": "attn/fao (for the attention of)"
  },
  {
    "id": "29ca07fd-77af-465f-adb6-4973a2df6974",
    "front": "**Def**: A television system in which signals are not publicly broadcast.\n**Farsi**: تلویزیون مداربسته",
    "back": "CCTV (Closed-Circuit Television)"
  },
  {
    "id": "c8f09381-cda6-4365-8d7f-189c079c1140",
    "front": "**Def**: A measure of general intelligence.\n**Farsi**: ضریب هوشی",
    "back": "IQ (Intelligence Quotient)"
  },
  {
    "id": "2ee25c69-833f-422f-af16-4f8bcf1b078d",
    "front": "**Def**: To diagnose an illness or problem incorrectly.\n**Farsi**: اشتباه تشخیص دادن",
    "back": "misdiagnose"
  },
  {
    "id": "d0c43f7e-89d0-45bf-9e51-165b5c58a7aa",
    "front": "**Def**: To treat someone or something badly or wrongly.\n**Farsi**: بدرفتاری کردن، بد مورد استفاده قرار دادن",
    "back": "mistreat"
  },
  {
    "id": "3bec889e-fd4a-45b8-a3ba-107bcbe68bb8",
    "front": "**Def**: To fail to produce the intended result.\n**Farsi**: ناکام ماندن، به هدف نخوردن",
    "back": "misfire"
  },
  {
    "id": "64984a9e-e76d-4ebb-8b9d-7b312ecf4771",
    "front": "**Def**: To lose something temporarily by putting it somewhere you can't remember.\n**Farsi**: گم کردن (موقت)، به اشتباه گذاشتن",
    "back": "mislay"
  },
  {
    "id": "1ac3a0c8-01b7-4dd4-ace8-445948e8009f",
    "front": "**Def**: To form a wrong opinion or conclusion about someone or something.\n**Farsi**: قضاوت اشتباه کردن",
    "back": "misjudge"
  },
  {
    "id": "239f624e-b27e-495e-a7e6-0699c35bb4a1",
    "front": "**Def**: Managed or dealt with badly or incompetently.\n**Farsi**: بد اداره شده، سوء مدیریت شده",
    "back": "mishandled/mismanaged"
  },
  {
    "id": "759e8f14-968d-4aff-8385-dceb8d62aa2b",
    "front": "**Def**: To make (a statement or situation) less confusing and more comprehensible.\n**Farsi**: شفاف کردن، توضیح دادن",
    "back": "clarify"
  },
  {
    "id": "4e193ad3-2ac8-405b-993b-61f63a2d1ea7",
    "front": "**Def**: To develop industry in (a country or region) on a wide scale.\n**Farsi**: صنعتی شدن",
    "back": "industrialize"
  },
  {
    "id": "467d56b7-d5a2-4c59-aa17-66f0e72517ed",
    "front": "**Def**: To charge with electricity; to excite greatly.\n**Farsi**: برق‌رسانی کردن، به هیجان آوردن",
    "back": "electrify"
  },
  {
    "id": "09d4f08c-b11a-4626-b4e4-862e80a1964f",
    "front": "**Def**: To be a typical example of.\n**Farsi**: مثالی از چیزی بودن، نمونه بودن",
    "back": "exemplify"
  },
  {
    "id": "4ce35dfa-beb6-4a0b-b664-70cfa3d10e69",
    "front": "**Def**: full of interesting or important things that happen. OPP uneventful.\n**Farsi**: پرماجرا، پرحادثه",
    "back": "eventful (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "797b26d7-b299-4370-964f-386d173eacc9",
    "front": "**Def**: that cannot be explained.\n**Farsi**: غیرقابل توضیح",
    "back": "inexplicable (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "0ce52ff8-672a-47f4-9d91-f6a09ff9f701",
    "front": "**Def**: acceptance that sth is true or legal.\n**Farsi**: پذیرش، به رسمیت شناختن",
    "back": "recognition (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f637fa9f-de95-4269-934c-12015d4055ec",
    "front": "**Def**: important, interesting, etc.\n**Farsi**: ارزشمند، مفید",
    "back": "worthwhile (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "a79fe317-c23d-45da-b43c-4f2270349fe2",
    "front": "**Def**: without value.\n**Farsi**: بی‌ارزش",
    "back": "worthless (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "cadefc86-da6c-4186-9788-522107902608",
    "front": "**Def**: deserving (to win/be respected).\n**Farsi**: شایسته، لایق",
    "back": "worthy (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "196db369-0fd2-47d9-adcb-f4e04fe6fc7e",
    "front": "**Def**: fill or use a space, area, or amount of time. occupied ADJ.\n**Farsi**: اشغال کردن، مشغول کردن",
    "back": "occupy sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "732a74a1-ea6b-47eb-b64a-86a86f97519e",
    "front": "**Def**: admit formally that you have done sth wrong or illegal. confession N.\n**Farsi**: اعتراف کردن",
    "back": "confess (to sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b501ad9b-91bd-4174-8a86-0a5ba1226fc4",
    "front": "**Def**: promise to do sth that requires time and loyalty. commitment N.\n**Farsi**: متعهد شدن، تعهد دادن",
    "back": "commit yourself"
  },
  {
    "id": "3b5c98b8-5d7c-4f6e-8068-009a669b83c4",
    "front": "**Def**: the cause of sth, or the place where it starts to exist. originate v.\n**Farsi**: منشأ، ریشه",
    "back": "origin (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "9d25291d-61a2-48b7-a5f9-ef0001e74ce3",
    "front": "**Def**: tell sb that sth is definitely true or definitely going to happen. assurance N.\n**Farsi**: اطمینان دادن",
    "back": "assure sb (that / of sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "bfaf269e-c126-4508-aa23-cd2e10fb1b8c",
    "front": "**Def**: make sth easier to do or understand. simplification N.\n**Farsi**: ساده کردن",
    "back": "simplify sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "a0079de8-2828-48a1-a5af-cce2735c8eaf",
    "front": "**Def**: treat sb in a cruel or violent way, often sexually. abuse N.\n**Farsi**: سوء استفاده کردن، بدرفتاری کردن",
    "back": "abuse sb (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f373e546-a7cf-461e-9971-022fd0ffcd82",
    "front": "**Def**: protect sb or yourself. defenceless ADJ.\n**Farsi**: دفاع کردن، محافظت کردن",
    "back": "defend sb/yourself"
  },
  {
    "id": "04f4c0ee-276f-4ba8-a5ae-7ba136633e28",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely bad or serious. severity N.\n**Farsi**: شدید، وخیم",
    "back": "severe (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f302d44e-6b08-4109-a47a-269e88dd6011",
    "front": "**Def**: (of babies, puppies, etc.) pretty and attractive.\n**Farsi**: بامزه، دوست‌داشتنی",
    "back": "cute (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "6212522d-6eab-4256-8a4e-d3e5c7bca781",
    "front": "**Def**: slightly fat, but in an attractive way (chubby cheeks/fingers).\n**Farsi**: تپل، گوشتالو (به طرز جذاب)",
    "back": "chubby (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "8b1ccb4c-abb4-4621-a4d8-0b4830166590",
    "front": "**Def**: show sth you are proud of.\n**Farsi**: خودنمایی کردن، به رخ کشیدن",
    "back": "show sth off (PHR V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "9eb1eded-c7db-4883-8071-60bd47db21c2",
    "front": "**Def**: a fat stomach on a man.\n**Farsi**: شکم، آبجوخوری (در مردان)",
    "back": "paunch (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "91b33d3b-37f1-4cbc-ad2b-198fb4d65dc3",
    "front": "**Def**: 1 be or push out further than sth else. 2 be noticeable.\n**Farsi**: بیرون زدن، برجسته بودن",
    "back": "stick out (PHR V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "2c1ecc04-d8db-4bda-a128-7dafeeb21b18",
    "front": "**Def**: be nearly a particular age, time, or number.\n**Farsi**: نزدیک شدن به سن/زمان خاص",
    "back": "be getting on for sth (PHR V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b842a9d9-1eb7-48fb-957d-b0cc40c58e29",
    "front": "**Def**: (especially of an old person) physically weak and thin. frailty N.\n**Farsi**: ضعیف، نحیف",
    "back": "frail (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "6b03f6fc-a76f-42be-9c2c-cae909a8dfa5",
    "front": "**Def**: walks slowly and shakily because they are frail.\n**Farsi**: متزلزل، لرزان (معمولاً به دلیل پیری)",
    "back": "doddery (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "9b476e26-1852-4ec6-b1ae-9c55bbfac01a",
    "front": "**Def**: to make straight (form from straight + -en).\n**Farsi**: صاف کردن، راست کردن",
    "back": "straighten (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "d640b2df-7f95-4252-a612-e76f9b156588",
    "front": "**Def**: the thing that makes you able to understand or achieve sth. SYN the secret of sth.\n**Farsi**: کلید، رمز اصلی (برای دستیابی به چیزی)",
    "back": "the key to sth (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "80b716c4-61b4-4f96-a57b-6a71d54817c8",
    "front": "**Def**: increase or improve the quality, value, or status of sth.\n**Farsi**: بهبود بخشیدن، ارتقا دادن",
    "back": "enhance sth (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "52f400d1-2d11-4c27-a640-938eca190d6f",
    "front": "**Def**: a part of sb's face or body.\n**Farsi**: ویژگی، قسمت برجسته (صورت یا بدن)",
    "back": "feature (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "3307007c-b243-467c-a616-f8735dda579e",
    "front": "**Def**: very impressive. SYN spectacular.\n**Farsi**: نفس‌گیر، شگفت‌انگیز",
    "back": "breathtaking (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "d41b3442-5c9c-4d8b-ab8c-f41a4d974db3",
    "front": "**Def**: only with great difficulty or effort. SYN only just.\n**Farsi**: به سختی، به زور",
    "back": "barely (ADV)"
  },
  {
    "id": "ea36d3cc-099b-4bda-9320-b6bd64e545a3",
    "front": "**Def**: A thing that is visible can be seen. OPP invisible.\n**Farsi**: قابل دید، مرئی",
    "back": "visible (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "7c9eb894-c7d2-47ad-a146-e827ac1c86b6",
    "front": "**Def**: smoke, dust, or mist in the air which is hard to see through. hazy ADJ.\n**Farsi**: مه رقیق، غبار",
    "back": "haze (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "bbb8ad68-37f6-4300-aed1-da8c13b6fd1b",
    "front": "**Def**: see, hear, or understand sth/sb with difficulty.\n**Farsi**: تشخیص دادن، متوجه شدن",
    "back": "make sth/sb out (PHR V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "e4fe4b09-7b3a-462c-8408-8bd1f8b146d0",
    "front": "**Def**: appear. OPP disappear from view/sight.\n**Farsi**: در معرض دید قرار گرفتن، پدیدار شدن",
    "back": "come into view/sight (PHR)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b06f91e9-44b9-4dca-84d1-eeb266b5b8bc",
    "front": "**Def**: stand without moving (also keep/stay/sit still).\n**Farsi**: ثابت ایستادن، بی‌حرکت ماندن",
    "back": "stand still (PHR)"
  },
  {
    "id": "4085a6f4-95e9-4bae-a6dd-94894d09fcec",
    "front": "**Def**: look at sb/sth carefully or because you are suspicious of them/it.\n**Farsi**: زیر نظر گرفتن، نگاه کردن (با سوءظن)",
    "back": "eye sb/sth (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "32e1d754-ecce-4404-8b21-65b4cb540d1d",
    "front": "**Def**: carefully, because you think there may be danger or a problem.\n**Farsi**: با احتیاط، محتاطانه",
    "back": "warily (ADV)"
  },
  {
    "id": "e5ce5a0b-1b36-489d-a341-efba6eeed4f0",
    "front": "**Def**: disappear suddenly or in a way you cannot explain.\n**Farsi**: غیب شدن، ناپدید شدن",
    "back": "vanish into thin air (PHR)"
  },
  {
    "id": "be8cba32-4c52-454c-90ae-93329e362fa4",
    "front": "**Def**: to see them for a very short time and not clearly or completely.\n**Farsi**: لحظه‌ای دیدن، نگاهی اجمالی انداختن",
    "back": "catch a glimpse of sth/sb (PHR)"
  },
  {
    "id": "777b6095-2e0c-428b-a294-38aabe01fbd2",
    "front": "**Def**: to see them suddenly, often when you have been hoping to see them.\n**Farsi**: ناگهان دیدن، چشمش به چیزی افتادن",
    "back": "catch sight of sb/sth (PHR)"
  },
  {
    "id": "0a06eee0-3fda-4a07-b362-70cef993cd96",
    "front": "**Def**: to see them suddenly, especially when they are hard to see.\n**Farsi**: ناگهان دیدن (در شرایط دشوار)",
    "back": "spot sb/sth (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b55a58dd-7a90-4262-9c94-548d49e07af1",
    "front": "**Def**: rub or knead the body’s muscles.\n**Farsi**: ماساژ دادن",
    "back": "massage (V/N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f0449857-ad07-46c4-9869-3d130c05c6b4",
    "front": "**Def**: move or make sth move easily over a smooth or wet surface.\n**Farsi**: لغزیدن، سُر خوردن",
    "back": "slide (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "5a38e125-7159-475b-873c-f8efbdf21e32",
    "front": "**Def**: press on sth hard with your hand, foot, etc.\n**Farsi**: فشار وارد کردن",
    "back": "apply pressure to sth (PHR)"
  },
  {
    "id": "a14cadd6-89c2-4891-904d-3de8c3d1a6a8",
    "front": "**Def**: make a part of the body or skin more active.\n**Farsi**: تحریک کردن",
    "back": "stimulate sth (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "29830eee-561d-478c-b24a-638ff4965c12",
    "front": "**Def**: touch sth lightly several times with your hand flat.\n**Farsi**: ضربه آرام زدن، دستمالی کردن (آرام)",
    "back": "pat sth (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "1435a2ac-1c56-4260-9dc7-e8068e1d4cd6",
    "front": "**Def**: hold sth tightly between the thumb and finger.\n**Farsi**: نیشگون گرفتن",
    "back": "pinch sth (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "34d85fb8-f595-4e44-89cd-e5322af2045b",
    "front": "**Def**: the feeling you have if your muscles are tight and not relaxed (release the tension = allow or cause the muscles to relax).\n**Farsi**: تنش، گرفتگی عضلانی",
    "back": "tension (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "12de5e5c-b0a1-4c34-a1e2-a03f2221fb63",
    "front": "**Def**: press sth firmly with your fingers.\n**Farsi**: فشار دادن، چلاندن",
    "back": "squeeze sth (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "ead84e5b-7190-4702-904c-59ca0d55cf35",
    "front": "**Def**: describe soft, relaxed movements.\n**Farsi**: به آرامی، ملایم",
    "back": "gently (ADV)"
  },
  {
    "id": "1e7f5c13-ab79-48be-b922-9b8c5db280c6",
    "front": "**Def**: describe soft, relaxed movements.\n**Farsi**: به آرامی، سبک",
    "back": "lightly (ADV)"
  },
  {
    "id": "780667da-1efe-4c3c-8716-a5b149b19877",
    "front": "**Def**: with much stronger force.\n**Farsi**: محکم، قاطعانه",
    "back": "firmly (ADV)"
  },
  {
    "id": "36b16fbc-d429-41ae-a400-5d2047665fa9",
    "front": "**Def**: regular, controlled movements.\n**Farsi**: پیوسته، با ثبات",
    "back": "steadily (ADV)"
  },
  {
    "id": "8bfa6edd-54b2-4d9a-a342-25d60571bfc3",
    "front": "**Def**: in a very energetic and active way. SYN energetically.\n**Farsi**: پرانرژی، با قدرت",
    "back": "vigorously (ADV)"
  },
  {
    "id": "8a000966-2d6c-410d-b880-c4aa7de71806",
    "front": "**Def**: light and pleasant. SYN subtle.\n**Farsi**: طعم/عطر لطیف",
    "back": "delicate flavour/fragrance (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "d92edd1b-fbf6-4716-9a51-298b0e377c6a",
    "front": "**Def**: a pleasant smell. fragrant ADJ.\n**Farsi**: عطر، بوی خوش",
    "back": "fragrance (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "ae7570b1-2039-4aab-aa99-be01804635ac",
    "front": "**Def**: just possible to smell, see, or hear.\n**Farsi**: ضعیف، کم‌رنگ",
    "back": "faint (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "43ba693b-608a-44c0-adf3-634de6b080cf",
    "front": "**Def**: making you feel hungry. OPP unappetizing.\n**Farsi**: اشتها‌آور",
    "back": "appetizing (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "7e6e8483-1290-4a4d-b84e-7b02dd60744e",
    "front": "**Def**: a pleasant, distinctive smell.\n**Farsi**: عطر، بوی مطبوع",
    "back": "aroma (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b8b0ba15-68d0-4cad-9eff-c67c925c59c6",
    "front": "**Def**: not having much taste. SYN bland.\n**Farsi**: بی‌مزه، بی‌طعم",
    "back": "insipid (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f8061c65-7af9-4b38-bf5c-c44a2a62a79c",
    "front": "**Def**: very strong smelling.\n**Farsi**: تند، زننده (بو)",
    "back": "pungent (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "0ab009df-e316-4199-baff-1cb902700eb6",
    "front": "**Def**: smelling unpleasant or damp; without freshness. SYN dank.\n**Farsi**: کهنه، نمور، بوی گندیده",
    "back": "musty (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "ff672a5c-7ff9-4526-8b9b-aae2834a9bde",
    "front": "**Def**: a smell, especially an unpleasant one.\n**Farsi**: بو (بوی نامطبوع)",
    "back": "odour (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "91c25e64-ad4a-4aa2-990f-c92aa2be7e3a",
    "front": "**Def**: very unpleasant. SYN disgusting.\n**Farsi**: منزجر کننده، چندش‌آور",
    "back": "revolting (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "2d42eff4-33ae-413b-9a23-febaf4b5ec5d",
    "front": "**Def**: (of food and drink) go bad and be unfit to eat or drink.\n**Farsi**: فاسد شدن (غذا)",
    "back": "go off (PHR V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "affea6f1-06ac-4256-a589-0d896527036e",
    "front": "**Def**: making you feel you want to vomit.\n**Farsi**: حالت تهوع‌آور",
    "back": "nauseating (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "6c8930e6-afff-4329-96f4-745f4a1a40b7",
    "front": "**Def**: a strong, very unpleasant smell.\n**Farsi**: بوی گند، بوی تعفن",
    "back": "stench (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "52a332f5-f681-4455-b883-94633c8822a5",
    "front": "**Def**: the skin covering the part of the head where your hair is. If it itches (or is itchy), you want to scratch it.\n**Farsi**: پوست سر خارش‌دار",
    "back": "itchy scalp"
  },
  {
    "id": "d5f7a874-0c4c-43dc-9ecc-d5b084056197",
    "front": "**Def**: a very bad headache.\n**Farsi**: سردرد شدید/وحشتناک",
    "back": "splitting headache"
  },
  {
    "id": "2c80d6c3-2289-4e3b-ba52-95ea6e67361d",
    "front": "**Def**: an allergy affecting the nose, eyes, and throat, caused by pollen from plants.\n**Farsi**: تب یونجه (حساسیت فصلی)",
    "back": "hay fever"
  },
  {
    "id": "854f9625-4314-44ac-a0f0-849724729f0c",
    "front": "**Def**: small sore areas inside the mouth, usually lasting a few days.\n**Farsi**: آفت دهان",
    "back": "mouth ulcers"
  },
  {
    "id": "c7ca9c62-721d-48a3-97ad-1fabe8071a45",
    "front": "**Def**: put a bone out of its normal position.\n**Farsi**: در رفتن استخوان",
    "back": "dislocate sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "158dfeba-76e7-4d0b-aaf1-67d03ef3723b",
    "front": "**Def**: an area of red spots on the skin, caused by an illness or a reaction to sth.\n**Farsi**: بثورات/جوش پوستی",
    "back": "rash"
  },
  {
    "id": "caa1556d-630c-4631-87a0-c0a443edc91b",
    "front": "**Def**: unpleasant (also a nasty accident).\n**Farsi**: ناخوشایند/بد",
    "back": "nasty"
  },
  {
    "id": "42b31110-2012-4e1e-93c0-68424844fc05",
    "front": "**Def**: a stomach problem causing sickness or diarrhoea.\n**Farsi**: ناراحتی معده",
    "back": "upset stomach"
  },
  {
    "id": "1e71fd89-28c2-4e1a-a9f3-a59e09c51dca",
    "front": "**Def**: passing waste from the body too often and in liquid form.\n**Farsi**: اسهال",
    "back": "diarrhoea"
  },
  {
    "id": "72608933-acc1-4f33-8350-02b86629b4ef",
    "front": "**Def**: unable to move waste material from the body. constipation N.\n**Farsi**: دچار یبوست",
    "back": "constipated"
  },
  {
    "id": "4630ff1e-90e7-40ef-b156-24a211cc3b39",
    "front": "**Def**: the pressure of the blood as it moves round the body. (High and low blood pressure are problem conditions.)\n**Farsi**: فشار خون بالا",
    "back": "high blood pressure"
  },
  {
    "id": "1da82616-6a2f-4020-a452-217f7ed13f4a",
    "front": "**Def**: injure a part of the body (usually the wrist or ankle) by turning it suddenly.\n**Farsi**: رگ به رگ شدن/پیچ خوردن",
    "back": "sprain sth (SYN twist sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "98ae9560-6831-416f-bc96-a7f4090d4880",
    "front": "**Def**: injure a muscle by stretching it too much.\n**Farsi**: کشیدگی عضله",
    "back": "pull a muscle"
  },
  {
    "id": "c7c03f61-ee34-4920-97e8-4dbb04df2787",
    "front": "**Def**: a sore swelling on the surface of the skin (here on the back of the foot) often caused by rubbing or burning.\n**Farsi**: تاول",
    "back": "blister"
  },
  {
    "id": "dbe0feae-c821-4198-8d68-3549891ece80",
    "front": "**Def**: mix a solid with a liquid until it becomes part of it.\n**Farsi**: حل کردن (در مایع)",
    "back": "dissolve sth (in sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "08c6d5fe-87d1-427e-9007-aed4c4d003fa",
    "front": "**Def**: (If sth is soluble it can be dissolved, e.g. soluble aspirin.)\n**Farsi**: حل شدنی",
    "back": "soluble"
  },
  {
    "id": "fce11f19-5fc0-45fb-b3d7-4d5fb72f67d7",
    "front": "**Def**: the state of not having any energy to do things. lethargic ADJ.\n**Farsi**: بی‌حالی/کسالت",
    "back": "lethargy"
  },
  {
    "id": "551eff4f-3fc0-4ef0-8ea8-453a271f96e0",
    "front": "**Def**: the state of feeling tired and almost asleep. drowsy ADJ.\n**Farsi**: خواب‌آلودگی",
    "back": "drowsiness"
  },
  {
    "id": "e612bfa6-6535-4b56-8519-32d6a72c4bd4",
    "front": "**Def**: lasting only a short period, e.g. a short-term solution. OPP long-term.\n**Farsi**: کوتاه‌مدت",
    "back": "short-term"
  },
  {
    "id": "7dd25d54-c4c2-4c59-a265-3fc14381001f",
    "front": "**Def**: the amount of a medicine that you take at any one time.\n**Farsi**: دوز/مقدار مصرف",
    "back": "dose (or dosage)"
  },
  {
    "id": "3255970a-6826-4f3f-8dd9-db3b75139020",
    "front": "**Def**: included inside sth else, usually inside a letter or packet.\n**Farsi**: ضمیمه شده",
    "back": "enclosed"
  },
  {
    "id": "6bc23e6c-6560-4e88-800a-9c35ed618ee5",
    "front": "**Def**: one or several pages of information about sth.\n**Farsi**: بروشور/راهنما",
    "back": "leaflet"
  },
  {
    "id": "fe91c19d-353f-4b28-bdd9-c57224f2ff35",
    "front": "**Def**: get rid of sth you no longer want or need.\n**Farsi**: دور انداختن",
    "back": "discard sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "b8858010-f6da-41ad-a776-79709096dc4b",
    "front": "**Def**: the date after which sth should not be used. expire v.\n**Farsi**: تاریخ انقضا",
    "back": "expiry date"
  },
  {
    "id": "e47f47fc-4c24-42c0-8af8-461e5205f4ab",
    "front": "**Def**: 1. do more of sth than is stated in an order or a law. 2. be greater than a number, amount, or quality.\n**Farsi**: تجاوز کردن از حد/بیشتر بودن",
    "back": "exceed"
  },
  {
    "id": "85e05203-2cb9-4f0b-a2e4-ab0fa65e42e6",
    "front": "**Def**: be greater than a number, amount, or quality.\n**Farsi**: بیش از/فراتر از",
    "back": "in excess of"
  },
  {
    "id": "f552f01c-22be-4743-97b9-cc498a449686",
    "front": "**Def**: acting in an open and natural way, without worrying about what you say or do. spontaneity N.\n**Farsi**: خودجوش/بی‌نقشه",
    "back": "spontaneous (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "2b80cdfd-4d82-4595-af13-943f43e1dc19",
    "front": "**Def**: the quality of being spontaneous.\n**Farsi**: خودجوشی",
    "back": "spontaneity (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "a2aa55f2-4868-4638-b8a5-859842b5cd50",
    "front": "**Def**: not caring or worrying about the future.\n**Farsi**: بی‌خیال/فارغ از غم",
    "back": "happy-go-lucky"
  },
  {
    "id": "c869e720-d2fd-499c-9e42-08870c2be154",
    "front": "**Def**: sensible and realistic in things you say or think.\n**Farsi**: واقع‌بین/منطقی",
    "back": "down-to-earth"
  },
  {
    "id": "a5bb540e-0468-403e-9d64-b82b21c20a7e",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who talks a lot. chatty ADJ.\n**Farsi**: وراج/پر حرف",
    "back": "chatterbox (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f43f2534-acf8-4c66-b02c-96f19c3cdec7",
    "front": "**Def**: very enthusiastic or interested in sth. passion (for sth) N.\n**Farsi**: پرشور/علاقه‌مند",
    "back": "passionate (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "1a1ca1c2-d5dd-4874-97d3-f991896de2ed",
    "front": "**Def**: be prepared to try sth. SYN have a go, give sth a try.\n**Farsi**: چیزی را امتحان کردن",
    "back": "give sth a go (SYN have a go)"
  },
  {
    "id": "38995b6a-befe-4838-984d-f8630c67afb4",
    "front": "**Def**: according to what is practical, possible, or sensible.\n**Farsi**: در حد معقول/منطقی",
    "back": "within reason"
  },
  {
    "id": "8a96a525-b7a3-421a-9e9b-5fb53bd6f91a",
    "front": "**Def**: be attracted to sb/sth.\n**Farsi**: جذب چیزی/کسی شدن",
    "back": "be drawn to sth/sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "3b3777ab-6ffa-46d6-b903-709f63f85c18",
    "front": "**Def**: always thinking about other people's wishes and feelings. OPP inconsiderate.\n**Farsi**: با ملاحظه/متفکر",
    "back": "considerate (SYN thoughtful)"
  },
  {
    "id": "c36fde28-9afb-46ff-a08c-09ebaa1721d0",
    "front": "**Def**: the feeling of liking or caring about sth/sb. affectionate ADJ.\n**Farsi**: محبت/علاقه",
    "back": "affection"
  },
  {
    "id": "cf3e8253-9e8c-4899-a493-bc972f75fb92",
    "front": "**Def**: the quality of being honest and having strong moral principles.\n**Farsi**: درستکاری/صداقت",
    "back": "integrity"
  },
  {
    "id": "f21b4f3d-c69c-4023-a6f4-db47304f820e",
    "front": "**Def**: trying to appear important, intelligent, etc. to impress others.\n**Farsi**: متظاهر/پر ادعا",
    "back": "pretentious"
  },
  {
    "id": "201d665d-9e58-4194-8268-6e5bf480dde1",
    "front": "**Def**: a quality or feature of sb/sth.\n**Farsi**: ویژگی/صفت",
    "back": "attribute"
  },
  {
    "id": "3c3059d3-da99-44c0-8f46-0ad8669daedc",
    "front": "**Def**: = What's your impression of sb/sth?\n**Farsi**: نظر شما در مورد کسی/چیزی چیست؟",
    "back": "What do you make of sb/sth?"
  },
  {
    "id": "dbc26ffb-5f94-48a8-9e0d-01ec06320d64",
    "front": "**Def**: An interesting or unusual person can be called a character (or a real character).\n**Farsi**: آدم خاص/فرد جالب",
    "back": "character (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "e5d74ee1-bfaf-4b80-b856-a4959d30be1c",
    "front": "**Def**: able to think quickly; intelligent.\n**Farsi**: باهوش/حاضر جواب",
    "back": "quick-witted"
  },
  {
    "id": "6a2fbe57-2de6-41b8-9885-de2d95669974",
    "front": "**Def**: good at judging people and situations.\n**Farsi**: زیرک/تیزبین",
    "back": "shrewd (SYN astute)"
  },
  {
    "id": "fa7a1a38-7732-4b6c-b655-b07029804019",
    "front": "**Def**: determined to get what you want and not caring about others.\n**Farsi**: بی‌رحم/سنگدل",
    "back": "ruthless"
  },
  {
    "id": "6c4a08d8-98c6-41f7-b583-2a2feb8218c7",
    "front": "**Def**: start liking sb/sth.\n**Farsi**: از کسی/چیزی خوش آمدن",
    "back": "take to sb/sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "a826f919-d2fa-4d39-9b3b-4e0d9ad67591",
    "front": "**Def**: make a particular impression.\n**Farsi**: به نظر رسیدن/برداشت خاصی ایجاد کردن",
    "back": "come across (as)"
  },
  {
    "id": "5853eb82-cf2c-44d4-ae80-a688b6745051",
    "front": "**Def**: trying hard to get what you want, especially in a rude manner.\n**Farsi**: سمج/زورگو",
    "back": "pushy (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "17ff5111-43a9-4515-8bdb-b1c5981fd72a",
    "front": "**Def**: thinking you are very important, clever, etc.\n**Farsi**: خودبین/متکبر",
    "back": "conceited (DISAPPROVING)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b6c8769a-be62-460b-b3aa-fe620d2cdc99",
    "front": "**Def**: give sb a particular impression.\n**Farsi**: به نظر رسیدن (برداشتی ایجاد کردن)",
    "back": "strike sb (as sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "30a5c34e-e6dd-4239-9c43-29b22864313d",
    "front": "**Def**: taking care to do things carefully and correctly.\n**Farsi**: وظیفه‌شناس/باوجدان",
    "back": "conscientious"
  },
  {
    "id": "a60be563-cca9-47fc-81cf-ef2021d34853",
    "front": "**Def**: able to be relied on as good, honest, etc.\n**Farsi**: قابل اعتماد",
    "back": "trustworthy"
  },
  {
    "id": "47997217-2540-415b-aa80-935f8dfae882",
    "front": "**Def**: behaving confidently so that people take notice of what you say.\n**Farsi**: قاطع/با اعتماد به نفس",
    "back": "assertive"
  },
  {
    "id": "add56078-e782-4d54-9897-15229404d7a7",
    "front": "**Def**: annoy sb very much.\n**Farsi**: روی اعصاب کسی رفتن/عصبانی کردن",
    "back": "get up sb's nose (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "a4d8976a-57fb-4880-9cc0-748c37d0af6d",
    "front": "**Def**: when not looked at or thought about carefully.\n**Farsi**: ظاهراً/در ظاهر",
    "back": "on the surface"
  },
  {
    "id": "2e0726c8-5dc1-4347-99c9-5af74103dc24",
    "front": "**Def**: not friendly towards others.\n**Farsi**: گوشه‌گیر/فاصله‌گیر",
    "back": "aloof (SYNS distant, stand-offish)"
  },
  {
    "id": "5087eba2-b7c3-415b-a7b1-3f64ce8f8323",
    "front": "**Def**: not confident; not wanting to talk about yourself.\n**Farsi**: کمرو/متواضع",
    "back": "diffident (SYN shy)"
  },
  {
    "id": "245bf86c-ed37-40cc-bf0d-0bfb35c77660",
    "front": "**Def**: don't form an opinion of sth/sb by their appearance only.\n**Farsi**: از روی ظاهر قضاوت نکن",
    "back": "don't judge a book by its cover (SAYING)"
  },
  {
    "id": "72f3ba61-f48e-42fd-8968-30372c26c3f9",
    "front": "**Def**: a feature of sb's character.\n**Farsi**: ویژگی/خصوصیت اخلاقی",
    "back": "trait"
  },
  {
    "id": "ecdbac10-f7a0-4dea-8a1b-5e1202c656d5",
    "front": "**Def**: giving the wrong idea or impression.\n**Farsi**: گمراه‌کننده",
    "back": "misleading (SYN deceptive)"
  },
  {
    "id": "eb6ea575-2f8c-4329-9fae-e5b41fbc088a",
    "front": "**Def**: a good or desirable quality. OPP vice. virtuous ADJ.\n**Farsi**: فضیلت/حسنه",
    "back": "virtue"
  },
  {
    "id": "19f4c7d2-2369-4dc3-995c-f3e48fbd1285",
    "front": "**Def**: able to do things by being clever, but not always honest.\n**Farsi**: حیله‌گر/زیرک",
    "back": "cunning (SYN crafty)"
  },
  {
    "id": "bd3d4595-b8d6-4583-ae3f-1109d840bc42",
    "front": "**Def**: doing things quickly, without thinking about the results.\n**Farsi**: تکانشی/بدون فکر",
    "back": "impulsive (SYNS impetuous, rash)"
  },
  {
    "id": "85155b2e-c022-4f9b-82c1-923041a2ffb5",
    "front": "**Def**: lacking experience of life, and trusting others too easily. naivety N.\n**Farsi**: ساده‌لوح/خام",
    "back": "naive"
  },
  {
    "id": "b22b6645-63ca-43df-ada8-f8dcca95cd22",
    "front": "**Def**: you believe people do things for themselves rather than for unselfish reasons. cynicism N.\n**Farsi**: بدبین (به انگیزه‌های انسان)",
    "back": "cynical"
  },
  {
    "id": "8a99cdab-d8e4-4b9f-8a9c-30cb7f0ec49f",
    "front": "**Def**: you are not confident that it is true or will happen. scepticism N.\n**Farsi**: شکاک/تردیدآمیز",
    "back": "sceptical"
  },
  {
    "id": "c7bcfd15-6f81-4601-ac98-fe508fa860d2",
    "front": "**Def**: very happy.\n**Farsi**: سرمست/ذوق زده",
    "back": "ecstatic (SYNS euphoric, elated, over the moon)"
  },
  {
    "id": "84c1668d-0057-40fe-8653-3b6abef77a32",
    "front": "**Def**: feeling extremely happy because of a success.\n**Farsi**: شادمان/مسرور",
    "back": "jubilant"
  },
  {
    "id": "a79927a9-fcba-455e-99d5-8b47e983cc82",
    "front": "**Def**: crying (close to tears = nearly crying).\n**Farsi**: گریان/اشک‌ریزان",
    "back": "in tears"
  },
  {
    "id": "5ba62fb3-d87d-42cb-97a3-78fdc876f60a",
    "front": "**Def**: very upset.\n**Farsi**: دلشکسته/به شدت ناراحت",
    "back": "devastated (SYN heartbroken)"
  },
  {
    "id": "fe5f572b-3a3b-400b-881c-031b9bc35e7e",
    "front": "**Def**: become very angry.\n**Farsi**: از کوره در رفتن/عصبانی شدن",
    "back": "lose your temper (SYN go mad INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "60260cc2-384a-4d00-94f1-60c38dcf9410",
    "front": "**Def**: become very angry.\n**Farsi**: خیلی عصبانی شدن",
    "back": "hit the roof (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f86b66d1-f178-41b3-ae2a-c80570a91d2d",
    "front": "**Def**: very disappointed.\n**Farsi**: خیلی ناامید/داغون",
    "back": "gutted (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "9a30df8a-0a4e-463c-9708-4ca829cd308b",
    "front": "**Def**: being in a state of extreme distress or excitement and crying, laughing, or shouting, etc.\n**Farsi**: هیستریک (از شدت هیجان یا ناراحتی)",
    "back": "hysterical"
  },
  {
    "id": "e18925b3-9803-40ea-918d-17969a19979e",
    "front": "**Def**: shocked and surprised.\n**Farsi**: مبهوت/شوکه",
    "back": "stunned (SYN gobsmacked INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "1d681339-a7bb-4a94-b39d-009e5495d921",
    "front": "**Def**: shocked because sth is very unpleasant.\n**Farsi**: وحشت‌زده/متحیر (از بدی چیزی)",
    "back": "appalled (SYN horrified)"
  },
  {
    "id": "45b13e8b-94b6-4cf2-aa6b-0f21cd72253a",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely anxious.\n**Farsi**: درمانده/مضطرب",
    "back": "desperate"
  },
  {
    "id": "6110e4f3-a1bf-4db8-b221-5b7357c92287",
    "front": "**Def**: an act of sheer (= absolute) desperation N.\n**Farsi**: استیصال/درماندگی مطلق",
    "back": "desperation"
  },
  {
    "id": "833bda63-3fcc-4e0e-a547-ed4a1b8e01f1",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely unhappy.\n**Farsi**: به شدت/با درماندگی",
    "back": "desperately (ADV)"
  },
  {
    "id": "70a370ee-1c6e-45a5-bee5-91c47294709b",
    "front": "**Def**: stop yourself showing negative emotions or feelings, especially over a long time (bottle up your emotions).\n**Farsi**: احساسات را سرکوب کردن/درون ریختن",
    "back": "bottle sth up"
  },
  {
    "id": "83203042-7c1f-46f5-969c-16c2b497427b",
    "front": "**Def**: make your feelings obvious to others.\n**Farsi**: احساسات خود را آشکار کردن",
    "back": "wear your heart on your sleeve"
  },
  {
    "id": "ab37c30a-7cc8-4f28-bee4-a2cc26e11b4a",
    "front": "**Def**: weak and easily hurt, physically or emotionally.\n**Farsi**: آسیب‌پذیر",
    "back": "vulnerable"
  },
  {
    "id": "4205bfbf-c85e-4f10-9cdc-d0d05f3c38e1",
    "front": "**Def**: slightly nervous, embarrassed, or worried.\n**Farsi**: ناراحت/معذب",
    "back": "uneasy (SYN uncomfortable)"
  },
  {
    "id": "7e2c534f-7be7-4d68-a43f-4b8a2d1a73a4",
    "front": "**Def**: express all your feelings, often because you are unhappy.\n**Farsi**: بیرون ریختن (احساسات)",
    "back": "pour sth out"
  },
  {
    "id": "f71e1b33-22e3-4753-9359-d93fb3d1ab1c",
    "front": "**Def**: the thoughts which are most personal and private.\n**Farsi**: درونی‌ترین افکار",
    "back": "innermost thoughts"
  },
  {
    "id": "f5ba931c-df73-40b0-a757-eb638d65df9d",
    "front": "**Def**: a way of behaving that results from responses you were born with rather than responses you have learned. instinctive ADJ.\n**Farsi**: غریزه/فطرت",
    "back": "instinct"
  },
  {
    "id": "0cf63106-1be1-4d30-a516-f4e4c60d7f89",
    "front": "**Def**: careful not to give too much information.\n**Farsi**: محتاط/تودار",
    "back": "guarded (SYN cautious)"
  },
  {
    "id": "8daaee34-9bcd-41c0-b5f5-135c4041d1cd",
    "front": "**Def**: tell people secret information.\n**Farsi**: لو دادن/افشا کردن",
    "back": "give sth away"
  },
  {
    "id": "d29c043d-abb8-49d6-a004-07f6c6e68c3b",
    "front": "**Def**: stop yourself from having or expressing feelings.\n**Farsi**: سرکوب کردن احساسات",
    "back": "suppress your feelings"
  },
  {
    "id": "e11c1c09-fe92-408e-8f1a-c0874eff298b",
    "front": "**Def**: (of emotions, energy, etc.) held back; not shown or expressed.\n**Farsi**: تلنبار شده/فروخورده",
    "back": "pent-up"
  },
  {
    "id": "381619cf-4393-4a39-89e5-43c1e8f91dd1",
    "front": "**Def**: I wasn't interested in or enthusiastic about it.\n**Farsi**: واقعاً به آن علاقه‌مند نبودم",
    "back": "my heart wasn't really in it"
  },
  {
    "id": "d0856b0e-7815-4a35-b3f7-e1a4a8a39a27",
    "front": "**Def**: I was unable to tell her she'd failed, because I knew she'd be upset.\n**Farsi**: دلش نیامد/طاقت نداشت",
    "back": "didn't have the heart to"
  },
  {
    "id": "67fcc272-7a92-4cd1-8a05-1d4bbd846710",
    "front": "**Def**: Emotionally, I felt I should help him.\n**Farsi**: حس قلبی‌ام گفت",
    "back": "my heart told me"
  },
  {
    "id": "7313fff3-1514-4bbc-b2e5-796b82341670",
    "front": "**Def**: dislike sb as soon as you meet them.\n**Farsi**: فوراً از کسی بدش آمدن",
    "back": "take an instant dislike to sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "5f9a39b9-4c04-4881-a4ab-841e5f468c0d",
    "front": "**Def**: unfriendly and aggressive. hostility N.\n**Farsi**: خصمانه/دشمنانه",
    "back": "hostile (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "7d336c39-ce87-4ed6-af8f-452cc9a29d8d",
    "front": "**Def**: If you say sth to sb's face, you say it to them directly.\n**Farsi**: مستقیم به کسی",
    "back": "to sb's face"
  },
  {
    "id": "a7156774-446d-49de-91ae-1f5dbe4ef6c3",
    "front": "**Def**: saying nice things about sb.\n**Farsi**: تعریف‌آمیز/تمجیدآمیز",
    "back": "complimentary (about sb)"
  },
  {
    "id": "09e5b7b6-34ad-4ac8-b04e-1f3326a0cd29",
    "front": "**Def**: If you say or do sth behind sb's back, you say or do it without their knowledge, and usually it is bad or unkind.\n**Farsi**: پشت سر کسی",
    "back": "behind sb's back"
  },
  {
    "id": "31eebdc0-a3ea-482c-bac9-2d5b284c3ecc",
    "front": "**Def**: used for saying that sth is certain to happen. inevitable ADJ.\n**Farsi**: به ناچار/اجتناب‌ناپذیر",
    "back": "inevitably (ADV)"
  },
  {
    "id": "e19cc3f1-4515-4aed-8fcb-12563c0fc399",
    "front": "**Def**: create pressure and anxiety for sb; create tension in a relationship.\n**Farsi**: فشار آوردن/تنش ایجاد کردن",
    "back": "put a strain on sb/sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "049ac2ae-fcc7-4032-b5cd-a2a07ff01a11",
    "front": "**Def**: support and defend sb if they are criticized.\n**Farsi**: حمایت کردن از کسی",
    "back": "stick up for sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "46cf99f3-12e9-4bb8-ac17-cc0dbdca2205",
    "front": "**Def**: over a period of time.\n**Farsi**: با گذشت زمان",
    "back": "as time went by"
  },
  {
    "id": "7e977fdc-985f-4854-ae15-ab73d73d334c",
    "front": "**Def**: become calmer and more relaxed.\n**Farsi**: آرام شدن/به روال افتادن",
    "back": "settle down"
  },
  {
    "id": "f321da47-ed66-4243-a882-53bca574f555",
    "front": "**Def**: 1. difficult: It's a tough decision. 2. strict: tough new driving laws. 3. able to deal with difficult situations: She's tough.\n**Farsi**: سخت/دشوار/قوی",
    "back": "tough"
  },
  {
    "id": "ee303df8-d740-4b7e-9b27-ba7a11767e30",
    "front": "**Def**: used to talk about a situation or life in general.\n**Farsi**: اوضاع/شرایط",
    "back": "things (PL)"
  },
  {
    "id": "91aaf09d-0a18-4903-8c5b-0c8fd846d636",
    "front": "**Def**: start to become better.\n**Farsi**: بهتر شدن (وضعیت)",
    "back": "look up (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "c4d9aaa9-08ea-4bcd-a329-47195b4ff69a",
    "front": "**Def**: in the beginning. initial ADJ.\n**Farsi**: در ابتدا",
    "back": "initially (ADV)"
  },
  {
    "id": "4525a03b-3dff-46e6-ae81-4cd94a7c2b26",
    "front": "**Def**: not wanting to do sth. reluctance N.\n**Farsi**: بی‌میل/ناراضی",
    "back": "reluctant (SYN unwilling)"
  },
  {
    "id": "7440c8e4-f6fd-44d5-b362-08b6cadafe22",
    "front": "**Def**: a connection between people based on shared feelings or experiences.\n**Farsi**: پیوند/ارتباط عاطفی",
    "back": "bond"
  },
  {
    "id": "9215a21c-f3a3-4e0c-a995-6a3e7db75040",
    "front": "**Def**: a feeling of admiration for sb because of their qualities. respect v.\n**Farsi**: احترام",
    "back": "respect (for sb)"
  },
  {
    "id": "6a5b1665-6c8b-4e15-9e8b-7fb1042d2cda",
    "front": "**Def**: a mixture of good and bad things in life or a relationship.\n**Farsi**: فراز و نشیب/پستی بلندی",
    "back": "ups and downs"
  },
  {
    "id": "94432955-eaec-4773-be0b-8062796e7509",
    "front": "**Def**: recognize sth and welcome it. appreciation N.\n**Farsi**: قدردانی کردن/ارزش قائل شدن",
    "back": "appreciate sth (v)"
  },
  {
    "id": "c3503bfd-3557-43ca-a69c-13f344684c9d",
    "front": "**Def**: give up sth important or valuable in order to do sth that seems more important. sacrifice sth v.\n**Farsi**: فداکاری کردن",
    "back": "make a sacrifice"
  },
  {
    "id": "126e1446-012b-4e19-84ff-624f7720beaf",
    "front": "**Def**: 1. allow sb to be part of a group; 2. agree to sth; 3. believe that sth is true; 4. admit you did sth wrong.\n**Farsi**: پذیرفتن/قبول کردن",
    "back": "accept (v)"
  },
  {
    "id": "8c0ccd8d-0186-43c6-8a00-ccd2ac7abfd3",
    "front": "**Def**: a woman you admire for her ability or personal qualities (hero for a man).\n**Farsi**: قهرمان زن",
    "back": "heroine (N) (SYN idol)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f8b3ab48-10f1-45f6-bfcd-728e6aa7ab02",
    "front": "**Def**: the ability to do sth, even though it is dangerous, frightening, or very difficult. courageous ADJ.\n**Farsi**: شجاعت/شهامت",
    "back": "courage (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "273cef5f-6922-4056-b7e6-0b9862f2bf0c",
    "front": "**Def**: a calm, controlled manner in a difficult situation. dignified ADJ.\n**Farsi**: وقار/عزت نفس",
    "back": "dignity (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "5e080d1b-a097-4321-b516-6e939d2d1e9d",
    "front": "**Def**: the quality of not believing you are better or more important than others. humble ADJ.\n**Farsi**: فروتنی/تواضع",
    "back": "humility (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "9594c23d-4256-4c44-a784-294558a1526b",
    "front": "**Def**: give sb the enthusiasm and desire to do sth. inspiration N. inspirational ADJ.\n**Farsi**: الهام بخشیدن",
    "back": "inspire sb (v)"
  },
  {
    "id": "205585a6-0f38-4b13-8c96-05284569f995",
    "front": "**Def**: admire or love sb very much.\n**Farsi**: پرستیدن/شدیداً تحسین کردن",
    "back": "idolize sb (SYN worship sb)"
  },
  {
    "id": "19f74de2-6d34-4ad9-97e4-898bc500ab21",
    "front": "**Def**: say unkind things or complain about sb.\n**Farsi**: انتقاد کردن/سرزنش کردن",
    "back": "have a go at sb (INF) (SYN criticize sb)"
  },
  {
    "id": "e6a69515-c818-4f29-8a9c-36d475966140",
    "front": "**Def**: admire and respect sb, often sb who is older or in a higher position.\n**Farsi**: احترام گذاشتن/تحسین کردن",
    "back": "look up to sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "fdf9f4d9-9475-48f3-a27a-e946cf52596d",
    "front": "**Def**: do the same work or be as successful as sb before you.\n**Farsi**: راه کسی را ادامه دادن/دنبال کردن",
    "back": "follow in sb's footsteps"
  },
  {
    "id": "26eb67df-e2b4-42c6-b939-d26344003619",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who opposes people in authority. rebel v. rebellious ADJ.\n**Farsi**: شورشی/یاغی",
    "back": "rebel (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "35b2907f-727f-4cbb-b24b-d9ab36d3f5c2",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who believes the world can be perfect. idealistic ADJ.\n**Farsi**: آرمان‌گرا",
    "back": "idealist (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "296c53ee-81a4-4700-8f54-c5775aea2e91",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who says they have strong principles but does not act according to these principles. hypocrisy N. hypocritical ADJ.\n**Farsi**: ریاکار/متظاهر",
    "back": "hypocrite (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "96343152-7024-4040-8c55-366b6ab4819e",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who thinks they are better than people in lower social classes.\n**Farsi**: خودبرتربین/متکبر طبقاتی",
    "back": "snob (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "fe6380c9-ee74-4834-a9eb-d8ff875c7128",
    "front": "**Def**: think that you are better than sb.\n**Farsi**: با تحقیر نگاه کردن/خود را برتر دانستن",
    "back": "look down on sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "f50224ae-e07f-400a-bec5-1740479d40cc",
    "front": "**Def**: not polite, elegant, or having good taste.\n**Farsi**: مبتذل/بی‌ادب/زننده",
    "back": "vulgar (SYNS coarse, crude)"
  },
  {
    "id": "86436ad3-5e94-4563-9fbc-1496c5cd477e",
    "front": "**Def**: be hurt or frightened by sb who is bigger and stronger (the person who does the bullying is a bully).\n**Farsi**: مورد قلدری قرار گرفتن",
    "back": "be bullied"
  },
  {
    "id": "5a27d0a8-8c90-4bf5-b51c-ca761691aa33",
    "front": "**Def**: hate and have no respect for sb/sth. despicable ADJ.\n**Farsi**: تحقیر کردن/نفرت داشتن",
    "back": "despise sb/sth (v)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b604aa63-8055-4c35-9dec-3c3805ca5631",
    "front": "**Def**: deserving hatred and contempt.\n**Farsi**: نفرت‌انگیز/پست",
    "back": "despicable (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "01cd3190-8b70-423a-a3de-fc49f6d767a3",
    "front": "**Def**: showing hatred and the desire to hurt people's feelings. malice N.\n**Farsi**: بدخواه/مغرض",
    "back": "malicious (ADJ) (SYNS spiteful)"
  },
  {
    "id": "c28f20ba-2018-404a-a84d-02131f0c514f",
    "front": "**Def**: stories about other people's private lives, which may be unkind or untrue. gossip v (also spread gossip).\n**Farsi**: شایعه/سخن‌چینی",
    "back": "gossip (N/V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "35a6c10b-9e98-4c40-b148-29effd537129",
    "front": "**Def**: strong beliefs that influence how you behave.\n**Farsi**: اصول/مبانی",
    "back": "principles (PL)"
  },
  {
    "id": "5321253f-6450-4a51-a8e8-8505ffd029bd",
    "front": "**Def**: beliefs about what is right and important in life.\n**Farsi**: ارزش‌ها",
    "back": "values (PL)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f434d2d0-3b93-40c4-aa16-c0ffe683ff94",
    "front": "**Def**: the basic character of a person.\n**Farsi**: طبیعت/ذات",
    "back": "nature (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "98b82d72-8151-48ef-badb-a9c729a7a0cb",
    "front": "**Def**: the care and attention given to help sb develop. nurture sb v.\n**Farsi**: تربیت/پرورش",
    "back": "nurture (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "153aa432-8d58-45f6-a271-abfc91b20dc3",
    "front": "**Def**: a person you admire and learn from.\n**Farsi**: الگو/سرمشق",
    "back": "role model"
  },
  {
    "id": "c2f21941-90a5-418d-933d-a5f456f6cd33",
    "front": "**Def**: the influence on your behaviour of people around you of the same age.\n**Farsi**: فشار همسالان",
    "back": "peer pressure"
  },
  {
    "id": "10082005-3eb5-4d6e-87f7-9b9cc378f9a4",
    "front": "**Def**: a thing that encourages you to work harder, do sth, etc.\n**Farsi**: انگیزه/محرک",
    "back": "incentive (to do sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "4e3c2ab4-e2d8-485a-9aab-3cb86cff09ee",
    "front": "**Def**: a thing that makes you less likely to do sth. deter sb v.\n**Farsi**: عامل بازدارنده",
    "back": "deterrent"
  },
  {
    "id": "03176010-e9ce-4a2b-8d03-2bc786c8faaa",
    "front": "**Def**: a family in which the parents are divorced or separated.\n**Farsi**: خانه از هم پاشیده (طلاق والدین)",
    "back": "broken home"
  },
  {
    "id": "73b87324-28b8-4946-b150-24d4d3f75117",
    "front": "**Def**: without sufficient food, education, or money. deprivation N.\n**Farsi**: محروم",
    "back": "deprived"
  },
  {
    "id": "d6e232f1-8c23-4991-a819-249bcabc911f",
    "front": "**Def**: a very negative effect.\n**Farsi**: اثر مخرب/زیان‌آور",
    "back": "detrimental effect (on sth) (OPP beneficial effect)"
  },
  {
    "id": "396f15c0-f7da-45c7-b71e-e29fe537b2f2",
    "front": "**Def**: dirty or untidy. mess N.\n**Farsi**: شلخته/نامرتب",
    "back": "messy (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "677a04e7-cfa3-4256-b428-5988bbb8e8f3",
    "front": "**Def**: work as hard as everyone else in a job or activity.\n**Farsi**: وظیفه خود را انجام دادن",
    "back": "pull your weight (SYN do your fair share)"
  },
  {
    "id": "cb971a02-7e44-403a-8875-e5e16b842019",
    "front": "**Def**: keep talking (about sth or to sb) in a boring way.\n**Farsi**: ادامه دادن (به صحبت خسته‌کننده)",
    "back": "go on and on (about sth, at sb)"
  },
  {
    "id": "36af45fd-9d67-4541-9472-1b6920af8edb",
    "front": "**Def**: keep complaining about sb's behaviour.\n**Farsi**: نق زدن/ایراد گرفتن مداوم",
    "back": "nag (v)"
  },
  {
    "id": "56385c56-e958-44ab-99ab-31efd832d8bf",
    "front": "**Def**: not pleasant or attractive.\n**Farsi**: ناخوشایند/غیرجذاب",
    "back": "unappealing (OPP appealing)"
  },
  {
    "id": "bd1b8335-d3f9-43f9-a085-4d8b0dc8dd9d",
    "front": "**Def**: likely to cause death (here it is being used humorously).\n**Farsi**: تهدیدکننده حیات",
    "back": "life-threatening"
  },
  {
    "id": "0aa2293b-1959-4c65-b002-3c2cf85a694a",
    "front": "**Def**: If you make a fuss about sth, you become angry and complain about sth which probably isn't important.\n**Farsi**: جنجال/هیاهو",
    "back": "fuss (N) (SYN kick up a fuss INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "8b162e9f-5b6a-4565-b120-2245dfbf419f",
    "front": "**Def**: say officially what the rules are.\n**Farsi**: قانون وضع کردن",
    "back": "lay down rules"
  },
  {
    "id": "13186e53-45d1-46e4-8764-387d0dda52f2",
    "front": "**Def**: behave in a way that others may copy.\n**Farsi**: الگو شدن/مثال زدن",
    "back": "set an (or a good/bad) example"
  },
  {
    "id": "1f6db233-d239-4d81-be2b-5b46141fcfac",
    "front": "**Def**: agree to do sth that you don't want to do.\n**Farsi**: تسلیم شدن/رضایت دادن",
    "back": "give in (to sb/sth) (SYN capitulate FML)"
  },
  {
    "id": "7c2dede2-e524-4c4b-96e9-396a57ca6f94",
    "front": "**Def**: To expect sth can mean to think it is right that sth should happen.\n**Farsi**: انتظار داشتن",
    "back": "expect (v)"
  },
  {
    "id": "d29a4c9d-4e7b-4634-89bc-7c64cca4e7a5",
    "front": "**Def**: idiom used for saying you are not surprised by something, even though it is unpleasant or disappointing.\n**Farsi**: چه انتظاری داری؟",
    "back": "What do/can you expect?"
  },
  {
    "id": "56dd721d-add3-4210-9241-f848c7abf740",
    "front": "**Def**: the formal rules of correct or polite behaviour in society.\n**Farsi**: آداب/نزاکت",
    "back": "etiquette"
  },
  {
    "id": "ea8b84a0-8d27-4f4e-a997-02728d74d86e",
    "front": "**Def**: behaviour that is considered polite in a particular society or culture.\n**Farsi**: آداب معاشرت/رفتار",
    "back": "manners (PL)"
  },
  {
    "id": "69082884-c130-43a0-8014-01a30d7977d1",
    "front": "**Def**: (often passive) disapprove of sth/sb.\n**Farsi**: ناپسند شمردن/ایراد گرفتن",
    "back": "frown on/upon sth/sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "59d0572e-ff63-40d1-aa03-170cd7fda212",
    "front": "**Def**: having bad manners and not showing respect. courtesy N.\n**Farsi**: بی‌ادب/بی‌نزاکت",
    "back": "discourteous (FML) (OPP courteous)"
  },
  {
    "id": "bf50e8a1-8da0-4a58-b1d2-c5dcc2637bb6",
    "front": "**Def**: usually done in a particular place or situation. custom N.\n**Farsi**: مرسوم/متعارف",
    "back": "customary (ADJ)"
  },
  {
    "id": "910baffb-86ba-4a06-90a2-4a65d9333fca",
    "front": "**Def**: showing polite behaviour towards sb/sth.\n**Farsi**: محترمانه/مؤدب",
    "back": "respectful (OPP disrespectful)"
  },
  {
    "id": "729aeb33-1b87-43a5-9286-fa8b921d7c1f",
    "front": "**Def**: moving or pointing towards a higher position.\n**Farsi**: به سمت بالا",
    "back": "upwards (OPP downwards)"
  },
  {
    "id": "e664bc38-ad77-4cba-b66c-6ffe50b5d27d",
    "front": "**Def**: rude in a way that makes sb upset or annoyed.\n**Farsi**: توهین‌آمیز/زننده",
    "back": "offensive (OPP inoffensive)"
  },
  {
    "id": "8c60c88c-08f4-4cb7-a981-9a7023516af0",
    "front": "**Def**: think about something in a particular way (used passively).\n**Farsi**: تلقی کردن/در نظر گرفتن",
    "back": "consider (v, FML)"
  },
  {
    "id": "7292c646-5c6e-45dd-b377-d27d7880c1e0",
    "front": "**Def**: think about something in a particular way (used passively).\n**Farsi**: محسوب شدن",
    "back": "regard (v, FML)"
  },
  {
    "id": "e05c72c4-4b43-4105-b1a2-6871f7c381e7",
    "front": "**Def**: think about something in a particular way (used passively).\n**Farsi**: دریافتن/ادراک کردن",
    "back": "perceive (v, FML)"
  },
  {
    "id": "7e65ab98-ede6-418b-912c-1c9b48d3d692",
    "front": "**Def**: perfect (impeccable manners/behaviour/service).\n**Farsi**: بی‌عیب و نقص/عالی",
    "back": "impeccable"
  },
  {
    "id": "251c5d46-9a28-47ae-b363-4b3556cd79b0",
    "front": "**Def**: excellent, and done in a way that others should copy.\n**Farsi**: نمونه/الگو",
    "back": "exemplary (FML)"
  },
  {
    "id": "7d49ae3f-5ffc-4bba-be6a-002a62cba0e7",
    "front": "**Def**: rude, often in an amusing way (often used by adults about children). cheek N.\n**Farsi**: گستاخ/پررو (بچه‌گانه)",
    "back": "cheeky (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "d730424a-8c6a-4c4d-b1b6-0c232cde0cd2",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely rude and disrespectful. insolence N.\n**Farsi**: بی‌شرم/اهانت‌آمیز",
    "back": "insolent"
  },
  {
    "id": "95287bd5-7a82-4b04-b932-d59d88014096",
    "front": "**Def**: used to emphasize sth negative (downright rude/offensive).\n**Farsi**: کاملاً/به وضوح (برای تاکید منفی)",
    "back": "downright"
  },
  {
    "id": "f52419b5-0ba7-4d5a-bb2f-6e93c81d2f77",
    "front": "**Def**: be upset or offended.\n**Farsi**: ناراحت/رنجیده شدن",
    "back": "be put out (SYN take offence)"
  },
  {
    "id": "30d22479-c1e5-42e1-8504-daeda0d59d08",
    "front": "**Def**: say sth that offends or upsets sb.\n**Farsi**: سوتی دادن/حرف نامناسب زدن",
    "back": "put your foot in it (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "217a5ee1-54d7-4085-95af-a9101533c49e",
    "front": "**Def**: considered to have the highest social status.\n**Farsi**: طبقه بالا",
    "back": "upper class"
  },
  {
    "id": "d2fea909-98e8-4b7e-99e9-6c38d7d57604",
    "front": "**Def**: behave in the most polite way you can.\n**Farsi**: مؤدبانه رفتار کردن",
    "back": "be on your best behaviour"
  },
  {
    "id": "2754e7cf-c3cf-42ae-ac57-9ffea923c35e",
    "front": "**Def**: object strongly to sth and be angry about it.\n**Farsi**: شدیداً اعتراض کردن/به دل گرفتن",
    "back": "take exception to sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "f5afd3ac-64f6-42af-9ab0-ac26cb770d92",
    "front": "**Def**: a few words that give your opinion about sth.\n**Farsi**: نظر/سخن",
    "back": "remark (SYN comment)"
  },
  {
    "id": "2c0a2ec0-9a2e-4663-958a-21b1ea033421",
    "front": "**Def**: very bad or unacceptable. disgrace N.\n**Farsi**: شرم‌آور/ننگین",
    "back": "disgraceful"
  },
  {
    "id": "11a5f458-1556-4996-9988-b72f96beede1",
    "front": "**Def**: be offensive and not at all appropriate.\n**Farsi**: نامناسب/توهین‌آمیز",
    "back": "be in poor/bad taste"
  },
  {
    "id": "e25264d1-3d20-4174-9394-af5ec3f2d0fa",
    "front": "**Def**: create untidiness or a disordered situation.\n**Farsi**: خرابکاری کردن، ریخت و پاش کردن",
    "back": "make a mess"
  },
  {
    "id": "cf632d15-b532-43ca-9689-89811db214b6",
    "front": "**Def**: show excessive concern, excitement, or agitation about something.\n**Farsi**: سروصدا راه انداختن، هیاهو کردن",
    "back": "make a fuss"
  },
  {
    "id": "33f1383b-7ad7-4bbf-ab45-bae7a2c45db9",
    "front": "**Def**: harmful; damaging.\n**Farsi**: مضر، زیان‌آور",
    "back": "detrimental"
  },
  {
    "id": "ad97a362-720e-4d22-a19e-8fb005b6e200",
    "front": "**Def**: resulting in good; favourable or advantageous.\n**Farsi**: مفید، سودمند",
    "back": "beneficial"
  },
  {
    "id": "c7e595cc-7de8-42ae-bfc7-5fa84888a450",
    "front": "**Def**: behaves in a way that others should copy.\n**Farsi**: الگوی خوبی است",
    "back": "sets a good example"
  },
  {
    "id": "72696f3f-4d17-4e69-9fb5-5983187edf00",
    "front": "**Def**: contributes an equal or expected amount to a task or effort.\n**Farsi**: سهم عادلانه خود را انجام می‌دهد",
    "back": "does her fair share"
  },
  {
    "id": "10427756-fa2e-4aab-a978-f7394f679ffa",
    "front": "**Def**: not attractive or interesting.\n**Farsi**: نامطلوب، ناخوشایند",
    "back": "unappealing"
  },
  {
    "id": "e86b863d-5547-4da8-acaa-8fdab37fb71e",
    "front": "**Def**: yields or surrenders to (often after resisting).\n**Farsi**: تسلیم شدن، کوتاه آمدن (در برابر کسی/چیزی)",
    "back": "gives in to"
  },
  {
    "id": "cf7c1262-9a8c-4f6f-adfb-fb8318d3eb96",
    "front": "**Def**: repeatedly asks or urges someone to do something.\n**Farsi**: نق زدن، سرزنش کردن مداوم",
    "back": "nags"
  },
  {
    "id": "c793a916-e6e7-4444-b357-244364c9523d",
    "front": "**Def**: behaviour that causes problems or annoyance to other people.\n**Farsi**: رفتار ضد اجتماعی",
    "back": "anti-social behaviour"
  },
  {
    "id": "92b2600d-ef38-471d-a9e2-57d2a19f3659",
    "front": "**Def**: the action of staying away from school without permission.\n**Farsi**: غیبت غیرموجه (از مدرسه)",
    "back": "truancy"
  },
  {
    "id": "697c87c2-1e07-4e66-8be4-7616fd81b560",
    "front": "**Def**: doing something dangerous and not worrying about the risks.\n**Farsi**: بی‌پروا، بی‌ملاحظه (رفتار)",
    "back": "reckless (behaviour)"
  },
  {
    "id": "2057e152-79ff-4cb2-bd3d-c03cb19a5aac",
    "front": "**Def**: tell someone officially that you disapprove of them.\n**Farsi**: توبیخ کردن، سرزنش کردن",
    "back": "reprimand sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "666116fd-f224-4b97-95ec-b795232b8f2e",
    "front": "**Def**: the person who leads others in mischievous or criminal activities.\n**Farsi**: سردسته، بانی",
    "back": "ringleader"
  },
  {
    "id": "c16dbb23-2831-4a53-8da4-fa0d70a8099d",
    "front": "**Def**: outstanding; serving as a perfect model (Positive remark, P).\n**Farsi**: نمونه، مثال‌زدنی",
    "back": "exemplary"
  },
  {
    "id": "a8440b60-3ab9-4e5c-a328-b4efde1a2d9c",
    "front": "**Def**: objected strongly to (Negative remark, N).\n**Farsi**: اعتراض کردن، ناخوشایند شمردن",
    "back": "took exception to (idiom)"
  },
  {
    "id": "e41312ab-1eaa-4394-9d09-911d8ea500aa",
    "front": "**Def**: is disapproved of (Negative remark, N).\n**Farsi**: مورد نقد و انتقاد قرار گرفتن، با اخم تلقی شدن",
    "back": "is frowned upon (phrasal verb)"
  },
  {
    "id": "7a4c5436-84dc-425d-9c4e-c2551a9909d5",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say someone has been rude or disrespectful (Negative remark, N).\n**Farsi**: چه رویی!، چه پررویی!",
    "back": "What a cheek! (idiom)"
  },
  {
    "id": "46132382-5201-477d-a7e3-bdf59b96cebf",
    "front": "**Def**: said something embarrassing or inappropriate (Negative remark, N).\n**Farsi**: گاف دادن، خراب کردن (با حرف نابجا)",
    "back": "put her foot in it (idiom)"
  },
  {
    "id": "0a0dc4f1-19f7-4d78-afe1-c7d21f945c7c",
    "front": "**Def**: polite and respectful (Positive remark, P).\n**Farsi**: با ادب، مؤدبانه",
    "back": "courteous"
  },
  {
    "id": "448dbb04-978f-4ba8-930f-db827bccb9c7",
    "front": "**Def**: the physical area immediately surrounding someone (often related to invasion).\n**Farsi**: حریم خصوصی فیزیکی",
    "back": "personal space"
  },
  {
    "id": "2c01ebcd-1ef7-491f-a2df-f0175e65de2c",
    "front": "**Def**: rude or impolite conduct.\n**Farsi**: رفتار ناشایست، بی‌ادبی",
    "back": "uncivil behaviour"
  },
  {
    "id": "1dce323b-b598-42c4-80d8-ac29198ca6df",
    "front": "**Def**: rude, unfriendly, and uncooperative.\n**Farsi**: بدخلق، خشن، غیردوستانه",
    "back": "churlish"
  },
  {
    "id": "80c1a670-1a9c-484b-a48d-e3375b0fb25d",
    "front": "**Def**: behave in a reasonable and acceptable way.\n**Farsi**: شرم و حیا/نزاکت داشتن برای انجام کاری",
    "back": "have the decency to do sth (idiom)"
  },
  {
    "id": "cd0e7ba0-0358-4e35-a098-88f0d3eacb1a",
    "front": "**Def**: an action or remark that is careless or inappropriate.\n**Farsi**: بی‌احتیاطی، عمل نسنجیده",
    "back": "indiscretion"
  },
  {
    "id": "6f9c5b31-c79d-4377-8057-45cf86021d29",
    "front": "**Def**: a round fruit with thick skin and many seeds.\n**Farsi**: انار",
    "back": "pomegranate"
  },
  {
    "id": "23832480-888d-4dcf-9b45-6b0f17a8d2d8",
    "front": "**Def**: a small round fruit with a purple or yellow skin, tropical.\n**Farsi**: پشن فروت",
    "back": "passion fruit"
  },
  {
    "id": "f860edae-2507-408e-a60b-15c883226972",
    "front": "**Def**: a large oval tropical fruit.\n**Farsi**: پاپایا (خربزه درختی)",
    "back": "papaya"
  },
  {
    "id": "7e136874-d6ab-4844-933a-422287273f7c",
    "front": "**Def**: small, red, round vegetables, eaten raw in salads.\n**Farsi**: تربچه",
    "back": "radishes"
  },
  {
    "id": "d529c887-a802-423e-9729-7206e709f9f5",
    "front": "**Def**: a round root vegetable with deep red skin and flesh.\n**Farsi**: چغندر قرمز",
    "back": "beetroot"
  },
  {
    "id": "ff472e4c-bd0a-4c2c-bf35-5e59ce0f9ac3",
    "front": "**Def**: young, newly-grown beans, often used in Asian cooking.\n**Farsi**: جوانه ماش/لوبیا",
    "back": "bean sprouts"
  },
  {
    "id": "09cb957b-dcc9-4fb6-b14d-a5c7c3a473a3",
    "front": "**Def**: a type of vegetable with hard skin (like pumpkin or courgette).\n**Farsi**: کدو حلوایی، کدو مسمایی",
    "back": "squash"
  },
  {
    "id": "ceeddf7f-dde1-4619-91cc-3eb091547ddf",
    "front": "**Def**: a plant with a crisp bulb and feathery leaves, eaten as a vegetable.\n**Farsi**: رازیانه، بادیان",
    "back": "fennel"
  },
  {
    "id": "c3431ae7-4889-47f5-8c6c-806697d34c98",
    "front": "**Def**: a round vegetable with thick, edible leaves.\n**Farsi**: کنگر فرنگی",
    "back": "artichoke"
  },
  {
    "id": "7f869c13-7ab5-44a0-a8f5-b6a220c74d48",
    "front": "**Def**: an oval edible nut.\n**Farsi**: بادام",
    "back": "almonds"
  },
  {
    "id": "b40dc98b-2b69-43c2-b4ff-ea0d51e30cdf",
    "front": "**Def**: kidney-shaped edible nuts.\n**Farsi**: بادام هندی",
    "back": "cashews"
  },
  {
    "id": "05963d1c-f41a-4de1-8490-70f1cc3e1474",
    "front": "**Def**: small dried seeds (a type of pulse) used in stews and soups.\n**Farsi**: عدس",
    "back": "lentils"
  },
  {
    "id": "aeb1a407-ec32-4bb8-a68b-57b79fd3e6ad",
    "front": "**Def**: a spicy root used in cooking and baking.\n**Farsi**: زنجبیل",
    "back": "ginger"
  },
  {
    "id": "e0ac8d2e-fda8-4797-bf30-a317ef5c0b5f",
    "front": "**Def**: a sweet-smelling spice, bark of a tree.\n**Farsi**: دارچین",
    "back": "cinnamon"
  },
  {
    "id": "dabc399c-62c0-457e-adf2-8bb487d454e9",
    "front": "**Def**: an herb with grey-green leaves, used to flavour food.\n**Farsi**: مرزنجوش، مریم گلی",
    "back": "sage"
  },
  {
    "id": "b5d604c9-fe01-4ed1-bdbe-911891cba082",
    "front": "**Def**: an herb used to flavour food, also known as cilantro.\n**Farsi**: گشنیز",
    "back": "coriander"
  },
  {
    "id": "20ff8657-b0f6-4f5c-aa39-41052ddb0480",
    "front": "**Def**: small, pale-coloured dried grapes (a type of dried fruit).\n**Farsi**: کشمش زرد، مویز روشن",
    "back": "sultanas"
  },
  {
    "id": "e722567d-2ed5-4c70-b8aa-bdc3ea5d08ed",
    "front": "**Def**: dried grapes (a type of dried fruit).\n**Farsi**: کشمش، مویز",
    "back": "raisins"
  },
  {
    "id": "35fde5b9-013b-47ae-b964-458ef4e4cd0a",
    "front": "**Def**: a bowl-shaped pan, used to stir-fry vegetables, meat, fish.\n**Farsi**: وک (تابه عمیق چینی)",
    "back": "wok"
  },
  {
    "id": "fe79bf24-50eb-4042-ba34-0f56b38aa04d",
    "front": "**Def**: other words ending in -ize.\n**Farsi**: صرفه‌جویی کردن، محبوب کردن، مدرن کردن، شخصی‌سازی کردن، تجاری کردن، نهایی کردن، تخصص یافتن، صنعتی کردن، اجتماعی شدن، تعمیم دادن، آشنا کردن، جزء به جزء فهرست کردن، برابر کردن، استانداردسازی کردن، نمادین کردن",
    "back": "economize, popularize, modernize, personalize, commercialize, finalize, specialize, industrialize, socialize, generalize, familiarize, itemize, equalize, standardize, symbolize"
  },
  {
    "id": "857c7b3d-4de9-42b5-8889-9ac80d599d66",
    "front": "**Def**: an appliance used to steam fish, rice, vegetables.\n**Farsi**: بخارپز",
    "back": "steamer"
  },
  {
    "id": "02cdc59f-438b-40c2-bb9f-c545ba4b73d8",
    "front": "**Def**: cook over boiling water.\n**Farsi**: بخارپز کردن",
    "back": "steam"
  },
  {
    "id": "39b63ee6-9052-4c03-8ba5-a6f3b6c086da",
    "front": "**Def**: a kitchen appliance used to deep-fry fish and potatoes.\n**Farsi**: سرخ‌کن عمیق",
    "back": "deep fat fryer"
  },
  {
    "id": "eed7dc7f-6afb-40e5-aa33-b086d9850aef",
    "front": "**Def**: fry food in a large amount of hot fat or oil.\n**Farsi**: سرخ کردن عمیق",
    "back": "deep-fry"
  },
  {
    "id": "688174c5-b031-4cb7-a642-edf50576f71f",
    "front": "**Def**: a large, deep dish used for cooking meat and vegetables slowly in liquid (also the name of the dish itself).\n**Farsi**: قابلمه چدنی (برای آرام‌پز کردن)، خوراک آرام‌پز",
    "back": "casserole"
  },
  {
    "id": "1145ee69-5e55-4060-b35f-34d249a44342",
    "front": "**Def**: cook meat slowly in liquid in a closed container.\n**Farsi**: آرام‌پز کردن، تفت دادن (و سپس آرام پختن)",
    "back": "braise/stew"
  },
  {
    "id": "034e22d3-7d1b-43da-b059-143105d6a16b",
    "front": "**Def**: an appliance used to chop, slice, and mix meat, vegetables, etc.\n**Farsi**: غذا ساز",
    "back": "food processor"
  },
  {
    "id": "89ea6150-2a00-44a4-a6b0-9a1a84029aca",
    "front": "**Def**: cut food into small pieces.\n**Farsi**: خرد کردن",
    "back": "chop"
  },
  {
    "id": "9a3c6926-bb58-46b7-9717-29c1f9f57c0d",
    "front": "**Def**: a utensil used to beat eggs, cream, or other liquids rapidly.\n**Farsi**: همزن دستی",
    "back": "whisk"
  },
  {
    "id": "efaec7dc-acb1-4c9a-8eb5-544dcfce94be",
    "front": "**Def**: mix rapidly to incorporate air.\n**Farsi**: زدن، هم زدن (تخم مرغ، خامه)",
    "back": "beat"
  },
  {
    "id": "434cacd6-298e-46d0-89e0-907ad808e8f0",
    "front": "**Def**: a bowl-shaped container with holes, used to drain vegetables that have been washed or cooked.\n**Farsi**: آبکش",
    "back": "colander"
  },
  {
    "id": "e16001cd-ea2a-4b53-a232-9a7ef43b9452",
    "front": "**Def**: remove the liquid from food or containers.\n**Farsi**: آبکش کردن، آب اضافی را خارج کردن",
    "back": "drain"
  },
  {
    "id": "2a0a6466-046d-4b5c-9b9a-f0043a883370",
    "front": "**Def**: a tool used to grate cheese (e.g., parmesan).\n**Farsi**: رنده",
    "back": "grater"
  },
  {
    "id": "1773c199-a21f-4b05-90e1-561121f01cfc",
    "front": "**Def**: shred food into small pieces using a grater.\n**Farsi**: رنده کردن",
    "back": "grate"
  },
  {
    "id": "4f980fa7-5208-41a8-81aa-c629e1d8d490",
    "front": "**Def**: a tool used to crush garlic.\n**Farsi**: سیر له کن",
    "back": "garlic crusher"
  },
  {
    "id": "b09523f0-d153-42cf-a896-89f7116f4935",
    "front": "**Def**: press or squeeze forcefully so as to break or distort.\n**Farsi**: له کردن، کوبیدن",
    "back": "crush"
  },
  {
    "id": "a0e64b83-0542-4f20-aa24-80d149646c99",
    "front": "**Def**: a utensil used to separate solids from liquid or larger solids from smaller ones (e.g., flour).\n**Farsi**: الک، صافی",
    "back": "sieve (tool)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f1b6e105-229e-4bbb-8734-5ba6a1c92868",
    "front": "**Def**: pass food through a sieve.\n**Farsi**: الک کردن، صاف کردن",
    "back": "sieve (action)"
  },
  {
    "id": "c0fe948e-8439-43c7-abd2-73c814196c63",
    "front": "**Def**: a tool used to peel vegetables (e.g., potatoes).\n**Farsi**: پوست‌کن",
    "back": "peeler"
  },
  {
    "id": "9c57fa3e-09e3-49b0-984e-84d97c3059b1",
    "front": "**Def**: remove the outer skin or rind of a fruit or vegetable.\n**Farsi**: پوست کندن",
    "back": "peel"
  },
  {
    "id": "6f690ca7-d958-4840-b318-aeecabd3c4c1",
    "front": "**Def**: a small tool used to squeeze lemons or limes.\n**Farsi**: آب‌لیمو/آب‌مرکبات‌گیر",
    "back": "lemon squeezer"
  },
  {
    "id": "5fa6637f-dc97-46db-bb9a-9a32d5d85ae2",
    "front": "**Def**: press firmly, typically with one's fingers.\n**Farsi**: فشردن، آب گرفتن",
    "back": "squeeze"
  },
  {
    "id": "4ca0b548-dd8d-498f-bedc-7255586c790c",
    "front": "**Def**: a tool used to open wine bottles by pulling out the cork.\n**Farsi**: چوب‌پنبه‌بازکن",
    "back": "corkscrew"
  },
  {
    "id": "d5ccf334-e136-471d-aeda-f503b68d3bb4",
    "front": "**Def**: a large long-handled spoon with a cup-shaped bowl, used to serve soup.\n**Farsi**: ملاقه",
    "back": "ladle"
  },
  {
    "id": "eb5dd268-7987-4935-8102-e74c110c56af",
    "front": "**Def**: present food or drink to someone.\n**Farsi**: سرو کردن",
    "back": "serve"
  },
  {
    "id": "21fb5cb9-ddf6-4d93-8c63-339f7d5d26cd",
    "front": "**Def**: an instrument used to weigh all types of food.\n**Farsi**: ترازوی آشپزخانه",
    "back": "kitchen scales"
  },
  {
    "id": "8273230b-4400-4d7b-8835-fa07ae274b48",
    "front": "**Def**: find out how heavy something is.\n**Farsi**: وزن کردن",
    "back": "weigh"
  },
  {
    "id": "2b3a8694-ce1c-4b18-905e-b571ef331ec0",
    "front": "**Def**: go badly wrong and be very unsuccessful.\n**Farsi**: به مشکل خوردن، خراب شدن (نقشه، برنامه)",
    "back": "go pear-shaped (idiom, INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f0116645-a516-40c3-a5f1-dbe9dd468f56",
    "front": "**Def**: admit that something you said was wrong.\n**Farsi**: حرف خود را پس گرفتن، اعتراف به اشتباه کردن",
    "back": "eat your words (idiom)"
  },
  {
    "id": "4582fa4c-8ec6-495a-ad18-4524a6499720",
    "front": "**Def**: protects the wearer from bullets (also bullet-proof armour/windows).\n**Farsi**: ضد گلوله (از استفاده کننده در برابر گلوله محافظت می‌کند)",
    "back": "bullet-proof"
  },
  {
    "id": "0939b676-2c04-4791-9648-7f84344b2337",
    "front": "**Def**: have the advantages of something without the disadvantages (implying selfishness).\n**Farsi**: هم خدا را خواستن هم خرما را، بهره‌مندی از همه مزایا بدون پذیرش معایب",
    "back": "have your cake and eat it (idiom)"
  },
  {
    "id": "d093fac8-0897-44fc-a737-94ecc6ba1ed3",
    "front": "**Def**: spend more time doing something than is necessary.\n**Farsi**: اغراق کردن، بیش از حد لازم وقت صرف کردن",
    "back": "make a meal of sth (idiom, INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "3e232a9c-14cb-416c-b8c8-fb6c7af6e6d3",
    "front": "**Def**: suspicious, and probably involving dishonesty.\n**Farsi**: مشکوک، بودار",
    "back": "fishy (adj, INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "5bf40c5d-7c07-4036-9c72-58fad6459be1",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who supports their family with money they earn.\n**Farsi**: نان‌آور خانواده",
    "back": "breadwinner"
  },
  {
    "id": "61e5e0b5-1277-4658-b0dc-4d0abe588034",
    "front": "**Def**: don't be too confident that something will be successful, because it may go wrong.\n**Farsi**: جوجه را آخر پاییز می‌شمارند (زود مطمئن نباش)",
    "back": "don't count your chickens (idiom, SAYING)"
  },
  {
    "id": "99e8e3a3-ce73-4640-99d0-eb1ededb2068",
    "front": "**Def**:  a crazy person.\n**Farsi**: آدم دیوانه، خل و چل",
    "back": "nutcase (n, INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "eda89b1e-fb28-4987-b190-976570b30c86",
    "front": "**Def**: used for saying that two people are very different.\n**Farsi**: مثل آسمان و ریسمان بودن، مثل زمین تا آسمان فرق داشتن",
    "back": "like chalk and cheese (idiom)"
  },
  {
    "id": "9d8b3e4b-85fd-4215-a755-ad7cc232295a",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely attractive or impressive. SYN beautiful.\n**Farsi**: حیرت‌انگیز، فوق‌العاده زیبا",
    "back": "stunning"
  },
  {
    "id": "fd19a3f9-d755-4daf-896a-086dd18bcb09",
    "front": "**Def**: growing and developing, and very successful. SYN flourishing.\n**Farsi**: پررونق، شکوفا، موفق",
    "back": "thriving"
  },
  {
    "id": "bf5d7562-0aeb-4de5-8925-8a83b462f0b1",
    "front": "**Def**: full of life and energy.\n**Farsi**: سرزنده، پرجنب و جوش",
    "back": "vibrant"
  },
  {
    "id": "dd4d2074-02af-4e60-a332-170d48fda623",
    "front": "**Def**: streets with a surface of old round stones.\n**Farsi**: خیابان‌های سنگفرش",
    "back": "cobbled streets"
  },
  {
    "id": "a848dfbe-6eb0-4820-98cb-f4dc58d9eef7",
    "front": "**Def**: in an unusual or surprising way. remarkable ADJ.\n**Farsi**: به طرز چشمگیری، قابل ملاحظه",
    "back": "remarkably"
  },
  {
    "id": "0496afb3-262e-4b8e-9199-81200f5148db",
    "front": "**Def**: of many different kinds.\n**Farsi**: متنوع",
    "back": "diverse"
  },
  {
    "id": "96feb441-acae-44af-8e3d-6e3ecfba5902",
    "front": "**Def**: experience a process of change.\n**Farsi**: متحمل شدن، از سر گذراندن",
    "back": "undergo sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "473d42d0-3541-439d-a04c-00f07ad62f67",
    "front": "**Def**: the work of repairing old buildings, paintings, etc.\n**Farsi**: مرمت، بازسازی",
    "back": "restoration"
  },
  {
    "id": "c3a17c32-ebf5-4cb1-a98d-0a72b7c93340",
    "front": "**Def**: relax and do very little.\n**Farsi**: اوقات را به بطالت گذراندن، استراحت مطلق کردن",
    "back": "laze around"
  },
  {
    "id": "9b53912f-e6cb-4ab4-9582-9caf06e97006",
    "front": "**Def**: absorb or take something into your senses, body, or mind.\n**Farsi**: جذب کردن، لذت بردن کامل (از چیزی)",
    "back": "soak sth up"
  },
  {
    "id": "5abfdd2b-5bc5-4aa7-8403-577a43ff3d35",
    "front": "**Def**: walk slowly without a real purpose or direction.\n**Farsi**: گشت و گذار کردن، پرسه زدن",
    "back": "go for a wander (around/in)"
  },
  {
    "id": "c6d71fa7-9b20-43fd-9552-31f0b60c867c",
    "front": "**Def**: keep something. retention N.\n**Farsi**: حفظ کردن، نگه داشتن",
    "back": "retain sth (FML)"
  },
  {
    "id": "035bdaba-9bdf-452f-b3e0-cdad993b71dd",
    "front": "**Def**: a pleasant or attractive quality or feature.\n**Farsi**: جذابیت، دلربایی",
    "back": "charm"
  },
  {
    "id": "32d58c47-438d-4610-8ce9-905092c1ebf9",
    "front": "**Def**: far away from other people and houses.\n**Farsi**: دورافتاده، خارج از مسیر معمول گردشگری",
    "back": "off the beaten track"
  },
  {
    "id": "7c427ae0-51ee-49fc-920b-09b3b45957d0",
    "front": "**Def**: a long hard walk, often in the mountains.\n**Farsi**: پیاده‌روی طولانی و دشوار",
    "back": "trek"
  },
  {
    "id": "8950a87a-c795-41f0-b32b-e71a579c78a3",
    "front": "**Def**: being the only one of its kind.\n**Farsi**: منحصر به فرد، بی‌نظیر",
    "back": "unique"
  },
  {
    "id": "9e25a2d1-6b71-4b53-aac3-2f97820aaa11",
    "front": "**Def**: go somewhere different to have a rest or holiday.\n**Farsi**: از همه چیز دور شدن و استراحت کردن",
    "back": "get away from it all"
  },
  {
    "id": "ba7e9fb4-e532-4a04-84f5-fc9ad35e1d09",
    "front": "**Def**: far from places where other people live. SYN isolated.\n**Farsi**: دور، پرت افتاده",
    "back": "remote"
  },
  {
    "id": "bda905df-9fe7-4e4e-8d9a-11b8410c8106",
    "front": "**Def**: (of a place) beautiful because it has not been changed or built on.\n**Farsi**: دست نخورده، بکر",
    "back": "unspoilt"
  },
  {
    "id": "7a816fec-72f5-4b81-933a-6f2d983b4885",
    "front": "**Def**: relax (SYN take it easy, chill out).\n**Farsi**: ریلکس کردن، آرام شدن",
    "back": "unwind"
  },
  {
    "id": "04374862-5869-4cde-8868-159e152970c2",
    "front": "**Def**: able to accept a bad situation that you cannot change. SYN resigned to sth.\n**Farsi**: کنار آمدن با، پذیرفتن (قادر به پذیرش وضعیتی بد که نمی‌توان آن را تغییر داد. مترادف: resigned to)",
    "back": "reconciled to sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "f7147124-3ca5-44b2-a217-5863bcf6fd20",
    "front": "**Def**: relax.\n**Farsi**: آرامش گرفتن، حال کردن (عامیانه)",
    "back": "chill out (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "0c722a0e-4495-4d28-abe1-79c47ece4c46",
    "front": "**Def**: valued traditions, historical buildings, etc.\n**Farsi**: میراث فرهنگی",
    "back": "heritage"
  },
  {
    "id": "211b7dae-8245-4367-81b1-152bcbdbdbce",
    "front": "**Def**: exciting and unusual, often from a distant place.\n**Farsi**: عجیب و غریب، غیربومی",
    "back": "exotic"
  },
  {
    "id": "cd5d09cc-ff8d-46b2-9646-a1c8bd304bf9",
    "front": "**Def**: famous for something.\n**Farsi**: مشهور، نامدار",
    "back": "renowned"
  },
  {
    "id": "42073363-6862-4c87-93fc-846ac0b7b8c6",
    "front": "**Def**: travelling a long distance (flight/destination).\n**Farsi**: مسافت طولانی",
    "back": "long-haul"
  },
  {
    "id": "266f3acc-c5d5-4986-9262-40d18f781916",
    "front": "**Def**: calm and peaceful.\n**Farsi**: آرام، ساکت و آرامش‌بخش",
    "back": "tranquil"
  },
  {
    "id": "ccebc617-e4c8-4815-8a54-487418df943e",
    "front": "**Def**: very frightening or exciting in a way that you enjoy.\n**Farsi**: هیجان‌انگیز، مو بر تن سیخ کن",
    "back": "spine-tingling"
  },
  {
    "id": "e28a03b5-ac54-4fb8-a6a4-bf10dc858434",
    "front": "**Def**: a story about the spirit of a dead person that sb hears or sees.\n**Farsi**: داستان ارواح، داستان شبح",
    "back": "ghost story"
  },
  {
    "id": "6e5499de-1d7e-4225-a588-8dea3e72a411",
    "front": "**Def**: very excited and interested in something (often a story or performance).\n**Farsi**: لب مرز نشستن (بسیار هیجان‌زده و مشتاق بودن)",
    "back": "on the edge of your seat (idiom)"
  },
  {
    "id": "fdf10beb-2eea-4a6a-a468-2a2f6b43059f",
    "front": "**Def**: the scenery and furniture used in a play, film, etc.\n**Farsi**: صحنه آرایی، دکور",
    "back": "set"
  },
  {
    "id": "7d6e3bfc-a30e-47c3-994c-ef5b680fd557",
    "front": "**Def**: sounds that are made artificially in a play, film, etc., to make it more realistic.\n**Farsi**: جلوه‌های صوتی",
    "back": "sound effects"
  },
  {
    "id": "5acebfb1-27be-4824-a1ba-19553b074421",
    "front": "**Def**: frighten someone very much.\n**Farsi**: تا سر حد مرگ ترساندن",
    "back": "scare sb out of their wits (idiom)"
  },
  {
    "id": "c258132c-f084-4bff-8f1a-7c68cc5b760c",
    "front": "**Def**: making you very excited or worried. SYN gripping.\n**Farsi**: پرتنش، هیجان‌آور (به حدی که ناخن بجوی)",
    "back": "nail-biting"
  },
  {
    "id": "ec09eddc-9eb3-4a58-ab4d-6c2b6a9d66cc",
    "front": "**Def**: a book or play that has been made into a film, TV programme, etc.\n**Farsi**: اقتباس",
    "back": "adaptation"
  },
  {
    "id": "f7205bbf-a1c2-4188-bb0e-b9ae9f183038",
    "front": "**Def**: an unexpected change or development in a story or situation.\n**Farsi**: پیچش داستانی، تحول غیرمنتظره",
    "back": "twist"
  },
  {
    "id": "8a969f4d-2533-4e15-ae29-04e475ba64e7",
    "front": "**Def**: (singular or plural verb) all the people who act in a play or film.\n**Farsi**: بازیگران، تیم بازیگری",
    "back": "cast"
  },
  {
    "id": "ff901ec8-4762-423c-9090-4464af4a7e99",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely good; wonderful. SYNS fabulous, brilliant.\n**Farsi**: فوق‌العاده، محشر، عالی",
    "back": "sensational (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "26f6106d-1d4a-4b89-8271-528317c9e604",
    "front": "**Def**: the sound of an audience showing approval by hitting their hands together. applaud V.\n**Farsi**: کف زدن، تشویق",
    "back": "applause"
  },
  {
    "id": "40071c78-9951-44ea-a8f3-ae2757160772",
    "front": "**Def**: in a very great or impressive way. SYN extraordinarily.\n**Farsi**: به طور فوق‌العاده‌ای، به نحو چشمگیری",
    "back": "phenomenally"
  },
  {
    "id": "5ec91fd7-3510-4cf1-bff2-eb322dbb0970",
    "front": "**Def**: in a way that is agreed by everyone. unanimous ADJ.\n**Farsi**: به اتفاق آراء، یک‌صدا",
    "back": "unanimously"
  },
  {
    "id": "de26eb9c-cd86-4075-8465-04c86cb18a10",
    "front": "**Def**: publicly talked or written about in an admiring way. acclaim N.\n**Farsi**: تحسین شده، مورد ستایش قرار گرفته",
    "back": "acclaimed"
  },
  {
    "id": "67f621f7-9e45-4c91-9409-3a270f6fc852",
    "front": "**Def**: very bad and unpleasant. SYN dire INF.\n**Farsi**: افتضاح، فجیع، خیلی بد",
    "back": "atrocious"
  },
  {
    "id": "d97f27e9-ef07-40e5-b856-829218f1ae50",
    "front": "**Def**: making people experience feelings of sadness, sympathy, etc. in a deliberate and obvious way.\n**Farsi**: احساساتی (با بار منفی)، آبکی",
    "back": "sentimental (DISAPPROVING)"
  },
  {
    "id": "6a78f9a1-c395-4cbe-bde7-ebf792f967d9",
    "front": "**Def**: boring, long, and slow.\n**Farsi**: خسته کننده، ملال‌آور",
    "back": "tedious"
  },
  {
    "id": "3047e1ca-8214-495b-85c0-20a2fd213417",
    "front": "**Def**: a phrase or idea that has been used so often it no longer has much meaning and is not interesting. clichéd ADJ.\n**Farsi**: کلیشه",
    "back": "cliché"
  },
  {
    "id": "bb624dc7-04e4-46fd-ae3e-f36c27a29f07",
    "front": "**Def**: not showing serious thought, feelings, etc. SYN superficial.\n**Farsi**: سطحی، کم عمق",
    "back": "shallow"
  },
  {
    "id": "f4c68fca-bb25-49b4-99a0-6e41a7ab5bfc",
    "front": "**Def**: very weak.\n**Farsi**: ضعیف، سست",
    "back": "feeble"
  },
  {
    "id": "0efda874-bcbf-4207-9dda-3e13578f4598",
    "front": "**Def**: not showing enough natural expression, emotion, or movement (especially acting/dialogue).\n**Farsi**: بی‌روح، خشک، غیرطبیعی",
    "back": "wooden"
  },
  {
    "id": "0dc632cf-b9e3-48f0-a0da-5a9e680373c2",
    "front": "**Def**: of only average quality.\n**Farsi**: متوسط، نه چندان خوب",
    "back": "mediocre"
  },
  {
    "id": "d0059b00-c520-4df7-888b-a35955f6a9a3",
    "front": "**Def**: needing sb/sth in order to survive or be successful.\n**Farsi**: وابسته به (نیاز داشتن به کسی/چیزی برای بقا یا موفقیت)",
    "back": "dependent on sb/sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "212b1888-0b72-4e1b-85e3-deb62a35c9fd",
    "front": "**Def**: not seeming true or real. OPP convincing.\n**Farsi**: غیرقابل باور، نامطمئن",
    "back": "unconvincing"
  },
  {
    "id": "cd0b144e-e7e6-4632-bfe1-70ec4a7998a2",
    "front": "**Def**: complete (used to emphasize something bad).\n**Farsi**: تمام، مطلق (معمولاً برای تأکید بر بدی)",
    "back": "utter"
  },
  {
    "id": "1563d953-d0da-4d58-86f1-43f54e76def1",
    "front": "**Def**: poor quality; nonsense.\n**Farsi**: مزخرف، آشغال",
    "back": "rubbish (n, INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "423e41f8-7b9e-48c2-8b26-be3089c44dc5",
    "front": "**Def**: very boring.\n**Farsi**: به طرز کشنده‌ای کسل‌کننده",
    "back": "deadly dull (idiom)"
  },
  {
    "id": "9c0d5895-7317-4b02-a4e9-a772fc76b112",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely bored.\n**Farsi**: از شدت بی‌حوصلگی (به ستوه آمدن)",
    "back": "bored to tears/death/stiff/out of your mind (idioms)"
  },
  {
    "id": "ed622cf4-d0b6-4ab3-ac36-f23aeb4c9517",
    "front": "**Def**: clever and funny.\n**Farsi**: بذله‌گو، شوخ طبع",
    "back": "witty"
  },
  {
    "id": "646be8ec-fafb-4b06-8f22-55143d8685a3",
    "front": "**Def**: talk enthusiastically about something.\n**Farsi**: با اشتیاق ستایش کردن",
    "back": "rave about sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "7e274f77-8168-4336-b936-d26b40548523",
    "front": "**Def**: containing a mixture of sadness and happiness.\n**Farsi**: تلخ و شیرین",
    "back": "bitter-sweet"
  },
  {
    "id": "7755248c-9799-4e9a-980f-f92d3e066adf",
    "front": "**Def**: a film or story intended to make the audience cry.\n**Farsi**: فیلم/داستان اشک‌آور",
    "back": "tear jerker"
  },
  {
    "id": "6a3a0a53-7081-41f6-be70-86a30286d408",
    "front": "**Def**: unpleasant and depressing.\n**Farsi**: سخت، گرفته، تیره و تار",
    "back": "grim"
  },
  {
    "id": "16edd339-02c1-41bc-806d-cecf51813160",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely distressing or painful.\n**Farsi**: دلخراش، اندوه‌آور",
    "back": "harrowing"
  },
  {
    "id": "fb6e8af8-02fe-4962-938f-b2d9c456b5e4",
    "front": "**Def**: playing in their own stadium. OPP away.\n**Farsi**: در خانه، در زمین خودی",
    "back": "at home"
  },
  {
    "id": "cbe251a3-1c3b-4cae-b941-aeb2b486c4be",
    "front": "**Def**: be good enough to enter a competition or reach a stage.\n**Farsi**: واجد شرایط شدن، صلاحیت پیدا کردن",
    "back": "qualify for sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "6c2e9329-b946-4982-9732-4246a1892266",
    "front": "**Def**: a competition where the winner continues and the loser is eliminated.\n**Farsi**: حذفی (مسابقات)",
    "back": "knockout"
  },
  {
    "id": "e2eb1b1e-d156-44be-987d-0c95030b5904",
    "front": "**Def**: a person or team that comes second in a competition.\n**Farsi**: نایب قهرمان(ها)، تیم دوم",
    "back": "runner(s)-up"
  },
  {
    "id": "8f055974-18be-4cc5-b135-bc9f323320c0",
    "front": "**Def**: the remaining people or things; the others.\n**Farsi**: بقیه، مابقی",
    "back": "the rest (of sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "871c060e-39dd-4703-b09a-2a10bbed5a03",
    "front": "**Def**: an act of deciding which teams play against each other by pulling names out of a bag. be drawn (against sb) v.\n**Farsi**: قرعه‌کشی",
    "back": "draw (n)"
  },
  {
    "id": "a026fb67-a685-4821-a4b8-3d2118562a06",
    "front": "**Def**: a stage in a sports competition.\n**Farsi**: دور (مسابقات)",
    "back": "round"
  },
  {
    "id": "0a6002c2-7ea3-4d2a-b760-f0741348111a",
    "front": "**Def**: reach the next stage in a competition.\n**Farsi**: صعود کردن، راه یافتن (به مرحله بعد)",
    "back": "get through (to sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "abd1f4f5-dea8-4e22-892d-b7dbff7c0efa",
    "front": "**Def**: not belonging to either of the teams who are playing.\n**Farsi**: بی‌طرف",
    "back": "neutral"
  },
  {
    "id": "a32e1ffa-ca99-4384-82c1-b6ed8ca6aa4e",
    "front": "**Def**: a place where an organized event happens.\n**Farsi**: محل برگزاری",
    "back": "venue"
  },
  {
    "id": "1064d9f8-3066-477a-90c0-d6b65de3a265",
    "front": "**Def**: success in a game, war, etc. victorious ADJ.\n**Farsi**: پیروزی، فتح",
    "back": "victory"
  },
  {
    "id": "5cf00dc9-4cf0-42d1-8da8-615f789c379a",
    "front": "**Def**: the way in which someone is performing (in or on good/great form; off form).\n**Farsi**: فرم، عملکرد، وضعیت آمادگی",
    "back": "form (performance)"
  },
  {
    "id": "e19d7dd5-5539-48a4-9fbf-5b5151d45b45",
    "front": "**Def**: a set of teams who play each other over a season to find the best team.\n**Farsi**: لیگ",
    "back": "league"
  },
  {
    "id": "65cbf9f8-9500-4437-a9df-3b4573066a9e",
    "front": "**Def**: a period of performing well or badly.\n**Farsi**: دوره (خوب/بد) عملکرد",
    "back": "a (good/bad) run"
  },
  {
    "id": "d916cafc-a6fd-47ff-960c-5d1611cece21",
    "front": "**Def**: not having lost.\n**Farsi**: شکست‌ناپذیر، بدون باخت",
    "back": "unbeaten"
  },
  {
    "id": "ed159454-2989-41cb-9d1b-e9b3993c547c",
    "front": "**Def**: the action of moving a team up to a higher league. OPP relegation N.\n**Farsi**: صعود (به لیگ بالاتر)",
    "back": "promotion"
  },
  {
    "id": "35f4651f-c5d3-45f2-b1a5-8b8d8d956d56",
    "front": "**Def**: fail to give someone the help and support they need.\n**Farsi**: ناامید کردن، تنها گذاشتن",
    "back": "let sb down"
  },
  {
    "id": "d99adf7f-16c4-40f0-be5a-47f9dbb5267d",
    "front": "**Def**: in a stressful situation.\n**Farsi**: تحت فشار",
    "back": "under pressure"
  },
  {
    "id": "3f196f5b-e527-4aae-9b0b-cbc3009bc30e",
    "front": "**Def**: sit down and relax.\n**Farsi**: لم دادن و استراحت کردن",
    "back": "put your feet up (idiom)"
  },
  {
    "id": "425e85ac-cdb4-4305-95d7-631b677ab7fc",
    "front": "**Def**: used for emphasizing that sth is true even though it is the opposite of what has been suggested.\n**Farsi**: برعکس، در مقابل (برای تاکید بر اینکه چیزی درست است، حتی اگر مخالف آنچه پیشنهاد شده باشد)",
    "back": "on the contrary"
  },
  {
    "id": "a9f46758-c1d9-4ba4-82d6-6831005fcdd6",
    "front": "**Def**: (in sport) play better than and be in control of the game. SYN be on top.\n**Farsi**: مسلط بودن، برتری داشتن",
    "back": "dominate"
  },
  {
    "id": "3d04ffc2-89eb-4337-b274-b1147e8fad5a",
    "front": "**Def**: near to the moment of doing or achieving something.\n**Farsi**: در آستانه چیزی بودن",
    "back": "on the verge of sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "e78212d2-3dbd-411b-83b9-f4fc9cf2770b",
    "front": "**Def**: a small chance (of success).\n**Farsi**: شانس ضعیف",
    "back": "outside chance"
  },
  {
    "id": "d91d4e26-8ab5-49d1-87cd-886a9ec99816",
    "front": "**Def**: a high possibility; good opportunity.\n**Farsi**: شانس بزرگ",
    "back": "great chance"
  },
  {
    "id": "44511cb9-7171-4b79-be33-5020885fb7b5",
    "front": "**Def**: a sports match that is arranged to be played on a particular date.\n**Farsi**: برنامه مسابقات، بازی تعیین شده",
    "back": "fixture"
  },
  {
    "id": "2e51506d-f837-4fa6-a609-9069496e1352",
    "front": "**Def**: hire a player to play for a team.\n**Farsi**: بازیکن جدید جذب کردن",
    "back": "sign a player"
  },
  {
    "id": "764ae42c-566d-4263-8422-8ce5fec06f06",
    "front": "**Def**: defeat someone heavily.\n**Farsi**: شکست سخت دادن، درهم کوبیدن",
    "back": "thrash sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "310a9b48-b060-4159-9a4c-b3d9e32a4860",
    "front": "**Def**: move a player from one team to another.\n**Farsi**: انتقال دادن (بازیکن)",
    "back": "transfer sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "78212960-cc0b-4c86-8f03-6dafd2168553",
    "front": "**Def**: a ranked player or team in a competition.\n**Farsi**: سید (بازیکن/تیم رده‌بندی شده)",
    "back": "seed (n)"
  },
  {
    "id": "3547ab99-fb7d-43ec-a46f-5f6517ef14e2",
    "front": "**Def**: play your first game for a team.\n**Farsi**: اولین بازی خود را انجام دادن",
    "back": "make your debut"
  },
  {
    "id": "69eb1cdc-122e-4ce1-ab18-6eb398d9b691",
    "front": "**Def**: SYN copy sth/sb.\n**Farsi**: تقلید کردن",
    "back": "imitate sth/sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "ce96fc10-2155-48e3-81c8-40c6ac52e025",
    "front": "**Def**: obtain something by buying it or being given it.\n**Farsi**: به دست آوردن، کسب کردن",
    "back": "acquire sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "d4ab5521-53ae-4550-9857-457be8c22cb0",
    "front": "**Def**: a small house, especially in the country.\n**Farsi**: کلبه، خانه ییلاقی",
    "back": "cottage"
  },
  {
    "id": "c50015f7-f7b6-439b-8848-ded702326e7a",
    "front": "**Def**: animals, birds, and insects that live in a natural state.\n**Farsi**: حیات وحش",
    "back": "wildlife"
  },
  {
    "id": "14515db8-04d7-4ce1-84c8-2ef8a96936eb",
    "front": "**Def**: an area of land that is used for something (camping site/building site).\n**Farsi**: محل، سایت، قطعه زمین",
    "back": "site"
  },
  {
    "id": "1f2f8137-2f5c-4943-9bfe-9d6bca284231",
    "front": "**Def**: an area of land that is higher at one end than the other.\n**Farsi**: شیب، سراشیبی",
    "back": "slope"
  },
  {
    "id": "472360af-a1b7-4c50-b4b8-34dec43bc5a4",
    "front": "**Def**: a small simple building, made of wood, and often found in gardens.\n**Farsi**: آلونک، انبار کوچک",
    "back": "shed"
  },
  {
    "id": "cf1a6120-83ac-4f10-9ed0-b00b5d1eb41e",
    "front": "**Def**: make something/someone come towards you.\n**Farsi**: جذب کردن، جلب کردن",
    "back": "attract sth/sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "1830476b-03cf-4138-b943-e2160a97f720",
    "front": "**Def**: throw or drop things in different directions over a wide area.\n**Farsi**: پراکنده کردن، افشاندن",
    "back": "scatter sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "38040817-92c4-49a2-8341-acc80abb14c0",
    "front": "**Def**: the small hard part of a plant from which new plants grow.\n**Farsi**: دانه، تخم",
    "back": "seed"
  },
  {
    "id": "c69eaa5f-30dc-42c4-b59f-bfc88ec2a2bb",
    "front": "**Def**: a field covered in grass, and often wild flowers.\n**Farsi**: چمنزار، مرغزار",
    "back": "meadow"
  },
  {
    "id": "dbae61bb-b9ff-410a-bc66-d23bf6784d75",
    "front": "**Def**: a place where birds lay their eggs and live with their young. nest v.\n**Farsi**: لانه، آشیانه",
    "back": "nest"
  },
  {
    "id": "ef88763f-3538-498b-af58-7a43048487cb",
    "front": "**Def**: the physical world and everything that lives in it.\n**Farsi**: طبیعت",
    "back": "nature (concept)"
  },
  {
    "id": "1d413888-45ce-4828-8424-6dea021e36a1",
    "front": "**Def**: a small job that you have to do regularly, often around the home.\n**Farsi**: کار روزمره، وظیفه",
    "back": "chore"
  },
  {
    "id": "5befb451-6cf7-4c00-9c1f-4b3f56c8ec82",
    "front": "**Def**: a mixture of decaying plants and food that is added to soil to help things grow.\n**Farsi**: کود گیاهی، کمپوست",
    "back": "compost"
  },
  {
    "id": "085c210c-846f-4f57-9089-ab9a9802bbbc",
    "front": "**Def**: improve the quality of something by adding something to it.\n**Farsi**: غنی‌سازی کردن",
    "back": "enrich sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "29390fa0-3eab-47e5-9bdc-a469172d0180",
    "front": "**Def**: the top part of the earth in which trees and plants grow.\n**Farsi**: خاک",
    "back": "soil"
  },
  {
    "id": "7bf5dbdd-305d-4bef-aac2-fe05235cac6f",
    "front": "**Def**: remove some of a plant's stems or branches to improve future growth. SYN cut sth back.\n**Farsi**: هرس کردن، شاخه‌زنی کردن",
    "back": "prune sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "9cc0c0aa-756c-4cb6-a1b7-b55f57a0f5cf",
    "front": "**Def**: (of the earth) wet from too much rain. mud N.\n**Farsi**: گِل‌آلود",
    "back": "muddy"
  },
  {
    "id": "d52ed9cc-51b1-4cb5-a938-889fc3c0bfa4",
    "front": "**Def**: remove the weeds (= wild plants growing where they are not wanted).\n**Farsi**: علف هرز کندن",
    "back": "do the weeding"
  },
  {
    "id": "20b95802-b594-49e6-a9f1-13f009f93b1c",
    "front": "**Def**: successful, and admired and respected by others. SYN illustrious.\n**Farsi**: برجسته، متمایز (موفق، و مورد تحسین و احترام دیگران. مترادف: illustrious)",
    "back": "distinguished"
  },
  {
    "id": "9b190a44-6029-4939-b1ac-581cd88980c2",
    "front": "**Def**: put flowers and other plants into the soil.\n**Farsi**: کاشتن",
    "back": "plant sth (v)"
  },
  {
    "id": "58006880-1a44-4649-97b8-fdaf94461ffe",
    "front": "**Def**: cut the grass on the lawn.\n**Farsi**: چمن‌زنی کردن",
    "back": "mow the lawn"
  },
  {
    "id": "82aa8c84-6114-4fad-b8ca-87796c56f36c",
    "front": "**Def**: a tool used for digging (a shovel).\n**Farsi**: بیلچه، بیل",
    "back": "spade"
  },
  {
    "id": "ca18c145-3a2a-4440-bc76-71c71fcb4874",
    "front": "**Def**: a machine for cutting grass.\n**Farsi**: ماشین چمن‌زنی",
    "back": "lawnmower"
  },
  {
    "id": "cc7c5a00-8de1-4ede-90dc-cb3ca2824deb",
    "front": "**Def**: a garden tool with a long handle and prongs, used for gathering leaves.\n**Farsi**: چنگک، شن‌کش",
    "back": "rake"
  },
  {
    "id": "56334eff-41b5-4d05-883b-7fc2315838e0",
    "front": "**Def**: plant seeds in the ground.\n**Farsi**: بذر کاشتن، تخم پاشیدن",
    "back": "sow (v)"
  },
  {
    "id": "40323cc3-5b9d-41af-89cd-109334af8df9",
    "front": "**Def**: small animals or insects that damage plants or food.\n**Farsi**: آفت‌ها",
    "back": "pests"
  },
  {
    "id": "870e74dc-399a-454a-a0e5-91c386389f7e",
    "front": "**Def**: looking for something.\n**Farsi**: در جستجوی چیزی",
    "back": "in search of sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "699b06eb-50ed-45ee-9432-a6bdd347eccf",
    "front": "**Def**: a label on something which shows how much you must pay.\n**Farsi**: برچسب قیمت",
    "back": "price tag"
  },
  {
    "id": "42809f65-bd82-4b2e-be90-0f8d4645fe93",
    "front": "**Def**: spend a long time shopping because you don't want to stop (till = until).\n**Farsi**: آنقدر خرید کردن که از حال بروی",
    "back": "shop till you drop (idiom, MODERN INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "33f87c51-6f3f-4089-ab0a-fab776d5029b",
    "front": "**Def**: casually look at things in a shop, or look through the pages of a book.\n**Farsi**: سرسری نگاه کردن، گشت زدن (در مغازه)",
    "back": "browse (v)"
  },
  {
    "id": "c9453e77-9f51-481a-877a-9fe4da91e7a4",
    "front": "**Def**: looking for and trying to obtain something.\n**Farsi**: در پی چیزی بودن",
    "back": "after sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "077ec0da-ef13-41cd-8aad-91152d2148d8",
    "front": "**Def**: as soon as. SYN the moment.\n**Farsi**: همین که، به محض اینکه",
    "back": "the minute (phrase)"
  },
  {
    "id": "01cfff50-7a8d-4e0d-a898-9e23dd6f10fd",
    "front": "**Def**: go; leave.\n**Farsi**: رفتن، ترک کردن (مکان)",
    "back": "be off (phrasal verb)"
  },
  {
    "id": "6c1dffe4-eb4a-40b8-913f-f7947c9eced3",
    "front": "**Def**: have a natural ability to see or find something (often used for bargains or detail).\n**Farsi**: ذوق و سلیقه داشتن، چشم تیزبین داشتن (برای چیزی)",
    "back": "have an eye for sth (idiom)"
  },
  {
    "id": "ba0d9494-4a14-44ee-ad89-d33677bad40e",
    "front": "**Def**: go to different shops until you find what you want.\n**Farsi**: مغازه به مغازه گشتن (برای یافتن بهترین قیمت/محصول)",
    "back": "shop around (v)"
  },
  {
    "id": "ef1e6651-18d7-4511-ba59-58134ea02fd0",
    "front": "**Def**: having a very clear aim; knowing what you want to do.\n**Farsi**: متمرکز",
    "back": "focused"
  },
  {
    "id": "d5ffc76a-f32b-42c7-92fd-dffa2714d14f",
    "front": "**Def**: be looking at or thinking about something so that you are unable to pay attention to other things.\n**Farsi**: حواس‌پرتی پیدا کردن، پرت شدن حواس توسط چیزی",
    "back": "be distracted by sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "46eaf00c-f1f0-4955-a119-20a447fa9418",
    "front": "**Def**: hobby, pastime (leisure/outdoor pursuits).\n**Farsi**: سرگرمی، مشغله",
    "back": "pursuit (leisure)"
  },
  {
    "id": "7eb58bc7-5bbd-4c41-ba12-7c89d7ca63a1",
    "front": "**Def**: a short period of time doing one activity in an uncontrolled way (spending/shopping spree).\n**Farsi**: ولخرجی، افراط (در یک دوره کوتاه)",
    "back": "spree"
  },
  {
    "id": "4759747e-4efc-402a-b7a3-00dbfae34078",
    "front": "**Def**: looking for something at a good price and cheaper than usual.\n**Farsi**: شکار تخفیف، جستجوی ارزان‌قیمت",
    "back": "bargain hunting"
  },
  {
    "id": "9c0e1a27-e1d7-4fe4-a67f-d8934b2ffa40",
    "front": "**Def**: go in the direction of.\n**Farsi**: به سمت جایی رفتن، رهسپار شدن",
    "back": "head for/towards"
  },
  {
    "id": "405a0b5d-302b-4f46-8fb4-bbe9f15c0bc4",
    "front": "**Def**: do something you like, especially something that is bad for you.\n**Farsi**: افراط کردن، زیاده‌روی کردن",
    "back": "indulge in sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "d710ab2c-6e1b-4a4c-80de-16a62ea2694a",
    "front": "**Def**: a small tool or piece of equipment that does something useful.\n**Farsi**: ابزارک، وسیله کاربردی کوچک",
    "back": "gadget"
  },
  {
    "id": "100cf526-bd2e-43ce-82cc-e6f62ab4a7e0",
    "front": "**Def**: someone who enjoys shopping and spends a lot of time doing it.\n**Farsi**: خرید بیمارگونه، معتاد به خرید",
    "back": "shopaholic (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "15529dba-d8f3-4788-afb4-77591de22d05",
    "front": "**Def**: finding it difficult to control their actions (a compulsive shopper/gambler/liar).\n**Farsi**: اجباری، غیرقابل کنترل",
    "back": "compulsive"
  },
  {
    "id": "a5fe18d7-61e6-4586-b2d5-73b607cb6a89",
    "front": "**Def**: unable to stop doing something which is usually harmful. addict N.\n**Farsi**: معتاد به چیزی",
    "back": "addicted to sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "791e5c24-127b-4f29-8f9b-4c9f13a8a1b9",
    "front": "**Def**: To treat a sick person successfully.\n**Farsi**: درمان کردن",
    "back": "cure V."
  },
  {
    "id": "ebb8432d-9663-4757-a55a-464f6c17b9af",
    "front": "**Def**: spend more than someone else.\n**Farsi**: بیشتر خرج کردن",
    "back": "outspend (prefix out-)"
  },
  {
    "id": "68c5f288-6429-4923-8f4d-9567775b5cf5",
    "front": "**Def**: be greater or more important than something else.\n**Farsi**: سنگین‌تر بودن، ارجح بودن",
    "back": "outweigh (prefix out-)"
  },
  {
    "id": "62fde74c-b462-44b0-af46-2b8aea961598",
    "front": "**Def**: shopping to cheer yourself up.\n**Farsi**: تسکین روحی با خرید",
    "back": "retail therapy"
  },
  {
    "id": "49164178-55a6-488b-8e5a-0f613e1cbd51",
    "front": "**Def**: a shop that sells donated goods for charity.\n**Farsi**: مغازه خیریه",
    "back": "charity shop"
  },
  {
    "id": "6c001fc7-090b-4630-9c2a-328303d19428",
    "front": "**Def**: argue about the price until a lower price is agreed.\n**Farsi**: چانه زدن",
    "back": "haggle"
  },
  {
    "id": "892d01f0-262b-4ae5-ab18-902341bfa1e5",
    "front": "**Def**: feel excitement from an activity.\n**Farsi**: لذت/هیجان شدید بردن از چیزی",
    "back": "get a buzz/rush from sth (idiom)"
  },
  {
    "id": "6a4abbd0-5ae4-4158-95d8-1a9ff66c9833",
    "front": "**Def**: spend time with other people in a friendly way. sociable ADJ.\n**Farsi**: اجتماعی شدن، معاشرت کردن",
    "back": "socialize (v)"
  },
  {
    "id": "bb732948-cd26-4ff5-9d8e-5ebc7dae0c3a",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who is giving a meal or a party. hostess N.\n**Farsi**: میزبان",
    "back": "host (n)"
  },
  {
    "id": "5a849839-0f54-49ab-b190-6c6a33481393",
    "front": "**Def**: provide something for someone, especially food, drink, or transport.\n**Farsi**: تدارک دیدن، فراهم کردن",
    "back": "lay sth on (phrasal verb, INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "120e3df7-20be-46f3-8bfd-d8f23f422e4d",
    "front": "**Def**: needing a lot of time (a time-consuming process).\n**Farsi**: زمان‌بر",
    "back": "time-consuming"
  },
  {
    "id": "2fe42cc6-14a4-497a-ac00-85bbad4eb199",
    "front": "**Def**: a thing that you give or do to help something be successful. contribute v.\n**Farsi**: مشارکت، سهم، کمک",
    "back": "contribution"
  },
  {
    "id": "de2f4486-0308-485e-bda2-8e722e87ceda",
    "front": "**Def**: leave everything clean and tidy (after a party/mess).\n**Farsi**: مرتب کردن، جمع و جور کردن",
    "back": "clear (sth) up"
  },
  {
    "id": "403f7e6a-58be-4cac-a0fb-cc2a80baeccb",
    "front": "**Def**: intended to be used once or twice then thrown away.\n**Farsi**: یکبار مصرف",
    "back": "disposable"
  },
  {
    "id": "83162a6d-9603-4ab9-8216-9d7722e0ee63",
    "front": "**Def**: before something else happens or is done.\n**Farsi**: از قبل، پیشاپیش",
    "back": "beforehand (adv)"
  },
  {
    "id": "863bc2ea-114b-4e63-b458-9609ef1be1f5",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who tries to get into a party without an invitation.\n**Farsi**: مهمان ناخوانده (که خود را تحمیل می‌کند)",
    "back": "gatecrasher"
  },
  {
    "id": "3a5ff1dc-98a6-409f-a66d-a37baa36cc0b",
    "front": "**Def**: (of a party or event) start to become interesting and enjoyable.\n**Farsi**: گرم شدن (مهمانی)، هیجان‌انگیز شدن",
    "back": "warm up (phrasal verb)"
  },
  {
    "id": "560ad764-f341-4fc2-942a-e66a2007d215",
    "front": "**Def**: very loud.\n**Farsi**: کر کننده، بسیار بلند",
    "back": "deafening"
  },
  {
    "id": "14a8cfb7-4499-45fc-9e2d-ca8a9f06c815",
    "front": "**Def**: be louder than other sounds, so they can't be heard.\n**Farsi**: صدای چیزی را تحت الشعاع قرار دادن (به دلیل بلند بودن)",
    "back": "drown sth out (phrasal verb)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b880ea8d-767f-4619-9343-b2556bff96ce",
    "front": "**Def**: make something more exciting.\n**Farsi**: هیجان دادن، پرشور کردن",
    "back": "liven sth up (phrasal verb)"
  },
  {
    "id": "0a5cdff0-4b37-4ba9-9bd4-87d73aea7bea",
    "front": "**Def**: become very excited or lose control of your feelings.\n**Farsi**: از خود بیخود شدن، هیجان‌زده شدن بیش از حد",
    "back": "get/be carried away (idiom)"
  },
  {
    "id": "424ed6eb-975f-44b4-878f-ec4870b21bca",
    "front": "**Def**: go somewhere quickly or for a fairly short time.\n**Farsi**: سر زدن، سریع رفتن (برای دیدار کوتاه)",
    "back": "pop round/over/in (phrasal verb, INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "025cee28-b476-4c32-824f-9f79ea30d10e",
    "front": "**Def**: want something or want to do something.\n**Farsi**: هوس چیزی کردن، چیزی را خواستن",
    "back": "fancy sth (v, INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "aa9e91b4-709a-40c0-8aa1-083bddfc84ea",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say you expect something will happen.\n**Farsi**: بدون شک، قطعاً",
    "back": "no doubt (phrase)"
  },
  {
    "id": "337a52a7-e950-4852-b90f-9e0264a30c0d",
    "front": "**Def**: having drunk too much alcohol. get/be drunk.\n**Farsi**: مست، سکران",
    "back": "drunk (adj)"
  },
  {
    "id": "77bccc12-b194-4ae3-a35b-7cc539df3f13",
    "front": "**Def**: not relaxed or comfortable with other people.\n**Farsi**: معذب، دست و پا چلفتی، ناجور",
    "back": "awkward"
  },
  {
    "id": "0aaf3498-9947-42d5-bdae-18a19d7e67ba",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who is often alone and usually prefers to be alone.\n**Farsi**: منزوی، گوشه‌گیر",
    "back": "loner"
  },
  {
    "id": "8069c1e2-0bf8-4b75-bbc8-d9d31e1ca542",
    "front": "**Def**: a friendly informal meeting or party.\n**Farsi**: دورهمی، جلسه دوستانه",
    "back": "get-together (n)"
  },
  {
    "id": "bdcace51-81d6-45ef-9871-083c64b3e745",
    "front": "**Def**: take part in an activity with other people.\n**Farsi**: ملحق شدن، شرکت کردن",
    "back": "join in (phrasal verb)"
  },
  {
    "id": "83b7c09b-cc12-4097-9e7d-e9d60c5fb597",
    "front": "**Def**: a friendly reception that makes you feel relaxed.\n**Farsi**: استقبال گرم",
    "back": "warm welcome"
  },
  {
    "id": "0ffe1336-b065-4aac-ab5c-f632e8bee141",
    "front": "**Def**: including all or almost all the facts or details that may be necessary.\n**Farsi**: فراگیر، جامع (شامل تمام یا تقریباً تمام حقایق و جزئیات لازم)",
    "back": "comprehensive"
  },
  {
    "id": "d3e9e0a3-40ed-4586-aa94-aaa8698fb7f8",
    "front": "**Def**: being with other people, or an enjoyable person (good company).\n**Farsi**: معاشرت، هم‌صحبتی",
    "back": "company (being with people)"
  },
  {
    "id": "7ccea89f-7421-4a39-a7bf-08c2aada6c34",
    "front": "**Def**: go with someone.\n**Farsi**: همراهی کردن",
    "back": "accompany (FML)"
  },
  {
    "id": "33c6362c-99c2-4d00-944d-90c87ae3100d",
    "front": "**Def**: do something to make people feel more relaxed when meeting for the first time.\n**Farsi**: سر صحبت را باز کردن",
    "back": "break the ice (idiom)"
  },
  {
    "id": "3b3e72f9-fa5c-4a57-91f2-eb6e97b9cc58",
    "front": "**Def**: organize a party.\n**Farsi**: مهمانی برگزار کردن",
    "back": "throw a party"
  },
  {
    "id": "df2786f6-cbee-4653-b662-6759d66a98ba",
    "front": "**Def**: a party to celebrate moving into a new home.\n**Farsi**: مهمانی خانه‌تکانی",
    "back": "housewarming party"
  },
  {
    "id": "32407204-a5d0-4393-88eb-c76451d2d320",
    "front": "**Def**: provide food and drink for a social event.\n**Farsi**: غذا و پذیرایی فراهم کردن/ خدمات پذیرایی",
    "back": "cater/catering"
  },
  {
    "id": "c069071b-5b25-447b-8579-e56ac39351a7",
    "front": "**Def**: completely change the appearance or character of sth, often to make it better.\n**Farsi**: متحول کردن، دگرگون کردن",
    "back": "transform sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "bf67a146-c028-4cd2-97b8-16afb95e715f",
    "front": "**Def**: The state or process of being transformed.\n**Farsi**: تحول، دگرگونی",
    "back": "transformation N."
  },
  {
    "id": "5ea6c065-5ff0-400f-99f5-72c1c762c8a2",
    "front": "**Def**: make changes to correct a mistake or improve a law, statement, document, etc.\n**Farsi**: اصلاح کردن، متمم زدن",
    "back": "amend sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "484d7d33-b009-4ecc-a54d-7e89be4cb00d",
    "front": "**Def**: A change or addition designed to correct or improve a text or law.\n**Farsi**: اصلاحیه، متمم",
    "back": "amendment N."
  },
  {
    "id": "e6c61ecf-66cf-48e4-b682-e2ce924c0bb0",
    "front": "**Def**: change your behaviour in order to be more successful in a new situation. SYN adjust (to sth).\n**Farsi**: وفق دادن، سازگار شدن (با)",
    "back": "adapt to sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "d9f05a1c-7d1a-4d4e-b0dd-cbdb60a7238e",
    "front": "**Def**: learn and get used to sth which is new and different.\n**Farsi**: جذب کردن، خو گرفتن",
    "back": "assimilate sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "e45b35b2-7db1-4c11-ba5e-cf6062c236ee",
    "front": "**Def**: The process of becoming assimilated.\n**Farsi**: جذب، همانندسازی",
    "back": "assimilation N."
  },
  {
    "id": "00821356-257e-4408-bfe8-8c14530fab03",
    "front": "**Def**: change gradually, often from something simple to something more complicated.\n**Farsi**: تکامل یافتن، متحول شدن",
    "back": "evolve"
  },
  {
    "id": "042240cb-559b-458f-ba14-ca4db378e034",
    "front": "**Def**: The process of evolving.\n**Farsi**: تکامل، فرگشت",
    "back": "evolution N."
  },
  {
    "id": "f016f7c7-d7b5-4f8b-87a4-2b17764e2a34",
    "front": "**Def**: a process or period of change from one state to another (a society in transition is changing).\n**Farsi**: گذار، دوره انتقال",
    "back": "transition FML"
  },
  {
    "id": "e95a6d53-fbe0-4ceb-8ad2-fa98e660e508",
    "front": "**Def**: change back to a state or situation that existed in the past. SYN go back.\n**Farsi**: بازگشتن (به حالت قبلی)",
    "back": "revert (back) to sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "14440597-f453-4d54-a5c3-f374ca880764",
    "front": "**Def**: return sth to its former state or condition.\n**Farsi**: احیا کردن، بازگرداندن",
    "back": "restore sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "b5b64fcf-4f7e-45ee-9d6b-c8147ca85682",
    "front": "**Def**: The act of restoring.\n**Farsi**: بازسازی، احیا",
    "back": "restoration N."
  },
  {
    "id": "87d949b8-18bd-4206-b761-96d8ecd99a3b",
    "front": "**Def**: The act of reversing.\n**Farsi**: وارونگی، برعکس شدن",
    "back": "reversal N."
  },
  {
    "id": "c64e73b1-572b-4e0f-8026-0ff3a2fdf96f",
    "front": "**Def**: Able to be reversed. OPP irreversible.\n**Farsi**: برگشت پذیر",
    "back": "reversible ADJ."
  },
  {
    "id": "af460691-df5e-446a-9ab0-73305bd5da88",
    "front": "**Def**: improve a system, an organization, a law, etc. by making changes to it.\n**Farsi**: اصلاح کردن، بهبود بخشیدن",
    "back": "reform sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "4c43af66-3582-4af3-a852-f821b9cf4687",
    "front": "**Def**: The act of reforming.\n**Farsi**: اصلاح، دگرسازی",
    "back": "reform N."
  },
  {
    "id": "ddcf90f9-c1a2-4294-afd5-a81f97d328e9",
    "front": "**Def**: refuse to accept sth and try to stop it happening.\n**Farsi**: مقاومت کردن در برابر",
    "back": "resist sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "faa5204a-8eba-4ca7-ab2c-009a72f7e289",
    "front": "**Def**: The refusal to accept or comply with something.\n**Farsi**: مقاومت",
    "back": "resistance N."
  },
  {
    "id": "3199b52c-50e3-40d4-93c8-d88d0f125993",
    "front": "**Def**: make people obey sth (enforce the law).\n**Farsi**: به اجرا درآوردن، تحمیل کردن (قانون)",
    "back": "enforce sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "1b203d69-5327-4d5c-a54f-75429afa08dc",
    "front": "**Def**: The act of enforcing.\n**Farsi**: اجرا، اعمال",
    "back": "enforcement N."
  },
  {
    "id": "aee33e6b-5643-47f4-bb99-b787e3566aba",
    "front": "**Def**: make sb accept sth against their wishes.\n**Farsi**: تحمیل کردن (چیزی بر کسی)",
    "back": "impose sth on/upon sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "3b07b9ae-6c13-49eb-8ebf-80e2de5011c5",
    "front": "**Def**: follow or try to achieve sth over a period of time (pursue a policy/goal).\n**Farsi**: دنبال کردن، پیگیری کردن",
    "back": "pursue sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "3f14f568-d29e-479d-bab2-ad5b3de1f80f",
    "front": "**Def**: FML not taking enough care over sth you are responsible for.\n**Farsi**: بی‌احتیاط، غافل (به اندازه کافی مراقبت نکردن از چیزی که مسئول آن هستید)",
    "back": "negligent"
  },
  {
    "id": "00288040-9e0e-45be-8183-373f8c6b2132",
    "front": "**Def**: a big change that will have an important effect.\n**Farsi**: تغییر گسترده، دگرگونی وسیع",
    "back": "sweeping change"
  },
  {
    "id": "1ded85e8-dcfe-48be-9d7c-9d5e45a7bcd5",
    "front": "**Def**: not easy to notice or understand (subtle difference). OPP obvious.\n**Farsi**: ظریف، نامحسوس",
    "back": "subtle"
  },
  {
    "id": "ad6c866b-9961-4904-a84d-cb47920483ea",
    "front": "**Def**: make an act or process easier to achieve.\n**Farsi**: تسهیل کردن، آسان کردن",
    "back": "facilitate sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "d09f710e-3dd1-4cb0-9008-b9a69007756f",
    "front": "**Def**: continuing to develop (an ongoing process/investigation).\n**Farsi**: مستمر، در حال انجام",
    "back": "ongoing"
  },
  {
    "id": "a19e2234-175f-4e0a-b707-35fd569886c4",
    "front": "**Def**: the act of discussing sth with sb before making a decision.\n**Farsi**: مشاوره، رایزنی",
    "back": "consultation"
  },
  {
    "id": "ad7b3a6b-ae4a-4030-b070-a99d13d5013e",
    "front": "**Def**: Relating to consultation.\n**Farsi**: مشورتی",
    "back": "consultative ADJ."
  },
  {
    "id": "81fd732e-5bf9-4d23-b507-39726bdbf514",
    "front": "**Def**: The process of implementing.\n**Farsi**: اجرا، پیاده سازی",
    "back": "implementation N."
  },
  {
    "id": "9b718d1c-3086-4508-8124-cedc1e45df75",
    "front": "**Def**: A big or fundamental change.\n**Farsi**: تغییر بنیادین/اساسی",
    "back": "radical change"
  },
  {
    "id": "b8477ffc-d21d-433e-a2fb-eadd9c2dd3fd",
    "front": "**Def**: A big and important change.\n**Farsi**: تغییر عمده/بزرگ",
    "back": "major change"
  },
  {
    "id": "0e7dfe2f-3284-4669-a72c-baff64828e65",
    "front": "**Def**: A change involving many people or things.\n**Farsi**: تغییر کلی/عمده",
    "back": "wholesale change"
  },
  {
    "id": "d3192589-92b8-42f5-927a-26c4cf357986",
    "front": "**Def**: a change that is pleasantly new or different.\n**Farsi**: تغییر دلپذیر/تازه",
    "back": "refreshing change"
  },
  {
    "id": "cd786493-e4d9-4f56-958f-66f5fe85aee0",
    "front": "**Def**: a change that is pleasantly new or different.\n**Farsi**: تغییر خوشایند",
    "back": "welcome change"
  },
  {
    "id": "d85ed285-462b-42e7-b619-87c45b3f6ccb",
    "front": "**Def**: avoid wasting sth.\n**Farsi**: حفظ کردن، صرفه‌جویی کردن",
    "back": "conserve sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "98bddc51-47eb-4ed3-9b5e-71d7e9b2f8f2",
    "front": "**Def**: The act of conserving.\n**Farsi**: حفاظت، صرفه‌جویی",
    "back": "conservation N."
  },
  {
    "id": "9e377a94-1459-448a-9344-28464a0216eb",
    "front": "**Def**: change from using one thing to using another.\n**Farsi**: سوییچ کردن به، عوض کردن با",
    "back": "switch to sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "296cfc89-5f6c-4ed0-a5b1-107c56136df0",
    "front": "**Def**: not wasting much energy (water-saving, labour-saving).\n**Farsi**: کم‌مصرف، صرفه‌جویی در انرژی",
    "back": "energy-saving"
  },
  {
    "id": "e9995e47-1f20-4c70-a25b-aea7ab080b82",
    "front": "**Def**: (short for ecology) relating to the environment (eco-home, eco-disaster).\n**Farsi**: زیست‌محیطی، دوستدار محیط زیست",
    "back": "eco(-)"
  },
  {
    "id": "febc5ec9-9062-4bdf-8403-f0793a36e31f",
    "front": "**Def**: send out sth such as light, heat, sounds, gas, etc.\n**Farsi**: منتشر کردن، ساطع کردن",
    "back": "emit sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "22f84cfe-2ee3-423f-9d97-30694829d8d7",
    "front": "**Def**: The act of emitting.\n**Farsi**: انتشار، ساطع شدن",
    "back": "emission N."
  },
  {
    "id": "e0412a42-f9b3-46df-949a-3beddcc6468f",
    "front": "**Def**: the act of using energy, food, or materials.\n**Farsi**: مصرف",
    "back": "consumption"
  },
  {
    "id": "b842987c-423d-4abf-bc6b-24d490505766",
    "front": "**Def**: To use up (energy, food, or materials).\n**Farsi**: مصرف کردن",
    "back": "consume V."
  },
  {
    "id": "6a136eca-0a53-41d1-9eea-aec6e28c7cd5",
    "front": "**Def**: a machine you use at home e.g. fridge, washing machine.\n**Farsi**: لوازم خانگی، دستگاه",
    "back": "appliance"
  },
  {
    "id": "6a7d9d5e-4576-49ba-b079-20a5a311a86f",
    "front": "**Def**: If a TV is on standby, it is connected to the power supply but is not in use.\n**Farsi**: در حالت آماده‌باش (استندبای)",
    "back": "on standby"
  },
  {
    "id": "01503a62-d3df-40a3-8f09-48e61bd9a6e7",
    "front": "**Def**: pass electricity through sth to store it there, using a charger (N).\n**Farsi**: شارژ کردن",
    "back": "charge sth (up)"
  },
  {
    "id": "93678730-75b3-4ce7-9585-d8d0d13baee2",
    "front": "**Def**: A device used to charge batteries.\n**Farsi**: شارژر",
    "back": "charger N."
  },
  {
    "id": "9f367385-7b02-4d9b-9453-6b10aa180ca5",
    "front": "**Def**: a machine that uses hot air to dry clothes.\n**Farsi**: خشک‌کن چرخشی (لباسشویی)",
    "back": "tumble dryer"
  },
  {
    "id": "edce8f51-2897-4987-a5b9-b2ed584db1cc",
    "front": "**Def**: an area of land where large amounts of rubbish are buried.\n**Farsi**: محل دفن زباله",
    "back": "landfill (site)"
  },
  {
    "id": "9db97212-7166-4878-a940-a335e46f692f",
    "front": "**Def**: poisonous (toxic chemicals/gases/substances).\n**Farsi**: سمی، زهرآلود",
    "back": "toxic"
  },
  {
    "id": "6dff17df-ce6c-4bc7-afcf-0d5ad2211fa9",
    "front": "**Def**: even better (still is used to make a comparison stronger).\n**Farsi**: بهتر از آن، حتی بهتر",
    "back": "better still"
  },
  {
    "id": "aa0a5c8f-8d36-48ea-8728-df67e8acf43c",
    "front": "**Def**: batteries that can be recharged.\n**Farsi**: باتری‌های قابل شارژ",
    "back": "rechargeable batteries"
  },
  {
    "id": "9c6e2736-3518-4fcb-a589-7b95bc196047",
    "front": "**Def**: concerned with or supporting the protection of the environment.\n**Farsi**: سبز (طرفدار محیط زیست)",
    "back": "green"
  },
  {
    "id": "04757fd1-fefc-40d2-9904-a1be13905dfa",
    "front": "**Def**: used when saying what you really think about sth. SYNS frankly, personally.\n**Farsi**: صادقانه بگویم، برای بیان نظر واقعی خود در مورد چیزی. (مترادف: frankly, personally)",
    "back": "to be (perfectly) honest"
  },
  {
    "id": "4ce01a7d-fd6a-4e23-baf9-b878afd7c4b0",
    "front": "**Def**: a large, new project. SYN venture.\n**Farsi**: طرح بزرگ، ابتکار",
    "back": "enterprise"
  },
  {
    "id": "9cf6dc5c-79e7-48ca-9e99-74b5fda49535",
    "front": "**Def**: (of fruit and vegetables) ready for eating now and available in large numbers. OPP out of season.\n**Farsi**: فصلی، در فصل",
    "back": "in season"
  },
  {
    "id": "0faada61-94a0-4317-a948-9e85201cb946",
    "front": "**Def**: Not ready for eating or available in large numbers.\n**Farsi**: خارج از فصل",
    "back": "out of season"
  },
  {
    "id": "e887abb8-300a-4bf8-9072-b8783b2efc8d",
    "front": "**Def**: the distance food travels from where it is grown or produced to where it is consumed.\n**Farsi**: مایل غذایی (فاصله حمل غذا)",
    "back": "food miles"
  },
  {
    "id": "a9848142-f87e-47dd-b61f-5954b75f6638",
    "front": "**Def**: To throw away.\n**Farsi**: دور انداختن",
    "back": "dispose of sth V."
  },
  {
    "id": "632750b0-e008-4e11-a68a-8bece2830b14",
    "front": "**Def**: treat sth so that it can be used again.\n**Farsi**: بازیافت کردن",
    "back": "recycle sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "715c3414-aa97-48ce-a272-033858b2ead4",
    "front": "**Def**: The process of treating things so they can be used again.\n**Farsi**: بازیافت",
    "back": "recycling N."
  },
  {
    "id": "576a7604-dd79-420e-86bd-0fb8029da0e6",
    "front": "**Def**: 1. make the best use of sth. 2. increase sth as much as possible. OPP minimize sth.\n**Farsi**: به حداکثر رساندن، بیشینه کردن",
    "back": "maximize sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "8b053125-21a5-46ce-892f-e4a9f5bff4eb",
    "front": "**Def**: reduce sth as much as possible.\n**Farsi**: به حداقل رساندن",
    "back": "minimize sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "13765209-d218-4f6b-8f67-dded63c3bd60",
    "front": "**Def**: using methods which do not harm the environment (sustainable agriculture/energy).\n**Farsi**: پایدار، سازگار با محیط زیست",
    "back": "sustainable"
  },
  {
    "id": "84bb791a-2554-4c61-b7cc-26da270de2c8",
    "front": "**Def**: The ability to be sustained.\n**Farsi**: پایداری",
    "back": "sustainability N."
  },
  {
    "id": "8d54d291-817e-4ce9-9540-d11869c81af1",
    "front": "**Def**: how much CO2 is emitted from your personal energy use (reduce your carbon footprint).\n**Farsi**: رد پای کربن",
    "back": "carbon footprint"
  },
  {
    "id": "5a460a00-8935-49db-8343-690e1b179fca",
    "front": "**Def**: Helping the environment.\n**Farsi**: دوستدار محیط زیست",
    "back": "eco-friendly"
  },
  {
    "id": "faa40040-d3b7-4408-a5b2-02416b91932a",
    "front": "**Def**: Helping the environment.\n**Farsi**: سازگار با محیط زیست",
    "back": "environmentally-friendly"
  },
  {
    "id": "3c5df56f-1b76-419e-8d6d-bf70c3930a5a",
    "front": "**Def**: easy to use or understand.\n**Farsi**: کاربرپسند، استفاده آسان",
    "back": "user-friendly"
  },
  {
    "id": "bdb60b57-b7b2-42d8-9ea0-626e1d957716",
    "front": "**Def**: A large new project or enterprise.\n**Farsi**: سرمایه‌گذاری پرخطر، پروژه",
    "back": "venture"
  },
  {
    "id": "92271ebd-6946-4de1-8393-031edeedb2d1",
    "front": "**Def**: the place where a plant or animal is usually found (natural habitat).\n**Farsi**: زیستگاه، محل سکونت",
    "back": "habitat"
  },
  {
    "id": "e886bfb2-0bc4-473f-9c38-28f723008a93",
    "front": "**Def**: The natural home of an animal or plant.\n**Farsi**: زیستگاه طبیعی",
    "back": "natural habitat"
  },
  {
    "id": "2a63d0a0-3aef-44f9-ba67-6b0f0ebae8d9",
    "front": "**Def**: the act of clearing forests (= removing trees).\n**Farsi**: جنگل‌زدایی، از بین بردن جنگل",
    "back": "deforestation"
  },
  {
    "id": "f273a827-4e72-4ffe-aba2-8a013c7d6a88",
    "front": "**Def**: species in danger because numbers are falling.\n**Farsi**: گونه‌های در معرض خطر",
    "back": "endangered species"
  },
  {
    "id": "c6d91eca-9e74-4d16-bfc2-f93841fdd9ff",
    "front": "**Def**: a group of animals, plants, etc. whose members are similar and can breed with each other.\n**Farsi**: گونه",
    "back": "species"
  },
  {
    "id": "098d4b07-3d0a-4467-9bb8-ad4e0f4a3fd4",
    "front": "**Def**: likely to be harmed or damaged; also threatened with sth.\n**Farsi**: در معرض خطر، تهدید شده",
    "back": "under threat (of sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "d1545e2d-b2bc-4b46-ad3c-c8a94b5d50c2",
    "front": "**Def**: a protected area for plants, animals, etc. (a wildlife/nature reserve).\n**Farsi**: منطقه حفاظت شده، ذخیره‌گاه",
    "back": "reserve"
  },
  {
    "id": "400c3e17-770c-42bb-a6fd-a8357f78d9a3",
    "front": "**Def**: A protected area for animals.\n**Farsi**: ذخیره‌گاه حیات وحش",
    "back": "wildlife reserve"
  },
  {
    "id": "af73930d-7c26-4fd6-9098-b20edddee5f1",
    "front": "**Def**: A protected area for nature.\n**Farsi**: ذخیره‌گاه طبیعی",
    "back": "nature reserve"
  },
  {
    "id": "8cc13b5f-9971-406c-830b-f677c1f69e06",
    "front": "**Def**: in a natural environment not controlled by people.\n**Farsi**: در طبیعت، در حیات وحش",
    "back": "in the wild"
  },
  {
    "id": "b57e88f0-438a-420d-838d-87c4e16c2fbb",
    "front": "**Def**: kept in a zoo or park, etc.\n**Farsi**: در اسارت",
    "back": "in captivity"
  },
  {
    "id": "86ab7f08-6e57-43e7-82b2-a51ed001f41b",
    "front": "**Def**: continuously decreasing in number, quantity, etc. (gradual/steady decline).\n**Farsi**: در حال کاهش، رو به زوال",
    "back": "in decline"
  },
  {
    "id": "9708545b-619d-46ae-9ea7-ec467ae847b7",
    "front": "**Def**: A slow decrease.\n**Farsi**: کاهش تدریجی",
    "back": "gradual decline"
  },
  {
    "id": "12ef8e8f-4816-4d36-b3a6-a1a3a00b0683",
    "front": "**Def**: A consistent decrease.\n**Farsi**: کاهش مداوم",
    "back": "steady decline"
  },
  {
    "id": "c851818a-d572-4438-be31-ce22fb3cd9b3",
    "front": "**Def**: exactly and completely (also used to emphasize that sth must happen in all circumstances: Smoking in the lift is strictly prohibited.).\n**Farsi**: دقیقاً و کاملاً (همچنین برای تأکید بر لزوم وقوع چیزی در همه شرایط: اکیداً ممنوع).",
    "back": "strictly"
  },
  {
    "id": "d033f28d-3fd6-4345-aba7-43040a60bce9",
    "front": "**Def**: destroy or get rid of sth completely.\n**Farsi**: از بین بردن، نابود کردن",
    "back": "wipe sb/sth out"
  },
  {
    "id": "fa850540-1372-43a6-96ea-c8fd4b0ec116",
    "front": "**Def**: become less common and eventually disappear.\n**Farsi**: منقرض شدن",
    "back": "die out"
  },
  {
    "id": "2a2c0ed2-8a96-4ecf-b98c-9d58c9f33c99",
    "front": "**Def**: If a plant or animal is extinct, it no longer exists.\n**Farsi**: منقرض",
    "back": "extinct ADJ."
  },
  {
    "id": "baf8d11b-565d-407c-b519-2336ddb66fda",
    "front": "**Def**: The state of being extinct.\n**Farsi**: انقراض",
    "back": "extinction N."
  },
  {
    "id": "bbfe038d-c4b5-4a57-8b42-3fc9056d5e5d",
    "front": "**Def**: very close to extinction.\n**Farsi**: در آستانه انقراض",
    "back": "on the verge of extinction"
  },
  {
    "id": "5aa31669-7d2d-48d2-bd74-43e1d18620b3",
    "front": "**Def**: the illegal hunting of animals, birds, etc.\n**Farsi**: شکار غیرقانونی",
    "back": "poaching"
  },
  {
    "id": "dd685516-2ee0-4f67-80eb-61ab7ce82d57",
    "front": "**Def**: The person who hunts illegally.\n**Farsi**: شکارچی غیرقانونی",
    "back": "poacher N."
  },
  {
    "id": "dd631563-f198-4484-a47d-16626d9bed2a",
    "front": "**Def**: create a threat (also pose a risk/danger to sb/sth).\n**Farsi**: تهدیدی ایجاد کردن برای",
    "back": "pose a threat to sb/sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "e0933ccd-95af-4738-881c-bc0085ae8fed",
    "front": "**Def**: wanted by many people but not easy to get.\n**Farsi**: پرطرفدار، کمیاب",
    "back": "sought after"
  },
  {
    "id": "8ce710c1-491b-428a-8b45-4f4f084238d4",
    "front": "**Def**: use sth for a purpose that is different from its original purpose.\n**Farsi**: منحرف کردن، تغییر مسیر دادن",
    "back": "divert sth (from sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "868e4554-6318-458a-a95d-ef683731f61a",
    "front": "**Def**: money available to be spent (raise funds = collect money).\n**Farsi**: بودجه، وجوه",
    "back": "funds PL"
  },
  {
    "id": "0c1a12d7-260b-4d9e-90ee-3391122f8a4d",
    "front": "**Def**: To collect money.\n**Farsi**: جمع آوری پول/کمک مالی",
    "back": "raise funds"
  },
  {
    "id": "6a342bde-80a7-465f-9794-a1344f5aa744",
    "front": "**Def**: the state of being poor.\n**Farsi**: فقر، نداری",
    "back": "poverty"
  },
  {
    "id": "f19b171e-1e93-4529-a17d-c7e8f3dc53f7",
    "front": "**Def**: SYN probability.\n**Farsi**: احتمال",
    "back": "likelihood"
  },
  {
    "id": "7c4e881d-85d4-4968-846f-1aab6bfae6e1",
    "front": "**Def**: The extent to which something is likely to happen.\n**Farsi**: احتمال",
    "back": "probability SYN"
  },
  {
    "id": "d2fceec4-76e0-4441-aada-3c8dcf091338",
    "front": "**Def**: have a bad effect on sth.\n**Farsi**: خسارت سنگینی وارد کردن، صدمه زدن",
    "back": "take a heavy toll on sth/sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "dd99d920-4695-4c6a-80d1-9f93ec0d1c6d",
    "front": "**Def**: gradually cover more and more of an area.\n**Farsi**: تجاوز کردن به، دست‌اندازی کردن",
    "back": "encroach on/upon sth FML"
  },
  {
    "id": "5b15e0c3-4361-4585-a4e7-0328ef6ff19a",
    "front": "**Def**: an area an animal regards as its own and defends against others.\n**Farsi**: قلمرو، محدوده",
    "back": "territory"
  },
  {
    "id": "52b22723-af06-4f5e-9529-801d5bf426d9",
    "front": "**Def**: Relating to territory.\n**Farsi**: قلمرویی",
    "back": "territorial ADJ."
  },
  {
    "id": "090efbe0-8965-4d75-9047-2dfe64795434",
    "front": "**Def**: a unit of information inside a cell which controls what the living thing will be like.\n**Farsi**: ژن",
    "back": "gene"
  },
  {
    "id": "bd198fdb-5fbb-4715-a45d-ac4ba332eb53",
    "front": "**Def**: the total of all the genes in a species.\n**Farsi**: خزانه ژنی",
    "back": "gene pool"
  },
  {
    "id": "f47a4530-d487-47c7-8329-543765fd1711",
    "front": "**Def**: a period of time that has a particular quality or character.\n**Farsi**: عصر، دوره",
    "back": "era"
  },
  {
    "id": "8826ed84-a352-42fb-9e55-7af355fcb55f",
    "front": "**Def**: progress made in science, medicine, technology, etc.\n**Farsi**: پیشرفت، ترقی",
    "back": "advance(s) (in sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "89650f6f-2a05-44a2-bc77-1dc1378ef9f8",
    "front": "**Def**: a period of ten years.\n**Farsi**: دهه",
    "back": "decade"
  },
  {
    "id": "939bb6ec-58be-4471-9160-704cb5e72621",
    "front": "**Def**: usual or traditional; not new or different.\n**Farsi**: مرسوم، سنتی",
    "back": "conventional"
  },
  {
    "id": "6b7ac60a-780a-4fa9-a2fb-e4dc9660ca0c",
    "front": "**Def**: A way in which something is usually done.\n**Farsi**: عرف، سنت",
    "back": "convention N."
  },
  {
    "id": "df5a58f1-91f3-4004-8886-b7632d32c5b4",
    "front": "**Def**: used for finding out what physical or mental problem sb has.\n**Farsi**: تشخیصی",
    "back": "diagnostic"
  },
  {
    "id": "b5e1c952-1366-4968-b331-c3e7482b2bd3",
    "front": "**Def**: To identify the nature of an illness.\n**Farsi**: تشخیص دادن",
    "back": "diagnose V."
  },
  {
    "id": "0bc41b81-f59b-484a-8047-e7d966ca78f6",
    "front": "**Def**: The identification of the nature of an illness.\n**Farsi**: تشخیص (بیماری)",
    "back": "diagnosis N."
  },
  {
    "id": "eafc7ff0-4e1b-477a-9832-f726b9786f10",
    "front": "**Def**: A limiting condition or measure.\n**Farsi**: محدودیت",
    "back": "restriction N."
  },
  {
    "id": "b07e9ffe-2e4b-4abd-b9bf-9aef118da39d",
    "front": "**Def**: likely to suffer from sth (also accident-prone).\n**Farsi**: مستعد، متمایل (به چیزی)",
    "back": "prone to sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "935e2742-cd13-48f0-92d0-8b863cd19dcc",
    "front": "**Def**: a medical treatment that makes a sick person well again.\n**Farsi**: درمان، معالجه",
    "back": "cure"
  },
  {
    "id": "8bbd2646-54c3-45d8-9cfe-a9997b501995",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the action of replacing someone or something with another.\n**Farsi**: جایگزینی",
    "back": "substitution"
  },
  {
    "id": "aa5879c4-4ac6-4a66-b16e-9217df541e43",
    "front": "**Def**: The process of giving a vaccine.\n**Farsi**: واکسیناسیون",
    "back": "vaccination N."
  },
  {
    "id": "827b86ee-c05d-4caa-8b14-0cdbe8fd2f36",
    "front": "**Def**: To administer a vaccine.\n**Farsi**: واکسن زدن",
    "back": "vaccinate V."
  },
  {
    "id": "6ae8b247-344d-4937-82ce-47e4e813fc9b",
    "front": "**Def**: a long-term illness or medical problem.\n**Farsi**: بیماری، عارضه",
    "back": "condition"
  },
  {
    "id": "0a26d142-39ab-4e67-92da-574b5dae3c71",
    "front": "**Def**: have to stay in bed / a wheelchair.\n**Farsi**: محدود به بستر/صندلی چرخدار شدن",
    "back": "be confined to bed / a wheelchair"
  },
  {
    "id": "650bb03a-b554-492b-8a16-434d86e9eec1",
    "front": "**Def**: (of medical treatment) involving cutting of the body.\n**Farsi**: تهاجمی",
    "back": "invasive"
  },
  {
    "id": "3d8be4f4-e010-4b02-8533-67c444d0bb38",
    "front": "**Def**: The action of invading.\n**Farsi**: تهاجم",
    "back": "invasion N."
  },
  {
    "id": "e3b9e9e4-6638-460c-9f73-6e7f3533ea21",
    "front": "**Def**: To enter in order to seize or subjugate.\n**Farsi**: حمله کردن",
    "back": "invade V."
  },
  {
    "id": "243475d2-c6f0-4a77-962b-da128f050152",
    "front": "**Def**: a medical operation or investigation (carry out / perform a procedure).\n**Farsi**: عمل جراحی، روش درمانی",
    "back": "procedure"
  },
  {
    "id": "2b3a8a36-0067-432f-baaf-cf4a5573fdc8",
    "front": "**Def**: a part of the body that has a particular purpose, such as the heart or brain.\n**Farsi**: عضو",
    "back": "organ"
  },
  {
    "id": "ccfd0fdf-342f-4f35-bbab-8e5800cd1de5",
    "front": "**Def**: an operation in which a damaged organ is replaced with one from a donor.\n**Farsi**: پیوند (عضو)",
    "back": "transplant"
  },
  {
    "id": "b88d06fb-2659-4c59-abe4-e4d68d2ac152",
    "front": "**Def**: To perform a transplant.\n**Farsi**: پیوند زدن",
    "back": "transplant V."
  },
  {
    "id": "d70fceb7-ca2b-4d03-ad95-7074015f3a00",
    "front": "**Def**: someone who gives part of their body, blood, etc.\n**Farsi**: اهدا کننده",
    "back": "donor"
  },
  {
    "id": "dd7a1d2d-0921-4102-81e9-91bc3fbc4ad1",
    "front": "**Def**: begin sth again after an interruption.\n**Farsi**: از سر گرفتن، ادامه دادن",
    "back": "resume sth FML"
  },
  {
    "id": "7745f0a1-93c1-44ef-961c-df087f394e8b",
    "front": "**Def**: The action of resuming.\n**Farsi**: از سرگیری",
    "back": "resumption N."
  },
  {
    "id": "6b0ff157-e12a-40b8-b443-367e28883b31",
    "front": "**Def**: the treatment of diseases, especially cancer, by drugs.\n**Farsi**: شیمی درمانی",
    "back": "chemotherapy"
  },
  {
    "id": "c9aff44c-75cf-47bd-b625-6233135fa135",
    "front": "**Def**: A measurement of the number of times something happens within a period.\n**Farsi**: نرخ، میزان",
    "back": "rate"
  },
  {
    "id": "a7651aed-f790-4911-b0b4-8b855e4abe9b",
    "front": "**Def**: the number of people dying.\n**Farsi**: نرخ مرگ و میر",
    "back": "mortality rate / death rate"
  },
  {
    "id": "38698859-1fff-486a-a8e6-59ab7351fb69",
    "front": "**Def**: the number of people continuing to live despite a serious illness.\n**Farsi**: نرخ بقا",
    "back": "survival rate"
  },
  {
    "id": "9ef198cb-3884-40ce-8a4f-8d7327a7fc23",
    "front": "**Def**: the number of babies born.\n**Farsi**: نرخ زاد و ولد",
    "back": "birth rate"
  },
  {
    "id": "6a5ce514-bd4f-470f-8dbe-d68a761d82ca",
    "front": "**Def**: to rise sharply.\n**Farsi**: به سرعت بالا رفتن",
    "back": "rocket V"
  },
  {
    "id": "39cfd7f5-5626-477e-b6c9-049f5f0af8be",
    "front": "**Def**: to fall sharply.\n**Farsi**: به سرعت سقوط کردن",
    "back": "plummet V"
  },
  {
    "id": "c2bde70d-3670-4aad-9493-9f7154099dc5",
    "front": "**Def**: Special words and phrases used by people who do the same kind of work. (OFTEN DISAPPROVING)\n**Farsi**: اصطلاحات تخصصی، ژارگون",
    "back": "jargon"
  },
  {
    "id": "5c93f4d4-43eb-464f-b7a5-462366aee929",
    "front": "**Def**: the secret numbers or letters you have to put into a computer in order to use it.\n**Farsi**: رمز عبور",
    "back": "password"
  },
  {
    "id": "eab0463c-c988-4880-8769-1abb2df3df64",
    "front": "**Def**: the name you use to operate a computer or program.\n**Farsi**: نام کاربری",
    "back": "username"
  },
  {
    "id": "aa18a2ba-25c0-4e30-acbe-6729344e9063",
    "front": "**Def**: perform the actions that let you start to use a computer system.\n**Farsi**: وارد شدن به سیستم (لاگین کردن)",
    "back": "log on/in"
  },
  {
    "id": "db508664-69c2-491c-9164-14ea48e9d17a",
    "front": "**Def**: Perform the actions that let you stop using a computer system.\n**Farsi**: خارج شدن از سیستم (لاگ اوت کردن)",
    "back": "log off/out OPP"
  },
  {
    "id": "7d49218a-a585-4c64-ba1e-306eb147eaf0",
    "front": "**Def**: move text on a screen up or down so that you can read different parts.\n**Farsi**: بالا و پایین کردن (صفحه)، پیمایش کردن",
    "back": "scroll (up/down)"
  },
  {
    "id": "fe0180d4-0b45-4b3c-b54f-ab848c204199",
    "front": "**Def**: type words into a search engine to find information about sb/sth.\n**Farsi**: جستجو کردن در گوگل",
    "back": "google sb/sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "51d977ed-e98f-4971-a274-dae13cc7ab70",
    "front": "**Def**: type words into a search engine to find information about sb/sth.\n**Farsi**: جستجو در وب انجام دادن",
    "back": "do a search (on sth/sb) SYN"
  },
  {
    "id": "cf9cb527-ddf6-428e-8251-6f1f2c74e180",
    "front": "**Def**: a connection between one file or document and another on the web.\n**Farsi**: پیوند، لینک",
    "back": "link"
  },
  {
    "id": "2f2b823a-a0da-4890-a585-8dff62229636",
    "front": "**Def**: in the process of being built.\n**Farsi**: در حال ساخت",
    "back": "under construction"
  },
  {
    "id": "e8673f8f-82ac-4680-ba50-36b2575fe6b1",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning prove or show (something) to be true or genuine.\n**Farsi**: اصالت چیزی را تأیید کردن",
    "back": "authenticate"
  },
  {
    "id": "eb8e5a2b-5340-48ae-8eaf-16e2321ee77e",
    "front": "**Def**: The act of sending spam.\n**Farsi**: ارسال هرزنامه",
    "back": "spamming"
  },
  {
    "id": "44903c5f-7267-4851-a792-c09409cef0cd",
    "front": "**Def**: a program that enters your computer and destroys or damages your data.\n**Farsi**: ویروس",
    "back": "virus N."
  },
  {
    "id": "0b897704-1d04-456f-b2b4-8d28315ede59",
    "front": "**Def**: a web-based company.\n**Farsi**: کسب و کار الکترونیک",
    "back": "e-business"
  },
  {
    "id": "d7cef224-5ad9-482a-9df1-a1cef4225dff",
    "front": "**Def**: learning that takes place on computers or the internet.\n**Farsi**: یادگیری الکترونیک",
    "back": "e-learning"
  },
  {
    "id": "af20dc94-1dcc-48da-a790-4f1de0efa6f6",
    "front": "**Def**: a café where people pay to use the internet.\n**Farsi**: کافه سایبری، کافی‌نت",
    "back": "cyber-café SYN internet café"
  },
  {
    "id": "3b6ed0c1-5900-4dfc-9fc7-119daf770a22",
    "front": "**Def**: the imaginary place where emails exist when being sent between computers.\n**Farsi**: فضای مجازی، سایبرفضا",
    "back": "cyberspace"
  },
  {
    "id": "6ec4f221-d267-4242-b7ec-3df33afc12cc",
    "front": "**Def**: Extremely great or successful.\n**Farsi**: خارق‌العاده، پدیده‌ای",
    "back": "phenomenal ADJ."
  },
  {
    "id": "505f375f-129b-4932-b61f-6f57fe9dfa5d",
    "front": "**Def**: have an idea, especially an unusual one. SYN think sth up.\n**Farsi**: فکری به سرش زدن، طرحی ریختن",
    "back": "dream sth up INF"
  },
  {
    "id": "e4f1096e-9b0a-4774-b029-42bb228f24df",
    "front": "**Def**: (in computing) the way data is organized in a computer file or program.\n**Farsi**: قالب، فرمت",
    "back": "format"
  },
  {
    "id": "71a234dc-775f-4397-8a03-043ea39652f5",
    "front": "**Def**: a program that lets you look at files on the internet.\n**Farsi**: مرورگر (وب)",
    "back": "(web) browser"
  },
  {
    "id": "ee31a7c7-ba04-400b-8859-5a42ee4cd48e",
    "front": "**Def**: (in computing) created by computers or appearing on computers or the internet (a virtual community, a virtual office, virtual reality).\n**Farsi**: مجازی",
    "back": "virtual"
  },
  {
    "id": "a1682f57-9851-4e77-bebd-cdfbea999ea9",
    "front": "**Def**: a person whose username and password are recorded on a website, so they can enter it.\n**Farsi**: کاربر ثبت‌نام شده",
    "back": "registered user"
  },
  {
    "id": "fe108836-e3ee-4a6c-b8da-6004688698e2",
    "front": "**Def**: send a file, video, etc. from your computer to a larger system using the internet. OPP download sth.\n**Farsi**: بارگذاری کردن، آپلود کردن",
    "back": "upload sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "82ae5ce0-79be-42d6-9a6e-ebb5ebaeb32a",
    "front": "**Def**: To transfer a file from the internet to your computer.\n**Farsi**: دانلود کردن، بارگیری کردن",
    "back": "download sth OPP"
  },
  {
    "id": "6760446b-885d-401b-bcc8-a80396e74446",
    "front": "**Def**: a personal video made by sb on sth they are interested in.\n**Farsi**: ویدئوبلاگ",
    "back": "videoblog"
  },
  {
    "id": "e70b7e12-5f6e-470e-ba63-d7a4f7636781",
    "front": "**Def**: a short part of a video or film.\n**Farsi**: کلیپ (ویدئویی)، قطعه فیلم",
    "back": "(video) clip"
  },
  {
    "id": "d2827d29-adbd-4695-a7a0-b82bc5f5b72b",
    "front": "**Def**: say how good you think sth is, e.g. good, acceptable, or bad.\n**Farsi**: امتیاز دادن، رتبه‌بندی کردن",
    "back": "rate sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "40ab88a5-4bd8-4ead-a2af-805bf3fe4df0",
    "front": "**Def**: happen at the same time as sth else.\n**Farsi**: همزمان شدن با، منطبق بودن با",
    "back": "coincide with sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "abc2daf2-94b6-4467-9902-1eec38d83429",
    "front": "**Def**: The occurrence of events at the same time by chance.\n**Farsi**: تصادف، همزمانی",
    "back": "coincidence N."
  },
  {
    "id": "9fedcea2-f487-4f78-a299-c710bb9b3850",
    "front": "**Def**: a video camera that can be carried around.\n**Farsi**: دوربین فیلمبرداری دستی",
    "back": "camcorder"
  },
  {
    "id": "0598a1b7-a767-47e8-8522-a4e4716816d0",
    "front": "**Def**: together or at the same time as sth/sb.\n**Farsi**: در کنار، همراه با",
    "back": "alongside sth/sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "34a9fd63-074b-4c1b-a838-74c03bd8d79a",
    "front": "**Def**: the programs used to operate a computer (install/run a piece of software).\n**Farsi**: نرم‌افزار",
    "back": "software"
  },
  {
    "id": "d00f77f2-6ec9-49d5-bb54-dcad2ba09ece",
    "front": "**Def**: escape from a dangerous situation, place, or person very quickly.\n**Farsi**: فرار کردن، گریختن",
    "back": "flee (from) sth/sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "1553310d-f556-42f6-aaf2-b38fdfb3a14b",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who is forced to leave their country for political/religious reasons.\n**Farsi**: پناهنده",
    "back": "refugee"
  },
  {
    "id": "bebab085-5684-4714-9f1f-fc8ab4076e1e",
    "front": "**Def**: find shelter or protection from trouble or danger.\n**Farsi**: پناه بردن، پناه گرفتن",
    "back": "seek/take refuge (from sth/sb)"
  },
  {
    "id": "0b04d0bf-291d-405c-9c1b-f9c1f6d49fd2",
    "front": "**Def**: the protection a country gives to a refugee (seek asylum, apply for asylum).\n**Farsi**: پناهندگی (سیاسی)",
    "back": "(political) asylum"
  },
  {
    "id": "c43686bc-5b44-4b87-9dd6-113f374f1743",
    "front": "**Def**: To apply for protection as a refugee.\n**Farsi**: درخواست پناهندگی دادن",
    "back": "seek asylum"
  },
  {
    "id": "40757e99-6a37-4f51-9f4d-bdc3f184265b",
    "front": "**Def**: a group of people with the same culture or race living in a place where most people are of a different culture/race.\n**Farsi**: اقلیت قومی",
    "back": "ethnic minority"
  },
  {
    "id": "e26edc20-d76f-4f7e-a60b-bbd74c3e0829",
    "front": "**Def**: A group sharing a common culture or race.\n**Farsi**: گروه قومی",
    "back": "ethnic group"
  },
  {
    "id": "40bc8add-2b7f-4263-9984-0f7b10f313eb",
    "front": "**Def**: live without quarrelling with others.\n**Farsi**: در صلح زندگی کردن با",
    "back": "live at peace with sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "e8fd2657-7ab6-408d-b0b3-3a126a123151",
    "front": "**Def**: a feeling of sadness mixed with pleasure when you think of happy times in the past.\n**Farsi**: دلتنگی، غم غربت",
    "back": "nostalgia"
  },
  {
    "id": "a5d30e8d-8f9e-4f3b-960b-0421ee22f192",
    "front": "**Def**: Pertaining to nostalgia.\n**Farsi**: نوستالژیک، حسرت‌بار",
    "back": "nostalgic ADJ"
  },
  {
    "id": "62be002c-9291-48c2-a74f-f14f306db363",
    "front": "**Def**: a strong wish (have no desire to do sth).\n**Farsi**: میل، اشتیاق",
    "back": "desire"
  },
  {
    "id": "e8d6ec19-a218-4691-a2b0-a2e57c69c3e0",
    "front": "**Def**: you become familiar with it and accept it as normal. SYN get used to.\n**Farsi**: عادت کردن به، خو گرفتن با",
    "back": "get accustomed to (doing) sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "f466b652-1b4f-44ca-972c-8dac853732de",
    "front": "**Def**: you become familiar with it and accept it as normal. SYN get accustomed to.\n**Farsi**: عادت کردن به",
    "back": "get used to (doing) sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "9432286e-d18a-47ad-9e6d-fcb5380654b9",
    "front": "**Def**: you become familiar with a new climate or situation.\n**Farsi**: سازگار شدن با (آب و هوا)",
    "back": "get acclimatized (to sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "cc0940c0-ac9a-4d54-9850-d61fda622b55",
    "front": "**Def**: you learn how to do, use, or understand something.\n**Farsi**: قلق چیزی دست کسی آمدن",
    "back": "get the hang of sth INF"
  },
  {
    "id": "f1e0c257-ee38-44a8-80ba-4fee7667f555",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning a state of extreme physical or mental fatigue.\n**Farsi**: خستگی مفرط",
    "back": "exhaustion"
  },
  {
    "id": "de576b34-76cb-49c6-bcf2-6f75be07d6ef",
    "front": "**Def**: the practice of treating a person or group in society less fairly than others.\n**Farsi**: تبعیض",
    "back": "discrimination"
  },
  {
    "id": "a5f10344-e55c-4ccc-af9b-1e80b0151da2",
    "front": "**Def**: To treat a person or group unfairly.\n**Farsi**: تبعیض قائل شدن",
    "back": "discriminate V"
  },
  {
    "id": "e1c690a7-9127-40ff-9499-9bd474d12bd0",
    "front": "**Def**: force sb to leave a country, often because they have no right to be there.\n**Farsi**: اخراج کردن (از کشور)",
    "back": "deport sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "d7f823a4-c6dc-445d-a42d-0d2ea08a2f41",
    "front": "**Def**: The act of deporting.\n**Farsi**: اخراج (از کشور)",
    "back": "deportation N"
  },
  {
    "id": "f8823aff-2084-42ab-9d7f-ae0f66473181",
    "front": "**Def**: an opinion about sb/sth that is not based on reason or experience, especially a dislike based on race, religion, etc.\n**Farsi**: پیش‌داوری، تعصب",
    "back": "prejudice (against sb/sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "5ff85cca-7a0e-4415-9553-c427a81e032c",
    "front": "**Def**: Having or showing prejudice.\n**Farsi**: متعصب",
    "back": "prejudiced ADJ"
  },
  {
    "id": "8462ccf9-8373-425d-a780-fda2f63d66d6",
    "front": "**Def**: The movement of people or animals from one place to another.\n**Farsi**: مهاجرت",
    "back": "migration N"
  },
  {
    "id": "2cb3f3c3-f142-4e53-b7fd-eb11dc01ff95",
    "front": "**Def**: the process of coming to live in a country that is not your own.\n**Farsi**: مهاجرت (به داخل کشور)",
    "back": "immigration N"
  },
  {
    "id": "7755eb74-fba4-4b88-9594-8f1f03b49165",
    "front": "**Def**: A person who comes to live permanently in a foreign country.\n**Farsi**: مهاجر (وارد شونده)",
    "back": "immigrant N"
  },
  {
    "id": "30ddce73-471d-4079-ba1b-0ca4da11bcc4",
    "front": "**Def**: The process of going to live in another country.\n**Farsi**: مهاجرت (به خارج کشور)",
    "back": "emigration N"
  },
  {
    "id": "27e88126-98b9-4473-a8ab-1602adfdb6dd",
    "front": "**Def**: To leave one's own country in order to settle permanently in another.\n**Farsi**: مهاجرت کردن (به خارج)",
    "back": "emigrate V"
  },
  {
    "id": "b39b098d-6170-4d3b-8cad-a54a9266c689",
    "front": "**Def**: A person who leaves their own country in order to settle in another.\n**Farsi**: مهاجر (خارج شونده)",
    "back": "emigrant N"
  },
  {
    "id": "73ebefa2-f011-4844-9beb-552b47ae61b2",
    "front": "**Def**: People who move abroad to find a better job.\n**Farsi**: مهاجران اقتصادی",
    "back": "economic migrants"
  },
  {
    "id": "01604f91-00fa-4a57-af60-a83b16bddf6e",
    "front": "**Def**: connected with the place where you were born and lived for the first years of your life (native country/land/city).\n**Farsi**: بومی، وطنی، اهل",
    "back": "native ADJ/N"
  },
  {
    "id": "84c86c50-d6d0-4178-b5ef-df4bfb6ebc9a",
    "front": "**Def**: a feeling of confusion and anxiety often felt by people staying in another country.\n**Farsi**: شوک فرهنگی",
    "back": "culture shock"
  },
  {
    "id": "6ce01ad1-14e1-4e06-9be0-f064c1bbb99b",
    "front": "**Def**: a feeling of anger or hatred. SYN hostility.\n**Farsi**: دشمنی، کینه",
    "back": "animosity (towards sb)"
  },
  {
    "id": "397a60a0-b17c-4ceb-a74e-8cc9ca2abe92",
    "front": "**Def**: Hostility or antagonism.\n**Farsi**: خصومت",
    "back": "hostility N SYN"
  },
  {
    "id": "45584433-d2cc-4490-a420-6cbe734f8945",
    "front": "**Def**: a strong belief in sth (this is often a religious faith).\n**Farsi**: اعتقاد، ایمان، مذهب",
    "back": "faith"
  },
  {
    "id": "33bcbf9f-4b9f-4651-9c78-b1f257bc6058",
    "front": "**Def**: a fixed idea of what a particular type of person or thing is like, but which is often not true in reality.\n**Farsi**: کلیشه، انگاره قالبی",
    "back": "stereotype"
  },
  {
    "id": "7a223825-60f0-4dc2-a5c7-ab86c8114315",
    "front": "**Def**: Relating to a stereotype.\n**Farsi**: کلیشه‌ای",
    "back": "stereotypical ADJ"
  },
  {
    "id": "098c51e2-6164-4899-a69e-daabad3715d6",
    "front": "**Def**: the process of becoming a full member of a group or society.\n**Farsi**: ادغام، یکپارچگی",
    "back": "integration"
  },
  {
    "id": "1376ed64-c82f-4e6a-81dc-dd3880539a47",
    "front": "**Def**: To become a full member of a group.\n**Farsi**: ادغام شدن",
    "back": "integrate (into sth) V"
  },
  {
    "id": "ccc9d33f-be9a-4a7e-88c1-6cb90febff80",
    "front": "**Def**: register to join a course, school, etc.\n**Farsi**: ثبت نام کردن",
    "back": "enrol SYN"
  },
  {
    "id": "7d68bce4-667a-4f35-aeab-a8b63284bca8",
    "front": "**Def**: the act of sending sb to get professional help (be referred to sb).\n**Farsi**: ارجاع (به متخصص)",
    "back": "referral"
  },
  {
    "id": "072f14ae-1910-4bf1-ba1a-2ca2b0294144",
    "front": "**Def**: advice from another person (i.e. not the original doctor).\n**Farsi**: نظر دوم، مشورت با پزشک دیگر",
    "back": "second opinion"
  },
  {
    "id": "07452a58-4d49-44a0-a4d5-882cabe6e3f7",
    "front": "**Def**: meant to be kept secret (strictly confidential).\n**Farsi**: محرمانه",
    "back": "confidential"
  },
  {
    "id": "2cbed870-f9e0-4dbc-9814-86a9e8a681c3",
    "front": "**Def**: Highly secret.\n**Farsi**: کاملاً محرمانه",
    "back": "strictly confidential"
  },
  {
    "id": "d9ba7260-41f0-46f4-8f13-58648eab0630",
    "front": "**Def**: The state of keeping things secret (protect patient/client confidentiality).\n**Farsi**: محرمانه بودن",
    "back": "confidentiality N"
  },
  {
    "id": "1720beac-c5b0-44e6-9a1b-f527e956d5d5",
    "front": "**Def**: failure to give proper care or attention.\n**Farsi**: غفلت، سهل‌انگاری (پزشکی)",
    "back": "negligence FML"
  },
  {
    "id": "e01ac15d-fa2c-4338-9108-8332a001694a",
    "front": "**Def**: Failing to take proper care.\n**Farsi**: سهل‌انگار",
    "back": "negligent ADJ"
  },
  {
    "id": "5f26b01b-1c7a-4e5f-aeb9-5e66a81e50fa",
    "front": "**Def**: reach, enter, or use sth (gain/have access to sth).\n**Farsi**: دسترسی پیدا کردن به",
    "back": "access sth FML"
  },
  {
    "id": "06458ea6-d63a-4b03-9968-38a7a3baf930",
    "front": "**Def**: when a surgery, office, etc. is closed.\n**Farsi**: خارج از ساعات کاری (اورژانسی)",
    "back": "out of hours"
  },
  {
    "id": "5fe3620c-7f4b-4169-b624-f7e50fb5826c",
    "front": "**Def**: medical treatment intended to improve sb's appearance (surgical repair after accidents, burns, etc. is called plastic surgery).\n**Farsi**: جراحی زیبایی",
    "back": "cosmetic surgery"
  },
  {
    "id": "076c402c-0d3c-432a-bc5a-49a8d6858603",
    "front": "**Def**: Surgical repair after accidents, burns, etc.\n**Farsi**: جراحی پلاستیک",
    "back": "plastic surgery"
  },
  {
    "id": "40cfa044-837c-4452-a4d6-b0c6dd9479cf",
    "front": "**Def**: If sth is free of charge it costs you nothing.\n**Farsi**: رایگان، بدون هزینه",
    "back": "free of charge"
  },
  {
    "id": "86b9d79a-0b1e-4850-8c7b-eae3f627cadf",
    "front": "**Def**: find or obtain sth (get hold of sb = find or contact sb).\n**Farsi**: به دست آوردن، پیدا کردن",
    "back": "get hold of sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "3a490dcb-ffcd-4621-8f40-f13eaeaa8d29",
    "front": "**Def**: a piece or period of research on the effectiveness or safety of drugs or treatment.\n**Farsi**: کارآزمایی بالینی، آزمایش بالینی",
    "back": "clinical trial"
  },
  {
    "id": "c0f3d63d-1d25-4103-ac10-bd185d4b66ea",
    "front": "**Def**: treatments that are not part of traditional Western medicine, e.g. acupuncture.\n**Farsi**: طب مکمل",
    "back": "complementary medicine"
  },
  {
    "id": "a809adc5-0601-408b-b689-d53d96cbba61",
    "front": "**Def**: make sb feel relaxed and not nervous.\n**Farsi**: راحت کردن (کسی را)",
    "back": "put sb at (their) ease"
  },
  {
    "id": "11b3af38-0210-4627-b013-66b5c3009031",
    "front": "**Def**: continue to give sb information about sth.\n**Farsi**: مطلع نگه داشتن (کسی را)",
    "back": "keep sb informed"
  },
  {
    "id": "47eaa1cd-ea63-4916-9424-9fdafc537e98",
    "front": "**Def**: perfectly clean (also spotlessly clean). SYN immaculate.\n**Farsi**: بی‌نقص تمیز، لکه‌دار",
    "back": "spotless"
  },
  {
    "id": "a2732722-9f1f-45ef-8f8d-97b3eb64647d",
    "front": "**Def**: Perfectly clean.\n**Farsi**: بی‌عیب و نقص، پاکیزه",
    "back": "immaculate SYN"
  },
  {
    "id": "927f8116-f297-4dca-be24-5712980561f3",
    "front": "**Def**: paying careful attention to every detail. SYN fastidious.\n**Farsi**: دقیق، با وسواس",
    "back": "meticulous"
  },
  {
    "id": "55331aaf-18dc-4921-a43b-0c7d5682e25f",
    "front": "**Def**: Paying careful attention.\n**Farsi**: دقیق، مشکل‌پسند",
    "back": "fastidious SYN"
  },
  {
    "id": "64a571eb-b422-4a27-af7a-60114171d729",
    "front": "**Def**: = sb is always ready to help.\n**Farsi**: هیچ کاری برای کسی دشوار نیست (همیشه آماده کمک)",
    "back": "nothing is too much trouble"
  },
  {
    "id": "2fadcf6b-8e36-4453-970e-decfe5fb0215",
    "front": "**Def**: a medical operation in which only a very small cut is made in the body.\n**Farsi**: جراحی با سوراخ کلید (لاپاروسکوپی)",
    "back": "keyhole surgery"
  },
  {
    "id": "b7547542-100a-476e-a041-ba440d5bca24",
    "front": "**Def**: a situation full of confusion due to a mistake. SYN muddle.\n**Farsi**: اشتباه، سوء تفاهم، درهم برهمی",
    "back": "mix-up INF"
  },
  {
    "id": "b9524604-91fd-4ae0-a65d-ca62c1071da7",
    "front": "**Def**: Confusion or mistake.\n**Farsi**: درهم برهمی",
    "back": "muddle SYN INF"
  },
  {
    "id": "02f98489-0bb3-4f89-8852-8287cdbd5b5f",
    "front": "**Def**: If a treatment is second to none, it is the best.\n**Farsi**: بی‌نظیر، بی‌همتا",
    "back": "second to none"
  },
  {
    "id": "59158448-a459-44d9-b733-fbb7a6e24c40",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely busy, with too many things to do.\n**Farsi**: سرشان شلوغ بودن (از فرط کار)",
    "back": "rushed off your feet"
  },
  {
    "id": "bf4f1aad-f081-40aa-9d82-3bdf32080197",
    "front": "**Def**: pay (no) attention to sth/sb.\n**Farsi**: توجه (نکردن) به کسی/چیزی",
    "back": "take (no) notice of sb/sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "51ed85fc-a4a4-4f1e-9a15-1660d3f379e8",
    "front": "**Def**: having a low rank in an organization or profession. OPP senior.\n**Farsi**: رده پایین، تازه کار",
    "back": "junior ADJ/N"
  },
  {
    "id": "712c6571-51cf-46b2-9f4a-6b8382869ac4",
    "front": "**Def**: the organization that provides local government in a city or area.\n**Farsi**: شورا",
    "back": "council"
  },
  {
    "id": "e17399da-ffe7-4640-9135-da746ef6b21f",
    "front": "**Def**: An elected member of the council.\n**Farsi**: عضو شورا",
    "back": "councillor N"
  },
  {
    "id": "89abdd21-c513-4a9f-a63f-7d52758038e0",
    "front": "**Def**: support or defend sth/sb. SYN stick up for sb INF.\n**Farsi**: حمایت کردن از، دفاع کردن از",
    "back": "stand up for sth/sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "ff81d875-e95a-4330-ba83-4dfdd8a10eaa",
    "front": "**Def**: as the representative of sb.\n**Farsi**: از طرف کسی، به نمایندگی از",
    "back": "on behalf of sb / on sb's behalf"
  },
  {
    "id": "74062666-d007-4554-a7d3-f9e3564a0c95",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who lives in a particular place. (Also a meaning of citizen).\n**Farsi**: ساکن، مقیم",
    "back": "resident"
  },
  {
    "id": "debb8863-cee6-4e39-bd34-8646a9dcddbc",
    "front": "**Def**: a person with legal rights in a country (can also mean resident).\n**Farsi**: شهروند",
    "back": "citizen"
  },
  {
    "id": "6994560f-5492-41eb-b334-92c52b56b990",
    "front": "**Def**: think that sth/sb is important and deserves respect.\n**Farsi**: جدی گرفتن",
    "back": "take sth/sb seriously"
  },
  {
    "id": "0e4da278-c991-4359-8d53-51b45a9ad6dc",
    "front": "**Def**: the right to take part in deciding sth (give sb a say / have a say in sth).\n**Farsi**: حق رأی، حق نظر",
    "back": "say N"
  },
  {
    "id": "84ba6e32-ae8c-43ea-bf2d-b4496dbcabd2",
    "front": "**Def**: give sth officially to sb/sth for a particular purpose.\n**Farsi**: اختصاص دادن، تخصیص دادن",
    "back": "allocate sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "b8b509fd-982c-4dd6-84bb-46ccb56614db",
    "front": "**Def**: make sure that sth happens or is definite.\n**Farsi**: تضمین کردن، مطمئن ساختن",
    "back": "ensure sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "0114b30b-6019-4187-b0db-2f5164dd0fd4",
    "front": "**Def**: a sum of money given, often by the government, for a purpose.\n**Farsi**: کمک مالی، یارانه",
    "back": "grant"
  },
  {
    "id": "f53fb7c0-834d-4f8a-a532-67ad03686f6b",
    "front": "**Def**: (of work) done by people (volunteers) who choose to do it without being paid.\n**Farsi**: داوطلبانه، اختیاری",
    "back": "voluntary ADJ"
  },
  {
    "id": "ef9b4629-01d9-4bab-aa4a-9e211d53c18e",
    "front": "**Def**: A person who does work without being paid.\n**Farsi**: داوطلب",
    "back": "volunteer N"
  },
  {
    "id": "222ec939-d5cb-4816-ba8c-ef1c0d653d1a",
    "front": "**Def**: The sector including charities and voluntary organizations.\n**Farsi**: بخش داوطلبانه/غیرانتفاعی",
    "back": "voluntary sector"
  },
  {
    "id": "31d6a542-20dd-4baa-aea4-db77f5e4e076",
    "front": "**Def**: An organization set up to provide help and raise money for those in need.\n**Farsi**: خیریه",
    "back": "charity organization"
  },
  {
    "id": "2dad9131-8839-45af-93b6-098386d2bad4",
    "front": "**Def**: the most important chosen or elected official in a town or city.\n**Farsi**: شهردار",
    "back": "mayor"
  },
  {
    "id": "0a9dd09a-152f-4f16-86cf-de0dd1d6a7fa",
    "front": "**Def**: allowed by rules or laws to do or receive sth. OPP ineligible.\n**Farsi**: واجد شرایط، ذی‌صلاح",
    "back": "eligible"
  },
  {
    "id": "5e451ce2-cd12-459c-8d82-7e344f8cf9cc",
    "front": "**Def**: Not allowed by rules or laws.\n**Farsi**: فاقد شرایط",
    "back": "ineligible OPP"
  },
  {
    "id": "530d6da7-e89a-4750-83a4-8d103392aaaa",
    "front": "**Def**: A person or thing with a high profile gets attention and is easily noticed (a high-profile job).\n**Farsi**: سرشناس، برجسته، در کانون توجه",
    "back": "high profile"
  },
  {
    "id": "47b66e8d-7d40-48eb-9a4b-ffaa571923cd",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who speaks on behalf of a group or an organization.\n**Farsi**: سخنگو",
    "back": "spokesperson"
  },
  {
    "id": "61a8f43b-6abe-4b34-8b6f-53d0d246221c",
    "front": "**Def**: help sth to happen or develop.\n**Farsi**: ترویج دادن، ارتقا دادن",
    "back": "promote sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "c5b63085-00f7-4752-9846-e7c769993b4b",
    "front": "**Def**: The act of promoting.\n**Farsi**: ترفیع، ارتقا",
    "back": "promotion N"
  },
  {
    "id": "595c26c6-7874-4443-90e4-0faf9cbd341b",
    "front": "**Def**: the amount of money a person or organization has to spend on sth (set a budget = decide a budget).\n**Farsi**: بودجه",
    "back": "budget"
  },
  {
    "id": "76242fe2-8a10-49be-b5d2-d99417f87dc1",
    "front": "**Def**: carefully planned in order to achieve a particular goal.\n**Farsi**: راهبردی، استراتژیک",
    "back": "strategic"
  },
  {
    "id": "dfca40ed-d2e8-433d-a795-81c37142a0f8",
    "front": "**Def**: A plan of action.\n**Farsi**: راهبرد، استراتژی",
    "back": "strategy N"
  },
  {
    "id": "657b0659-d851-4abc-882d-bd15041134ad",
    "front": "**Def**: happening or existing across the whole of a city (also nationwide, worldwide).\n**Farsi**: در سطح شهر، سراسری شهری",
    "back": "city-wide"
  },
  {
    "id": "3c377e2a-52c9-46c9-ad90-00da6d506513",
    "front": "**Def**: Across the whole country.\n**Farsi**: در سطح کشور، سراسری",
    "back": "nationwide"
  },
  {
    "id": "06fddeef-c940-4328-b80d-3a58f61751ff",
    "front": "**Def**: Across the whole world.\n**Farsi**: جهانی",
    "back": "worldwide"
  },
  {
    "id": "4a784cc7-bd53-4c43-adf4-0c6c47c35840",
    "front": "**Def**: the activity of keeping order in a place, using the police.\n**Farsi**: نظارت پلیس، اعمال قانون",
    "back": "policing"
  },
  {
    "id": "be5588e3-3507-44e1-b1d4-5b3b7ee95f6c",
    "front": "**Def**: a business or government department that provides a particular service (employment/advertising/travel agency).\n**Farsi**: آژانس، سازمان، نهاد",
    "back": "agency"
  },
  {
    "id": "50cae2a6-77c9-4ed4-9f5b-722c0e9a18a2",
    "front": "**Def**: a system of roads, lines, wires, etc. that are connected to each other (rail/road/underground/network).\n**Farsi**: شبکه",
    "back": "network"
  },
  {
    "id": "d1e5f638-7fd0-4265-8f7f-90f7fff65d98",
    "front": "**Def**: A warrant issued for arrest.\n**Farsi**: حکم جلب",
    "back": "arrest warrant"
  },
  {
    "id": "f9fc4cfe-dc54-4d04-9137-ace41929e0d3",
    "front": "**Def**: an official who acts as a judge in trials involving minor offences.\n**Farsi**: قاضی صلح، دادیار",
    "back": "magistrate"
  },
  {
    "id": "b8d986e9-b1ff-4cbf-ba68-1f7c67de2c7a",
    "front": "**Def**: good or true reasons for saying or doing sth (reasonable grounds for sth, on the grounds that ...).\n**Farsi**: دلایل، شواهد (کافی)",
    "back": "grounds (for sth) PL, FML"
  },
  {
    "id": "e1269d52-e406-49d8-a6da-101cba7a13af",
    "front": "**Def**: be going to do sth very soon.\n**Farsi**: در آستانه (انجام کاری) بودن",
    "back": "be about to (do sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "0d4d08af-3821-4241-a0c3-6b4e66b25d29",
    "front": "**Def**: warn sb officially that anything they say may be used against them as evidence in court.\n**Farsi**: هشدار رسمی دادن (اخطار پلیس)",
    "back": "caution sb FML"
  },
  {
    "id": "bc8d36cf-7333-4f15-807f-02373634452c",
    "front": "**Def**: the state of being in prison while awaiting trial (in custody).\n**Farsi**: بازداشت، توقیف",
    "back": "custody"
  },
  {
    "id": "397ba2ef-4d64-4456-8313-73c982f67ae6",
    "front": "**Def**: Held by the police or in prison.\n**Farsi**: در بازداشت",
    "back": "in custody"
  },
  {
    "id": "2cd27435-4094-4088-a30f-aef58b7f4521",
    "front": "**Def**: A person in charge of a meeting or committee.\n**Farsi**: رئیس، گرداننده جلسه",
    "back": "chairperson N (Neutral)"
  },
  {
    "id": "dbfc6d3f-68a6-4bca-ab31-9060d458d185",
    "front": "**Def**: A male chairperson.\n**Farsi**: رئیس (مرد)",
    "back": "chairman N (Men only)"
  },
  {
    "id": "650b2961-ed0e-47e2-be37-21df803e4d89",
    "front": "**Def**: A female chairperson.\n**Farsi**: رئیس (زن)",
    "back": "chairwoman N (Women only)"
  },
  {
    "id": "6150fb7b-4294-405e-b126-ad15a1ac0fca",
    "front": "**Def**: A male spokesperson.\n**Farsi**: سخنگو (مرد)",
    "back": "spokesman N (Men only)"
  },
  {
    "id": "9a4bbff8-51a3-435b-99e4-35b90c2c1f4f",
    "front": "**Def**: A female spokesperson.\n**Farsi**: سخنگو (زن)",
    "back": "spokeswoman N (Women only)"
  },
  {
    "id": "e423d651-f8f4-4507-aed8-6562ebedb9a9",
    "front": "**Def**: A female mayor or the mayor's wife.\n**Farsi**: شهردار زن / همسر شهردار",
    "back": "mayoress N (Women only)"
  },
  {
    "id": "af6f8a17-5a4b-416e-a2a3-1e59e2105c54",
    "front": "**Def**: the buying and selling of sth illegally. drug-/human-trafficking.\n**Farsi**: قاچاق، معامله غیرقانونی",
    "back": "trafficking"
  },
  {
    "id": "5cfd46b6-84ef-4cae-8b36-58d7977cadbd",
    "front": "**Def**: Illegal trade in drugs.\n**Farsi**: قاچاق مواد مخدر",
    "back": "drug-trafficking"
  },
  {
    "id": "199b1b6d-f45e-4b67-a75e-1c9f6c72d6ba",
    "front": "**Def**: Illegal trade in people.\n**Farsi**: قاچاق انسان",
    "back": "human-trafficking"
  },
  {
    "id": "70d72c5b-e593-4b99-bc44-ad15a67d9fc0",
    "front": "**Def**: the money you receive when you sell or organize sth.\n**Farsi**: عواید، سود (حاصل از جرم)",
    "back": "proceeds (of sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "14df617a-bbf9-4568-8ff6-e31690f28d83",
    "front": "**Def**: the crime of moving goods or people illegally into or out of a country.\n**Farsi**: قاچاق (کالا یا انسان)",
    "back": "smuggling"
  },
  {
    "id": "8ace7938-96ef-4b40-8e46-7b4d2afc5ee5",
    "front": "**Def**: To move goods or people illegally.\n**Farsi**: قاچاق کردن",
    "back": "smuggle sth/sb V"
  },
  {
    "id": "3ad29f87-84c6-4830-aa40-0e782ec16449",
    "front": "**Def**: a situation in which sb treats sb else unfairly in order to make money from their work.\n**Farsi**: استثمار، بهره‌کشی",
    "back": "exploitation DISAPPROVING"
  },
  {
    "id": "08f478ca-deb1-4c4f-8fe0-7727190b82bf",
    "front": "**Def**: To treat someone unfairly to make money.\n**Farsi**: استثمار کردن، بهره‌کشی کردن",
    "back": "exploit sb V"
  },
  {
    "id": "4d1a304e-47e2-4b12-aa28-46a971bc17e4",
    "front": "**Def**: hard physical work that sb is forced to do.\n**Farsi**: کار اجباری",
    "back": "forced labour"
  },
  {
    "id": "1d4fc234-25e7-4602-bbeb-685c7b03400a",
    "front": "**Def**: the crime of obtaining money from sb by tricking them.\n**Farsi**: کلاهبرداری، تقلب",
    "back": "fraud"
  },
  {
    "id": "6f415e53-5e57-4a4c-a2bf-b8e3ce7c5cd0",
    "front": "**Def**: To obtain money from someone by deception.\n**Farsi**: کلاهبرداری کردن از",
    "back": "defraud sb V"
  },
  {
    "id": "74648761-4dbd-4795-9664-9bd5c8b55793",
    "front": "**Def**: a group of criminals working together.\n**Farsi**: باند، دسته تبهکار",
    "back": "gang"
  },
  {
    "id": "fd228d6e-c2d1-4be7-be0e-ba32f5d274b8",
    "front": "**Def**: persuade sb to do sth, usually by offering them sth.\n**Farsi**: وسوسه کردن، فریب دادن",
    "back": "entice sb to do sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "ceac3b26-c62b-43a7-930c-30174dd9da99",
    "front": "**Def**: the crime of making an exact copy of documents or works of art in order to make money by selling them.\n**Farsi**: جعل، سندسازی",
    "back": "forgery"
  },
  {
    "id": "f6974d60-9653-4552-baaf-ee3ca45d40dc",
    "front": "**Def**: To make a fraudulent copy.\n**Farsi**: جعل کردن",
    "back": "forge sth V"
  },
  {
    "id": "37883cc5-fb71-4106-9a33-2aa91c36cd47",
    "front": "**Def**: a gun that can be carried.\n**Farsi**: سلاح گرم",
    "back": "firearm FML"
  },
  {
    "id": "b4d8ae69-adea-4b5f-8dc4-03968007a477",
    "front": "**Def**: keep sb in an official place, e.g. a police station, and prevent them from leaving (be detained in custody).\n**Farsi**: بازداشت کردن، در توقیف نگه داشتن",
    "back": "detain sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "c7276609-0363-4873-8c12-856d5879c924",
    "front": "**Def**: a legal document signed by a judge that allows the police to do sth; a judge issues a warrant.\n**Farsi**: حکم (جلب/بازداشت)",
    "back": "warrant"
  },
  {
    "id": "ab27e143-a2f2-4d06-818e-bc2ac23604f0",
    "front": "**Def**: Sent to prison until the trial.\n**Farsi**: در بازداشت موقت بودن",
    "back": "remanded in custody"
  },
  {
    "id": "13d37b7f-f7ee-43c7-97db-7f033009a0fc",
    "front": "**Def**: money left with a court to ensure that a prisoner will return for their trial (a judge releases sb on bail/grants bail or refuses bail).\n**Farsi**: وثیقه، ضمانت",
    "back": "bail"
  },
  {
    "id": "0974a9f0-9134-46a0-acf0-38a8836216c9",
    "front": "**Def**: To release someone upon payment of bail.\n**Farsi**: آزاد کردن با وثیقه",
    "back": "release sb on bail"
  },
  {
    "id": "7971aab3-4eb9-46d9-bc56-d4fa1b766e4a",
    "front": "**Def**: To allow release on bail.\n**Farsi**: وثیقه قبول کردن",
    "back": "grant bail"
  },
  {
    "id": "1950b645-a19c-4eee-9616-54cc94b8386e",
    "front": "**Def**: To deny release on bail.\n**Farsi**: وثیقه نپذیرفتن",
    "back": "refuse bail"
  },
  {
    "id": "757a6b43-9815-4b26-97af-5452b14594b8",
    "front": "**Def**: an officer of the lowest rank.\n**Farsi**: پاسبان، گروهبان",
    "back": "police constable (PC)"
  },
  {
    "id": "0a59172f-4b09-40dc-b0b8-9ca298a57bc2",
    "front": "**Def**: A police officer above constable.\n**Farsi**: گروهبان",
    "back": "sergeant"
  },
  {
    "id": "3e89bce8-aa65-4fcc-a4a6-9d6fb162ebc8",
    "front": "**Def**: A police officer above sergeant.\n**Farsi**: بازرس",
    "back": "inspector"
  },
  {
    "id": "68b2087e-1079-4dff-8bc3-2f7225a8e7d1",
    "front": "**Def**: the head of each regional police force.\n**Farsi**: فرمانده پلیس (منطقه)",
    "back": "chief constable"
  },
  {
    "id": "ca2bf4ff-2789-47fc-8a4f-13303bd8e4fd",
    "front": "**Def**: the official ending of a law, system, or institution.\n**Farsi**: لغو رسمی (قانون، سیستم یا نهاد)",
    "back": "abolition"
  },
  {
    "id": "b2438a77-69a3-4bda-abfd-89296354d100",
    "front": "**Def**: punishment by death.\n**Farsi**: مجازات اعدام",
    "back": "capital punishment"
  },
  {
    "id": "cfdf1c29-d28b-4f1a-bd22-11e94920e080",
    "front": "**Def**: severe punishment for something serious that somebody has done.\n**Farsi**: قصاص، مجازات شدید",
    "back": "retribution"
  },
  {
    "id": "1d1d7f51-0ab2-4834-803c-b618b430459e",
    "front": "**Def**: to put somebody in prison (syn put sb in prison).\n**Farsi**: زندانی کردن، به حبس انداختن",
    "back": "lock somebody up"
  },
  {
    "id": "b9c4eb60-4e51-4ee2-9b87-39d87fa7f3a4",
    "front": "**Def**: the process of helping people to live a normal life after they have been ill or in prison.\n**Farsi**: توانبخشی، بازپروری",
    "back": "rehabilitation"
  },
  {
    "id": "42bbd382-78a1-4019-a5e1-eba7f04b9ef1",
    "front": "**Def**: change your behaviour and become a better person.\n**Farsi**: تغییر رویه دادن، متحول شدن",
    "back": "turn over a new leaf"
  },
  {
    "id": "f95ac55f-0c01-4025-b979-6a4830407bc4",
    "front": "**Def**: in a period of great difficulty and uncertainty.\n**Farsi**: در بحران",
    "back": "in crisis"
  },
  {
    "id": "e0ea6779-7392-4967-8f97-9d564c21db45",
    "front": "**Def**: (informal) commit a crime again (a person is a reoffender).\n**Farsi**: مرتکب جرم مجدد شدن",
    "back": "reoffend"
  },
  {
    "id": "88cf9c7a-5775-492b-b2a1-f723252aa00a",
    "front": "**Def**: think about something/somebody in a particular way.\n**Farsi**: چیزی/کسی را به عنوان چیزی تلقی کردن",
    "back": "regard sth/sb as sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "b8cd18dc-7180-457d-9bf7-01f6cd3d0c7a",
    "front": "**Def**: a risk or danger (= hazard) that is part of a job.\n**Farsi**: خطر شغلی",
    "back": "occupational hazard"
  },
  {
    "id": "8acbc745-f9b7-4a46-8d3b-cecddcb6e670",
    "front": "**Def**: take action to punish somebody because they made you suffer.\n**Farsi**: انتقام گرفتن",
    "back": "take revenge"
  },
  {
    "id": "182a2fac-0063-415c-bb55-cd281016611d",
    "front": "**Def**: show that something is right or fair.\n**Farsi**: توجیه کردن، حق دادن",
    "back": "justify sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "fa7e19d4-d2b4-43bc-82ed-bdc1703a5efb",
    "front": "**Def**: only, and with nothing else (e.g. We rely exclusively on rail.).\n**Farsi**: منحصراً، فقط",
    "back": "exclusively"
  },
  {
    "id": "3ce619be-ca17-413e-95cd-14baac21793b",
    "front": "**Def**: treatment of a physical or mental problem or illness.\n**Farsi**: درمان، معالجه",
    "back": "therapy"
  },
  {
    "id": "9eff5106-4420-4b2e-a12d-fe024aa5f142",
    "front": "**Def**: a person living in a prison.\n**Farsi**: زندانی، محبوس",
    "back": "inmate"
  },
  {
    "id": "c51e58f3-19c8-4f25-b007-9f6944de45b0",
    "front": "**Def**: a part or share of the whole amount or number.\n**Farsi**: نسبت، سهم",
    "back": "proportion"
  },
  {
    "id": "11c63e1d-3a0f-44e3-8ef7-e48944f54419",
    "front": "**Def**: be different from what is normal.\n**Farsi**: منحرف شدن از",
    "back": "deviate from sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "f04156d7-21cb-497b-a687-a375295cae29",
    "front": "**Def**: the policy of separating people of different sex, race, religion, etc.\n**Farsi**: جداسازی، تفکیک",
    "back": "segregation"
  },
  {
    "id": "7f64062f-c904-42c9-8323-fb236c460e8c",
    "front": "**Def**: keep somebody/something within an enclosed area.\n**Farsi**: محدود کردن، محصور کردن",
    "back": "confine sb/sth in sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "a53db910-e93b-455a-b8aa-d6978dedbccc",
    "front": "**Def**: a lockable room for prisoners in a prison or police station.\n**Farsi**: سلول (زندان)",
    "back": "cell"
  },
  {
    "id": "02dedf3d-c6b1-4d99-ae0c-02c45a3d324e",
    "front": "**Def**: agreement about something.\n**Farsi**: رضایت، توافق",
    "back": "consent"
  },
  {
    "id": "52058242-ab15-4cb6-ae18-fb90fa72dc9d",
    "front": "**Def**: a holiday where you cook your own meals.\n**Farsi**: خدمات غذایی بر عهده مشتری (سلف کترینگ)",
    "back": "self-catering"
  },
  {
    "id": "3338bac3-b2bd-4e7b-a43f-0bbb69a2318e",
    "front": "**Def**: when you judge your own progress and achievements.\n**Farsi**: خودارزیابی",
    "back": "self-assessment"
  },
  {
    "id": "482f5f9e-05d0-424f-aa35-3bdd7aa96a7c",
    "front": "**Def**: a country's army, navy, and air force (syn the armed forces).\n**Farsi**: نیروهای مسلح، نظامیان",
    "back": "the military"
  },
  {
    "id": "34350f69-8c77-4c06-86d2-fe616ecee3b0",
    "front": "**Def**: a part of a large organization (e.g. branch of a bank).\n**Farsi**: شاخه، بخش",
    "back": "branch"
  },
  {
    "id": "bc42ffee-48d3-4fb7-96bc-fe2f3c01b2ce",
    "front": "**Def**: a planned military or police action (military operation).\n**Farsi**: عملیات، مأموریت",
    "back": "operation"
  },
  {
    "id": "ef70d736-5ec7-4f8d-8be4-ad1c79fa78bc",
    "front": "**Def**: a person or group of people who protect something/somebody.\n**Farsi**: نگهبان، محافظت کردن",
    "back": "guard"
  },
  {
    "id": "2d59c2c9-7eac-4b4a-9469-0993adb5f590",
    "front": "**Def**: not belonging to the armed forces.\n**Farsi**: غیرنظامی",
    "back": "civilian"
  },
  {
    "id": "8026b69f-f19c-4dba-982b-2b2162add035",
    "front": "**Def**: the power to give orders to other people.\n**Farsi**: اقتدار، صلاحیت",
    "back": "authority"
  },
  {
    "id": "af98a8f6-c30b-449f-8380-c7ebadf56d50",
    "front": "**Def**: an extra force that performs part-time duties and is available if needed.\n**Farsi**: نیروی ذخیره",
    "back": "the reserve(s)"
  },
  {
    "id": "64a5f9e8-9836-43ac-bc37-5fe2dfc66626",
    "front": "**Def**: recognize a difference between people or things (syn differentiate).\n**Farsi**: تمایز قائل شدن بین",
    "back": "distinguish between"
  },
  {
    "id": "99dffffa-790e-4dd1-b593-65b7533ee41a",
    "front": "**Def**: (especially AME) relating to members of the armed forces below officer rank (to enlist is to join the armed forces).\n**Farsi**: سرباز عادی، ثبت نام شده در نیروهای مسلح",
    "back": "enlisted (people or things)"
  },
  {
    "id": "ab8bf35f-4bf6-4dfa-aa20-986acd22a009",
    "front": "**Def**: central, and forming the necessary basis of something.\n**Farsi**: بنیادی، اساسی",
    "back": "fundamental"
  },
  {
    "id": "254af1a6-0a07-4115-974e-3c71e322a428",
    "front": "**Def**: fighting between forces (armed/unarmed combat).\n**Farsi**: رزم، مبارزه",
    "back": "combat"
  },
  {
    "id": "03b83fd2-cc6a-462b-a68f-417356cb105f",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely large (syn huge).\n**Farsi**: بسیار بزرگ، گسترده",
    "back": "vast"
  },
  {
    "id": "83089ced-ac69-424a-ab9b-b3504aada8b7",
    "front": "**Def**: include something within an area or area of activity.\n**Farsi**: شامل شدن، دربرگرفتن",
    "back": "encompass sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "a99a8a8d-0e3e-44b3-8b0b-91b172f194c9",
    "front": "**Def**: (in the forces) be in charge of people (a person is in command).\n**Farsi**: فرماندهی کردن",
    "back": "command sb/sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "83df352d-03ed-42c4-94c3-1c77c3141a6e",
    "front": "**Def**: a structure which produces nuclear energy.\n**Farsi**: راکتور هسته‌ای",
    "back": "nuclear reactor"
  },
  {
    "id": "e5b72bb7-fb37-4c7e-8f07-df93c4eb80bb",
    "front": "**Def**: an object such as a knife, gun, or bomb that is used for fighting.\n**Farsi**: سلاح",
    "back": "weapon"
  },
  {
    "id": "07f26ef5-0f4b-473b-8006-cca7f0c0e98d",
    "front": "**Def**: comprise, compose (used to describe what something is formed of).\n**Farsi**: تشکیل دادن، شامل شدن",
    "back": "make up"
  },
  {
    "id": "3e4977f3-1af0-432d-a2be-9ba048caf3ed",
    "front": "**Def**: (formal) help somebody to do something.\n**Farsi**: کمک کردن، یاری رساندن",
    "back": "assist (sb) in/with sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "3f4aed11-cc5a-4fff-a757-65b2bf7579f1",
    "front": "**Def**: intending to stop people fighting (a peacekeeping force).\n**Farsi**: صلح‌بانی",
    "back": "peacekeeping"
  },
  {
    "id": "9e0f0cf2-4d0b-43d3-96e4-22499eb5ba5e",
    "front": "**Def**: connected with the people who live in a country (civil unrest/war/rights).\n**Farsi**: مدنی، غیرنظامی",
    "back": "civil"
  },
  {
    "id": "fde58945-1cfc-4d32-a2aa-aef468757b9c",
    "front": "**Def**: much; a great deal.\n**Farsi**: به میزان قابل توجهی",
    "back": "considerably"
  },
  {
    "id": "c84a00cd-b001-4be5-9b47-82289268bb3b",
    "front": "**Def**: money provided for a special purpose (government funding).\n**Farsi**: تأمین مالی، بودجه",
    "back": "funding"
  },
  {
    "id": "e31576ae-37e7-48ff-851a-555f283c3eb5",
    "front": "**Def**: the second of two things that have just been mentioned.\n**Farsi**: دومی، مورد دوم",
    "back": "the latter"
  },
  {
    "id": "468e1188-5d92-4abd-af03-53176309f7fe",
    "front": "**Def**: prepare an army to fight in a war.\n**Farsi**: بسیج کردن",
    "back": "mobilize (sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "a491260b-1825-4a27-bc0a-923de3e7f4c9",
    "front": "**Def**: having the opposite effect to the one intended.\n**Farsi**: نتیجه معکوس",
    "back": "counter-productive"
  },
  {
    "id": "68b0ddc3-08d2-4a4e-8640-f8efeba4b7b1",
    "front": "**Def**: only; simply (used to emphasize what you are saying).\n**Farsi**: صرفاً، فقط",
    "back": "merely"
  },
  {
    "id": "d5ccca0c-8541-46e5-87d8-4487f247b54e",
    "front": "**Def**: the activity of fighting a war, often of a particular type (guerrilla warfare).\n**Farsi**: جنگ، رزم",
    "back": "warfare"
  },
  {
    "id": "eedb99cb-1aed-4563-965e-5b2433d007c4",
    "front": "**Def**: move (goods) illegally into or out of a country.\n**Farsi**: قاچاق کردن",
    "back": "smuggle"
  },
  {
    "id": "40d9d785-a485-4c85-95f5-555eee7d32d7",
    "front": "**Def**: a subject under discussion.\n**Farsi**: مسئله، موضوع",
    "back": "issue"
  },
  {
    "id": "0ed37482-2726-46fe-bd01-8acc7a0e2fe9",
    "front": "**Def**: place someone on bail or in custody.\n**Farsi**: بازداشت موقت کردن، تحت نظر قرار دادن",
    "back": "remand someone"
  },
  {
    "id": "1b01ba64-07cf-4d3f-b2d1-9dbfe50002f0",
    "front": "**Def**: give a warning.\n**Farsi**: هشدار، اخطار دادن",
    "back": "caution"
  },
  {
    "id": "2ffcd113-08cc-47d1-b909-b76fddf25bcb",
    "front": "**Def**: make full use of and benefit from (a resource).\n**Farsi**: بهره‌برداری کردن",
    "back": "exploit"
  },
  {
    "id": "c90b070e-86ff-41f3-a6b7-dabbf7fc9fc1",
    "front": "**Def**: make a copy of (a document, etc.) illegally.\n**Farsi**: جعل کردن",
    "back": "forge"
  },
  {
    "id": "0584d680-4725-4a24-a913-708b21097409",
    "front": "**Def**: keep someone in official custody.\n**Farsi**: بازداشت کردن",
    "back": "detain someone"
  },
  {
    "id": "ac8075c4-9302-40ee-9886-8d70f0157b24",
    "front": "**Def**: fake, copied illegally.\n**Farsi**: تقلبی، جعلی",
    "back": "counterfeit"
  },
  {
    "id": "08bbb16b-3b67-44ec-ad84-4c6388c11d4e",
    "front": "**Def**: theft or misappropriation of funds.\n**Farsi**: اختلاس",
    "back": "embezzlement"
  },
  {
    "id": "087c9d02-d2e8-4c00-b3a0-39d75c637c4f",
    "front": "**Def**: the practice of spying.\n**Farsi**: جاسوسی",
    "back": "espionage"
  },
  {
    "id": "5886bb0c-a786-4af1-8abc-0967c07c2920",
    "front": "**Def**: escaping or fleeing (from police/justice).\n**Farsi**: در حال فرار",
    "back": "on the run"
  },
  {
    "id": "de5963cd-2327-49f5-99be-b2dcad04d25c",
    "front": "**Def**: handing over a criminal to another jurisdiction.\n**Farsi**: استرداد مجرم",
    "back": "extradition"
  },
  {
    "id": "9a676dbc-ab8a-46e5-82ed-35bc890d4928",
    "front": "**Def**: a secret investigation by agents pretending to be ordinary citizens.\n**Farsi**: عملیات مخفی",
    "back": "undercover operation"
  },
  {
    "id": "d23c548a-4bdc-4783-8444-daed57d803d0",
    "front": "**Def**: to imprison or confine.\n**Farsi**: زندانی کردن",
    "back": "incarcerate"
  },
  {
    "id": "c2907ab8-26d7-4032-8100-eb091fec5dfe",
    "front": "**Def**: release of an offender from detention, subject to a period of good behaviour.\n**Farsi**: آزادی مشروط",
    "back": "probation"
  },
  {
    "id": "23af21d6-95fc-415a-8045-90540be8279d",
    "front": "**Def**: isolation from others in a small room.\n**Farsi**: حبس انفرادی",
    "back": "solitary confinement"
  },
  {
    "id": "2ba5e29a-2b0e-4d71-b82a-c14a0e1ed07e",
    "front": "**Def**: a sentence requiring the offender to be held in custody (prison sentence).\n**Farsi**: حکم زندان",
    "back": "custodial sentence"
  },
  {
    "id": "5925905e-6963-41aa-a01c-0eff79bd08ef",
    "front": "**Def**: a sentence that is not enforced immediately, but only if the offender commits another crime.\n**Farsi**: حکم تعلیقی",
    "back": "suspended sentence"
  },
  {
    "id": "08203366-190c-4950-9cff-2a586f9a1ddd",
    "front": "**Def**: a prison guard.\n**Farsi**: زندانبان",
    "back": "warder"
  },
  {
    "id": "d710e1b6-a534-48be-b173-205f7f6a56c7",
    "front": "**Def**: an urgent and emotional request.\n**Farsi**: درخواست عاجزانه",
    "back": "plea"
  },
  {
    "id": "286524f6-a97f-4560-a4e4-d4f8ce3325f0",
    "front": "**Def**: the act of taking someone illegally.\n**Farsi**: آدم‌ربایی",
    "back": "kidnapping"
  },
  {
    "id": "075f697a-2413-4981-9ae1-0bd306b8c78d",
    "front": "**Def**: a difficult or unpleasant experience.\n**Farsi**: سختی، محنت، تجربه ناخوشایند",
    "back": "ordeal"
  },
  {
    "id": "99b3d635-9554-4abc-9d97-7a00840a016f",
    "front": "**Def**: the US legislative body (or similar bodies in other countries).\n**Farsi**: سنا (مجلس علیای قانونگذاری)",
    "back": "Senate"
  },
  {
    "id": "d657f752-877f-4a31-ae84-e145e0744aad",
    "front": "**Def**: strongly recommend or encourage.\n**Farsi**: اصرار کردن، ترغیب کردن",
    "back": "urge"
  },
  {
    "id": "748371e8-5354-4e41-bfb2-776cea688a2a",
    "front": "**Def**: an attempt to do something.\n**Farsi**: تلاش، کوشش",
    "back": "bid (to do sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "bf0495da-331e-4bbb-ab99-4c88423f0dde",
    "front": "**Def**: to force somebody out of a job or position.\n**Farsi**: بیرون راندن، برکنار کردن",
    "back": "oust"
  },
  {
    "id": "17be0d00-7738-4a04-aea1-1eb00c3541e4",
    "front": "**Def**: a thing that helps or encourages something.\n**Farsi**: تقویت، افزایش دادن",
    "back": "boost"
  },
  {
    "id": "d24d253b-2196-4df3-863e-3bd18e5b464c",
    "front": "**Def**: formal permission to do something.\n**Farsi**: مجوز، چراغ سبز",
    "back": "Go-ahead (for scheme)"
  },
  {
    "id": "42f8293f-b081-4561-9500-0d79cbb6f161",
    "front": "**Def**: stop happening or existing.\n**Farsi**: متوقف کردن",
    "back": "cease"
  },
  {
    "id": "26528398-4be7-42ee-842d-6c7e67c31f37",
    "front": "**Def**: to limit or control something.\n**Farsi**: مهار کردن، کنترل کردن",
    "back": "curb"
  },
  {
    "id": "edb3531c-7dcc-42f1-88aa-fa6789294e5a",
    "front": "**Def**: a problem that is difficult to solve.\n**Farsi**: معما",
    "back": "riddle"
  },
  {
    "id": "04c7166b-48ae-4026-b367-d6e2ba1b4d2f",
    "front": "**Def**: in the process of being attacked.\n**Farsi**: تحت حمله",
    "back": "under attack"
  },
  {
    "id": "1a43b2be-14ea-486a-bead-1b833c007cec",
    "front": "**Def**: bad news, especially when something unfortunate has happened.\n**Farsi**: ضربه، خبر بد",
    "back": "blow (bad news)"
  },
  {
    "id": "22596f95-3e95-40ce-b50a-235dabec3e3e",
    "front": "**Def**: a warning.\n**Farsi**: هشدار",
    "back": "alert"
  },
  {
    "id": "db84f0c1-e2ba-4f73-bf40-e96255bd03d4",
    "front": "**Def**: reached a point where it is about to happen (often something very bad).\n**Farsi**: در آستانه، در مرز",
    "back": "on brink of"
  },
  {
    "id": "ae6451fa-d74c-406f-b21c-32627237d546",
    "front": "**Def**: to reject the possibility of something.\n**Farsi**: رد کردن امکان چیزی",
    "back": "rule out"
  },
  {
    "id": "f24221e5-1f71-4443-aeff-1d0c315874b3",
    "front": "**Def**: jewellery (or precious stones).\n**Farsi**: جواهرات، سنگ‌های قیمتی",
    "back": "gems"
  },
  {
    "id": "392b178b-2119-4937-a84f-e3b9d609bc51",
    "front": "**Def**: a statement, without proof, that somebody has done something wrong.\n**Farsi**: ادعا، اتهام (بی‌اساس)",
    "back": "allegation"
  },
  {
    "id": "90f419d4-bc86-45f9-b5d8-4f6b07647783",
    "front": "**Def**: an attempt to stop people discovering the truth about something.\n**Farsi**: لاپوشانی",
    "back": "cover-up"
  },
  {
    "id": "741e6630-9057-46f6-8684-314aba2d91e8",
    "front": "**Def**: one of the people who provides information, especially for journalists.\n**Farsi**: منبع (اطلاعات)",
    "back": "source"
  },
  {
    "id": "a08cf49a-e8b6-4003-829d-4cc3565553d3",
    "front": "**Def**: a small mistake caused by forgetting something or carelessness.\n**Farsi**: اشتباه، غفلت",
    "back": "lapse"
  },
  {
    "id": "4b57ce83-8103-4d93-a3f9-2df6e181cb9a",
    "front": "**Def**: causing a lot of discussion and disagreement.\n**Farsi**: بحث‌برانگیز، جنجالی",
    "back": "controversial"
  },
  {
    "id": "f90d54fa-0261-48bc-aed4-420d1bce2e91",
    "front": "**Def**: an official action taken in order to achieve something.\n**Farsi**: اقدام، تدبیر",
    "back": "measure"
  },
  {
    "id": "6324378f-8622-4cea-b581-ebb8c294d63b",
    "front": "**Def**: without people's awareness or knowledge (in private, not in public).\n**Farsi**: پشت صحنه، مخفیانه",
    "back": "behind the scenes"
  },
  {
    "id": "3becda44-1e91-4302-b93d-bdd49ed6a633",
    "front": "**Def**: used for saying where the facts or information have come from.\n**Farsi**: طبق گفته، بر اساس",
    "back": "according to"
  },
  {
    "id": "a0562be5-d797-4c2a-af1d-8927c8376e41",
    "front": "**Def**: a process of asking people for their opinion about something.\n**Farsi**: نظرسنجی",
    "back": "opinion poll"
  },
  {
    "id": "ffc38d54-ea84-4d5b-8287-02806d84d95e",
    "front": "**Def**: (of facts, information, etc.) become known.\n**Farsi**: آشکار شدن، پدیدار شدن",
    "back": "emerge"
  },
  {
    "id": "2f8268ea-4ee4-4f9b-a589-f8d9edd02f5f",
    "front": "**Def**: strongly critical (scathing attack/remark).\n**Farsi**: کوبنده، به شدت انتقادی",
    "back": "scathing"
  },
  {
    "id": "cd19267f-501a-4fe7-88fc-38a2cd2a9d27",
    "front": "**Def**: give secret information to journalists or the public.\n**Farsi**: درز دادن اطلاعات",
    "back": "leak sth to sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "9abae4bf-4ef3-4d59-95ed-d03785dbb9c6",
    "front": "**Def**: repeat the exact words that somebody said.\n**Farsi**: نقل قول کردن",
    "back": "quote sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "cc960258-89a8-467e-81f9-b24aa26c3cca",
    "front": "**Def**: a situation in which a large number of people express strong feelings against something.\n**Farsi**: طوفان اعتراض",
    "back": "storm of protest"
  },
  {
    "id": "3e96d668-83e4-4919-a575-7acb8980a60a",
    "front": "**Def**: the situation and public opinion are changing.\n**Farsi**: ورق برگشتن، تغییر جهت جریان (افکار عمومی)",
    "back": "the tide is now turning"
  },
  {
    "id": "b887318a-0395-4b02-a654-c2f1ff2244b8",
    "front": "**Def**: cause something to start or develop.\n**Farsi**: جرقه‌زدن، آغاز کردن",
    "back": "spark further trouble"
  },
  {
    "id": "f0faf51d-abd7-4029-8a62-0ad39330d20d",
    "front": "**Def**: a very angry argument.\n**Farsi**: نزاع آتشین، مشاجره شدید",
    "back": "a blazing row"
  },
  {
    "id": "d186a41f-7d68-45a6-8f9a-151904c1f10a",
    "front": "**Def**: been strongly criticized.\n**Farsi**: مورد حمله قرار گرفتن (انتقاد)",
    "back": "come under attack"
  },
  {
    "id": "0548ad39-2d58-487b-bde3-fae9978caa8d",
    "front": "**Def**: in a position in which people can criticize and blame you.\n**Farsi**: در خط آتش (در معرض انتقاد و سرزنش)",
    "back": "in the firing line"
  },
  {
    "id": "88565cc2-40ae-4e88-806b-f8ccb8487dc5",
    "front": "**Def**: a difficult situation.\n**Farsi**: در گوشه سخت گیر افتادن، در مخمصه قرار گرفتن",
    "back": "get himself into a tight corner"
  },
  {
    "id": "d36075fb-8c2e-4aa7-ad8b-75df7b3c1d1e",
    "front": "**Def**: behaviour that is unfair or dishonest.\n**Farsi**: تقلب، تخلف، بازی کثیف",
    "back": "foul play"
  },
  {
    "id": "a9765ee1-d387-4da6-ba25-f41c186046d5",
    "front": "**Def**: a situation in which everyone has the same opportunities.\n**Farsi**: زمین بازی برابر (فرصت‌های برابر)",
    "back": "a level playing field"
  },
  {
    "id": "782daa00-643d-49f3-83a6-3aecd5fccf1e",
    "front": "**Def**: write down details of an arrangement which you may have to change later.\n**Farsi**: به طور موقت یادداشت کردن",
    "back": "pencil sth in"
  },
  {
    "id": "eaf854d0-66a8-47a3-a6a6-ea04967e4815",
    "front": "**Def**: make a small hole in something (puncture skin / a tyre).\n**Farsi**: سوراخ کردن، پنچر کردن",
    "back": "puncture sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "78d1d223-f59d-4235-8de9-e380540460b0",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely painful (excruciating pain/headaches).\n**Farsi**: طاقت‌فرسا، درد شدید",
    "back": "excruciating"
  },
  {
    "id": "1b5cba12-ce33-4704-95c7-c3a4de84f66d",
    "front": "**Def**: happening after or as a result of another event.\n**Farsi**: متعاقب، در پی آمده",
    "back": "ensuing"
  },
  {
    "id": "c96ef558-4ab3-472f-b66b-0f72ec1e94f6",
    "front": "**Def**: (especially of a disease) lasting a long time and hard to cure.\n**Farsi**: مزمن",
    "back": "chronic"
  },
  {
    "id": "9ace002d-153c-4355-8bb7-cf8632f3673f",
    "front": "**Def**: still existing or needing to be dealt with.\n**Farsi**: باقی مانده",
    "back": "remaining"
  },
  {
    "id": "8ea90afb-ed10-4a42-9dc9-ced76c675940",
    "front": "**Def**: get well again quickly after an illness or accident.\n**Farsi**: بهبود سریع یافتن",
    "back": "make a speedy/rapid recovery"
  },
  {
    "id": "de80872a-d369-4433-92c6-b8932ba9091c",
    "front": "**Def**: to be brave enough to do something.\n**Farsi**: جرأت داشتن، جسارت کردن",
    "back": "dare (to)"
  },
  {
    "id": "7c59cad6-da45-443d-ad79-55d767f92029",
    "front": "**Def**: stay somewhere that protects you from danger or bad weather.\n**Farsi**: پناه گرفتن، سرپناه",
    "back": "shelter"
  },
  {
    "id": "d8d06dff-b211-422f-9f6a-be329421f258",
    "front": "**Def**: full of very many insects, animals, etc. (rat-infested, shark-infested).\n**Farsi**: مملو (از حشرات یا حیوانات مضر)",
    "back": "infested"
  },
  {
    "id": "1c2ec765-0963-477c-b44f-015c80739e9f",
    "front": "**Def**: an area in which the ground is very wet or covered in water.\n**Farsi**: باتلاق",
    "back": "swamp"
  },
  {
    "id": "4ca0c1f0-4e59-4592-b9ec-15f1b567e245",
    "front": "**Def**: begin to deal with a situation.\n**Farsi**: اقدام کردن",
    "back": "take action"
  },
  {
    "id": "cd3dddd8-9158-4a7b-95f6-33ade4b3850c",
    "front": "**Def**: extreme in a way that has a sudden, violent, or serious effect.\n**Farsi**: شدید، جدی",
    "back": "drastic"
  },
  {
    "id": "5e462ca7-405f-4a4b-bc39-5665881e493a",
    "front": "**Def**: move away from where you should be, without intending to.\n**Farsi**: سرگردان، گم شدن",
    "back": "stray"
  },
  {
    "id": "2634031e-00b9-4281-a4f8-ae739626b07e",
    "front": "**Def**: unable to think clearly because of shock or a blow to the head.\n**Farsi**: گیج، منگ",
    "back": "dazed"
  },
  {
    "id": "db248cff-51a6-4af1-8779-48fb484d2872",
    "front": "**Def**: confused about where you are or which way to go.\n**Farsi**: سردرگم، جهت گم کرده",
    "back": "disorientated"
  },
  {
    "id": "a7403498-8872-4214-a528-875c3abc1fb7",
    "front": "**Def**: think clearly again after a period of confusion.\n**Farsi**: به خود آمدن، هوشیاری خود را بازیافتن",
    "back": "regain your senses"
  },
  {
    "id": "df3145d2-1518-4c2f-ade8-34662aa8bbb7",
    "front": "**Def**: (informal) stay where you are rather than moving away.\n**Farsi**: ثابت ماندن، تکان نخوردن",
    "back": "stay put"
  },
  {
    "id": "51ad42ac-ef45-46ec-b47f-a514930660f4",
    "front": "**Def**: decide to do something, even though it involves risk.\n**Farsi**: ریسک کردن، شانس خود را امتحان کردن",
    "back": "take a chance on sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "0099fd8e-7116-46c7-8b51-8eecefcb7590",
    "front": "**Def**: very difficult and tiring; needing great effort (syn punishing).\n**Farsi**: طاقت‌فرسا، بسیار سخت",
    "back": "gruelling"
  },
  {
    "id": "c8b0f2f5-d54a-413c-a13e-ed3bba1617d7",
    "front": "**Def**: a famous person (syns personality, celeb INF).\n**Farsi**: سلبریتی، فرد مشهور",
    "back": "celebrity"
  },
  {
    "id": "4fd4a2db-5f31-4907-bce3-8a1096104f6e",
    "front": "**Def**: it is right that you should have something.\n**Farsi**: شایسته بودن، سزاوار بودن",
    "back": "deserve sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "79d1de22-b4dd-4c93-84ea-3947925161e4",
    "front": "**Def**: an investigation into the opinions or behaviour of a large group of people.\n**Farsi**: نظرسنجی، بررسی",
    "back": "survey"
  },
  {
    "id": "85dd02cc-457b-4471-ab5a-851afe8725ed",
    "front": "**Def**: the state of being alone and not watched or disturbed by others.\n**Farsi**: حریم خصوصی",
    "back": "privacy"
  },
  {
    "id": "0e289179-995d-44d8-b355-6a13a56e9ce9",
    "front": "**Def**: the reporting of news in the press.\n**Farsi**: پوشش خبری",
    "back": "coverage"
  },
  {
    "id": "3f10c759-29c4-4394-ba1d-0a2c6bdb0066",
    "front": "**Def**: well known to many people through TV or the press.\n**Farsi**: در معرض دید عموم، مشهور",
    "back": "in the public eye"
  },
  {
    "id": "8a103a6a-a18c-454b-9c00-0f08a7337739",
    "front": "**Def**: information learned as the result of research.\n**Farsi**: یافته‌ها، نتایج",
    "back": "findings"
  },
  {
    "id": "b314a65c-b805-437f-b511-90cfe13e7b9a",
    "front": "**Def**: a thing that comes into somebody's life in a negative way.\n**Farsi**: تجاوز، مزاحمت",
    "back": "intrusion (into sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "7989e465-3412-4120-93c4-82d64fef394f",
    "front": "**Def**: a newspaper that gives emphasis to stories about famous people (less serious).\n**Farsi**: روزنامه زرد",
    "back": "tabloid"
  },
  {
    "id": "69705f88-50c8-4698-8feb-d1e1c3236a5e",
    "front": "**Def**: choose somebody/something from a group for special attention.\n**Farsi**: جدا کردن، متمایز کردن",
    "back": "single sb/sth out"
  },
  {
    "id": "315b652f-a53a-4468-85ca-ea24db976d92",
    "front": "**Def**: the process of helping to cure somebody with drug or alcohol addiction (short for rehabilitation).\n**Farsi**: ترک اعتیاد، بازپروری",
    "back": "rehab"
  },
  {
    "id": "29d8cc93-2a04-477f-b1e6-9dc6b32c1e98",
    "front": "**Def**: (informal) upset somebody/something.\n**Farsi**: تکان دادن، ناراحت کردن",
    "back": "rock sb/sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "8e4c114d-a7f8-41ad-b52c-e1dc8cef1fdd",
    "front": "**Def**: a situation in which important people behave in a dishonest or immoral way that shocks people.\n**Farsi**: رسوایی، آبروریزی",
    "back": "scandal"
  },
  {
    "id": "f2b55ef4-4b5f-4383-83d2-249763198372",
    "front": "**Def**: a man and woman who have not been married long.\n**Farsi**: تازه عروس و داماد",
    "back": "newlyweds"
  },
  {
    "id": "4aa1cec4-d4be-4e40-b03d-f47b795d6b64",
    "front": "**Def**: (informal) in difficulties and likely to fail (usually about a relationship).\n**Farsi**: در آستانه شکست، در خطر",
    "back": "on the rocks"
  },
  {
    "id": "672d24e0-ac4f-4eec-8085-d7baf4b9922a",
    "front": "**Def**: a story or piece of information that may or may not be true.\n**Farsi**: شایعه",
    "back": "rumour"
  },
  {
    "id": "7b4da023-9392-4455-be88-bc1df3ed7bbe",
    "front": "**Def**: (informal) end a romantic relationship with somebody.\n**Farsi**: ترک کردن (رابطه)",
    "back": "dump sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "477ea3eb-9a4f-4af4-a6a4-d57d40e47924",
    "front": "**Def**: produce a baby or young animal.\n**Farsi**: زایمان کردن، به دنیا آوردن",
    "back": "give birth"
  },
  {
    "id": "8c9b0083-62b0-44e5-a548-17a4dc0c38e7",
    "front": "**Def**: used to describe somebody who is in the same situation as you (fellow students/workers).\n**Farsi**: همکار، همتا، همراه‌",
    "back": "fellow"
  },
  {
    "id": "dc207e43-40b8-42f1-9e94-dd54f9d63c9c",
    "front": "**Def**: come together to help or support somebody/something.\n**Farsi**: بسیج شدن، گرد هم آمدن (برای کمک)",
    "back": "rally (round/to sb/sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "9602a176-8b74-4052-905e-772d14de0974",
    "front": "**Def**: support and agree with something/somebody (also be in favour of sth/sb).\n**Farsi**: طرفدار بودن، موافق بودن",
    "back": "favour with sth/sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "b97438e9-2b80-40df-83d8-62770b8b1f7a",
    "front": "**Def**: the existing situation (maintain the status quo).\n**Farsi**: وضعیت موجود",
    "back": "status quo"
  },
  {
    "id": "73775869-e7bd-47b1-98df-3c8b1257d583",
    "front": "**Def**: disagreeing strongly with something/somebody.\n**Farsi**: مخالف با",
    "back": "opposed to sth/sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "00f860af-f115-47fd-89f4-85f98dd9296b",
    "front": "**Def**: complete and fundamental (often implying major change).\n**Farsi**: رادیکال، بنیادی",
    "back": "radical"
  },
  {
    "id": "eb1185a5-7172-464c-9c94-7cfeb081846b",
    "front": "**Def**: share something among a number of people.\n**Farsi**: توزیع کردن",
    "back": "distribute sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "c75374e9-6b86-4bb9-ac6d-dc727c230d38",
    "front": "**Def**: in a way that is fair and the same for everyone.\n**Farsi**: به طور مساوی، عادلانه",
    "back": "equally"
  },
  {
    "id": "da19340e-e8dd-4096-89fb-761fabe452c4",
    "front": "**Def**: a person whose political views are generally not considered to be normal or reasonable (far-reaching).\n**Farsi**: افراطی چپ‌گرا",
    "back": "left-wing extremist"
  },
  {
    "id": "10ddb96c-505c-4cf6-a87d-83eb7b3be71e",
    "front": "**Def**: a political party that is not left-wing or right-wing (in the centre).\n**Farsi**: حزب میانه",
    "back": "centre party"
  },
  {
    "id": "eeba3dca-398e-40a7-b616-f3fac2d57cce",
    "front": "**Def**: a way of doing or achieving something (means of transport/communication).\n**Farsi**: ابزار، وسیله",
    "back": "means"
  },
  {
    "id": "07d4abab-88bc-4bb3-a50c-7f81d9946158",
    "front": "**Def**: the materials and equipment needed to produce things.\n**Farsi**: ابزارهای تولید",
    "back": "means of production"
  },
  {
    "id": "a4380f29-6020-467a-adff-73f9b2a22938",
    "front": "**Def**: a way of showing who you are.\n**Farsi**: شناسایی، مدرک هویت",
    "back": "identification"
  },
  {
    "id": "1738a118-f7a1-4a21-90c7-159ef1d61bbe",
    "front": "**Def**: a weakness in an idea, a system, or an organization.\n**Farsi**: ترک برداشتن (نشانه ضعف)",
    "back": "crack a line on the surface of sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "1c168a63-cc30-472c-90a8-1072daf84c71",
    "front": "**Def**: be in control of a situation (syn pull the strings).\n**Farsi**: در جایگاه هدایت، کنترل را در دست داشتن",
    "back": "driving seat"
  },
  {
    "id": "d661f156-5702-4b65-83dd-663880bca15b",
    "front": "**Def**: cause problems by making changes to a situation that is satisfactory as it is.\n**Farsi**: جنجال به پا کردن، وضعیت آرام را به هم زدن",
    "back": "rock the boat"
  },
  {
    "id": "aa3e4efc-f704-4716-9353-824763485edf",
    "front": "**Def**: create the basic ideas or principles from which something can then develop.\n**Farsi**: زیربنا نهادن، اصول اساسی را ایجاد کردن",
    "back": "foundations (lay the foundations)"
  },
  {
    "id": "8286d8dd-1f16-4a87-8605-a1778e02faeb",
    "front": "**Def**: be in a situation that is too difficult for you to control.\n**Farsi**: از عهده برنیامدن، خارج از عمق توانایی",
    "back": "depth (of sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "9fc91ede-483f-461a-9537-309b8084da79",
    "front": "**Def**: Made or became more intense or severe.\n**Farsi**: تشدید شده، تقویت شده",
    "back": "intensified"
  },
  {
    "id": "a7c1f780-1c18-49c9-9e62-3e29980e408b",
    "front": "**Def**: fail or succeed (without help).\n**Farsi**: شکست خوردن یا موفق شدن (به حال خود رها شدن)",
    "back": "sink or swim"
  },
  {
    "id": "80a1ceeb-a510-43f3-a783-d7119d55c7f1",
    "front": "**Def**: an angry discussion (also heated discussion).\n**Farsi**: داغ کردن بحث، بحث عصبانی",
    "back": "heat sth (make sth hot)"
  },
  {
    "id": "d870ae86-2ceb-4078-aa7f-4ecfea5c56e6",
    "front": "**Def**: a person you can rely on.\n**Farsi**: فرد قابل اعتماد",
    "back": "safe pair of hands"
  },
  {
    "id": "235df91a-c25a-476e-84ca-1d1ccf985d80",
    "front": "**Def**: making good progress.\n**Farsi**: در مسیر درست حرکت کردن",
    "back": "head (in a direction)"
  },
  {
    "id": "d9fb1761-83ff-4680-b4db-b9d43273de97",
    "front": "**Def**: being watched and examined very carefully (under the microscope).\n**Farsi**: زیر ذره‌بین بودن، با دقت بررسی شدن",
    "back": "microscope"
  },
  {
    "id": "8a692c58-8e4e-4e97-b294-8bc4bda131eb",
    "front": "**Def**: give information to make it appear better, or less bad.\n**Farsi**: چرخش خبری، مدیریت رسانه‌ای",
    "back": "spin"
  },
  {
    "id": "b6e28942-9ca6-431a-99cc-3139f1bf88db",
    "front": "**Def**: an area or region with a particular feature (a war/danger zone).\n**Farsi**: منطقه",
    "back": "zone"
  },
  {
    "id": "19d98a23-341c-4dc0-8ffd-66ad23f38e31",
    "front": "**Def**: broken stones or bricks from a building that has been destroyed.\n**Farsi**: آوار، نخاله",
    "back": "rubble"
  },
  {
    "id": "f50f8d8c-b162-44f1-965f-c7673500f599",
    "front": "**Def**: not readily available; in short supply.\n**Farsi**: کمیاب",
    "back": "scarce"
  },
  {
    "id": "1cb5da59-db2a-4f56-a8a4-42000324e6d6",
    "front": "**Def**: defeat somebody/something completely.\n**Farsi**: کاملاً شکست دادن، تحت تأثیر قرار دادن",
    "back": "overwhelm sb/sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "5db4ed5b-301b-4e24-bb3d-5141293ce0dd",
    "front": "**Def**: fire a metal case full of explosives, to be fired from a large gun.\n**Farsi**: گلوله توپ، خمپاره",
    "back": "shell"
  },
  {
    "id": "e3e28c23-6c7d-45f9-a895-22ab7d85a28c",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who shoots at somebody from a hidden position.\n**Farsi**: تک‌تیرانداز",
    "back": "sniper"
  },
  {
    "id": "cfc40fe9-04a9-49e0-9900-e60cc166b884",
    "front": "**Def**: happening without any intended or regular pattern.\n**Farsi**: تصادفی، بی‌هدف",
    "back": "random"
  },
  {
    "id": "70f41e5f-b649-405a-8b9a-3483fa055954",
    "front": "**Def**: the time when problems have become so great that somebody can no longer deal with them.\n**Farsi**: نقطه شکست، آستانه تحمل",
    "back": "breaking point"
  },
  {
    "id": "89b4d4bc-4556-4384-8af0-e9dd3d89f606",
    "front": "**Def**: go away from a place and leave it empty (syn abandon sth).\n**Farsi**: رها کردن، ترک کردن",
    "back": "desert sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "f3398238-54a3-472f-b687-bf7e5c35c5fa",
    "front": "**Def**: a substance secreted in the body when you are excited or afraid, giving you more energy.\n**Farsi**: آدرنالین",
    "back": "adrenaline"
  },
  {
    "id": "f4267f34-bf6c-4fd2-b044-4a34ddc4ec98",
    "front": "**Def**: a military operation in which an armed force surrounds a place and stops the supply of food, etc.\n**Farsi**: محاصره",
    "back": "siege"
  },
  {
    "id": "9a4083a3-badd-4b85-88b5-1687cc99e347",
    "front": "**Def**: To transfer (a business or industry) from public to private ownership.\n**Farsi**: خصوصی‌سازی کردن",
    "back": "privatize"
  },
  {
    "id": "12184383-3447-4060-a7d3-3774cc3cb020",
    "front": "**Def**: A room designed to prevent sound from entering or leaving.\n**Farsi**: اتاق ضد صدا",
    "back": "soundproof room"
  },
  {
    "id": "3b376035-1074-413b-ab3c-55c082bcf670",
    "front": "**Def**: Locks designed to prevent young children from opening them.\n**Farsi**: قفل کودک",
    "back": "childproof locks"
  },
  {
    "id": "090d3569-d893-4fe5-accf-3b87cde9bfa5",
    "front": "**Def**: Income that is not subject to tax.\n**Farsi**: درآمد معاف از مالیات",
    "back": "tax-free income"
  },
  {
    "id": "7bbc7502-3a58-434b-96d3-7a7a70e1038b",
    "front": "**Def**: A method incapable of going wrong or failing.\n**Farsi**: روش تضمینی، روش غیرقابل شکست",
    "back": "foolproof method"
  },
  {
    "id": "1de7a8db-7462-4329-b6f9-be128f5fe2d0",
    "front": "**Def**: Goods bought without paying the usual tax.\n**Farsi**: عطر بدون عوارض گمرکی",
    "back": "duty-free perfume"
  },
  {
    "id": "150e6b17-4de9-435e-9f2d-8bd9a574ca8b",
    "front": "**Def**: With no interest charged on borrowed money.\n**Farsi**: بدون بهره",
    "back": "interest-free"
  },
  {
    "id": "89094eed-afb4-49c9-b262-66718e27d28f",
    "front": "**Def**: Able to stop a bullet from penetrating.\n**Farsi**: ضد گلوله",
    "back": "bulletproof"
  },
  {
    "id": "7a53d373-9915-46eb-96ec-a802e88351d8",
    "front": "**Def**: Protected against loss of real value from inflation.\n**Farsi**: مقاوم در برابر تورم",
    "back": "inflation-proof"
  },
  {
    "id": "ded5bdd5-07b8-4138-8990-896970022e94",
    "front": "**Def**: To consider or think of someone or something as.\n**Farsi**: به حساب آوردن، تلقی کردن",
    "back": "regard (as)"
  },
  {
    "id": "cfe5063c-20df-4d61-b636-25e403748c5a",
    "front": "**Def**: A short passage taken from a text, film, or music.\n**Farsi**: گزیده، بخش جدا شده",
    "back": "extract/excerpt"
  },
  {
    "id": "32d21ce6-bcdd-4f84-9973-4a0d5130c70a",
    "front": "**Def**: A persistent feeling of ill will or resentment resulting from a past insult or injury.\n**Farsi**: کینه، دلخوری",
    "back": "grudge"
  },
  {
    "id": "298bfe41-1465-4d35-b902-bce585fc5dc4",
    "front": "restriction",
    "back": "**Def**: A limiting condition or measure.\n**Farsi**: محدودیت"
  },
  {
    "id": "d4d8de66-6b0c-4aff-9381-22e5912ba818",
    "front": "**Def**: A natural ability to do something.\n**Farsi**: استعداد، شایستگی",
    "back": "aptitude"
  },
  {
    "id": "18fa65bc-0397-4f2b-a415-bea8331e6143",
    "front": "**Def**: A person chosen or appointed to act or speak for another or others.\n**Farsi**: نماینده",
    "back": "representative"
  },
  {
    "id": "9595e0a3-9318-410f-928f-633519a7f094",
    "front": "**Def**: Contingent on or determined by.\n**Farsi**: وابسته",
    "back": "dependent"
  },
  {
    "id": "1edd76d1-2f41-4212-88c1-e67aea42606b",
    "front": "**Def**: Accepted (something unwelcome) without protest.\n**Farsi**: کنار آمده، پذیرفته شده",
    "back": "reconciled/resigned"
  },
  {
    "id": "86732613-f1be-42c3-8f9a-fd1324920944",
    "front": "**Def**: Resolved or determined to do something.\n**Farsi**: مصمم، متمرکز",
    "back": "intent"
  },
  {
    "id": "d40b8499-2dbf-4123-97ce-85f8c3c16d0f",
    "front": "**Def**: Offering opposition to something or someone.\n**Farsi**: مقاوم، مخالف",
    "back": "resistant"
  },
  {
    "id": "17ddc0af-2c79-41f1-b6fc-80b1e63a8567",
    "front": "**Def**: Originates or is caused by.\n**Farsi**: ناشی می‌شود از، سرچشمه می‌گیرد از",
    "back": "stems (from)"
  },
  {
    "id": "31d7134c-5940-45c4-ac6c-6fc94004acd8",
    "front": "**Def**: Tending to remind one of something.\n**Farsi**: یادآور، تداعی‌کننده",
    "back": "reminiscent (of)"
  },
  {
    "id": "c63da47c-7347-452c-8314-c13f57a3dec8",
    "front": "**Def**: As a substitute or equivalent for.\n**Farsi**: در ازای، در عوض",
    "back": "in exchange for"
  },
  {
    "id": "67531f22-a1ae-4431-beb2-fa756c22a145",
    "front": "**Def**: Being examined by authorities/believed to be guilty of a crime.\n**Farsi**: تحت بررسی/سوء ظن",
    "back": "under investigation/suspicion"
  },
  {
    "id": "0aa1e54c-05ef-4d26-9662-7916f4a6b6a1",
    "front": "**Def**: Having or owning something.\n**Farsi**: در اختیار داشتن، مالک بودن",
    "back": "in possession of"
  },
  {
    "id": "17bb13c0-8565-4ee8-8332-a70113974cdd",
    "front": "**Def**: In communication with (or having current information about).\n**Farsi**: در تماس",
    "back": "in touch"
  },
  {
    "id": "eb8c55fe-74d7-46f8-ae80-e4b1377539aa",
    "front": "**Def**: To postpone plans temporarily.\n**Farsi**: برنامه‌ها را به حالت تعلیق درآوردن",
    "back": "put our holiday plans on hold"
  },
  {
    "id": "ae56a9e2-2bdb-4256-95e1-4ccddc2af246",
    "front": "**Def**: To show honor or regard for.\n**Farsi**: به احترام، به پاس",
    "back": "out of respect for"
  },
  {
    "id": "d4475a46-9ece-427f-ad0f-4597a3f0b2fa",
    "front": "**Def**: Not having current knowledge or information about something.\n**Farsi**: بی‌اطلاع بودن از",
    "back": "out of touch with"
  },
  {
    "id": "b93521fb-c48b-4be9-80c4-f3a4ee93d6e2",
    "front": "**Def**: Using a particular method or agency.\n**Farsi**: به وسیله، از طریق",
    "back": "by means of"
  },
  {
    "id": "8c4eaa62-7bdd-402c-a8e2-04c9ee8dc15a",
    "front": "**Def**: Not visible; hidden.\n**Farsi**: ناپدید، دور از چشم",
    "back": "out of sight"
  },
  {
    "id": "42f98bd1-a2df-478b-a579-d5ca2c22c6e2",
    "front": "**Def**: Famous or well known, typically for some bad quality or deed.\n**Farsi**: بدنام، معروف به بدی",
    "back": "notorious/infamous"
  },
  {
    "id": "27161c20-e985-41fc-8eef-01e9fa991f39",
    "front": "**Def**: In low spirits from loss of hope or courage.\n**Farsi**: افسرده، ناامید",
    "back": "despondent"
  },
  {
    "id": "9cd1974f-fb60-41b6-b817-b4f5cfedd98a",
    "front": "**Def**: Without clothes or covering.\n**Farsi**: برهنه، عریان",
    "back": "naked bare (nude)"
  },
  {
    "id": "e7ef6211-4c72-45a0-8579-483b6db0aa29",
    "front": "**Def**: Having positive qualities associated with a child (innocence)/having negative qualities associated with a child (immaturity).\n**Farsi**: کودکانه (مثبت)/بچه گانه (منفی)",
    "back": "childlike/childish"
  },
  {
    "id": "ddb24a01-ac46-4748-a19b-4c6a3c4b9842",
    "front": "**Def**: Extremely useful/having no value or use.\n**Farsi**: بسیار با ارزش/بی ارزش",
    "back": "invaluable/worthless/valueless"
  },
  {
    "id": "00d8905b-fd69-468d-9e43-f25bc715450d",
    "front": "**Def**: Failing to take proper care/so small or unimportant as to be disregarded.\n**Farsi**: بی‌توجه، سهل‌انگار/ناچیز، قابل اغماض",
    "back": "negligent/negligible"
  },
  {
    "id": "a96e85d5-eb5c-43dd-b75f-8724280e6eb5",
    "front": "**Def**: Clearly; obviously (used to indicate what is apparent).\n**Farsi**: بدیهی است، واضحاً",
    "back": "Evidently"
  },
  {
    "id": "4f760ba8-b61a-41ed-9bd8-725e69259bb0",
    "front": "**Def**: Used to suggest that a fact is surprising.\n**Farsi**: به اندازه کافی عجیب، به شکل عجیبی",
    "back": "curiously/strangely/oddly enough"
  },
  {
    "id": "d51c7d30-25fd-4f92-861b-c50a61492c67",
    "front": "**Def**: Used to indicate that one is stating one's honest opinion.\n**Farsi**: صادقانه، شخصاً",
    "back": "frankly/personally"
  },
  {
    "id": "ec101838-21b6-4092-82f2-c6309f412e3b",
    "front": "**Def**: In terms of money or business.\n**Farsi**: از نظر مالی/تجاری",
    "back": "Financially/Commercially (speaking)"
  },
  {
    "id": "70357986-fbea-4a7d-9d58-30b8e81f11f8",
    "front": "**Def**: Used to give your opinion on something.\n**Farsi**: تا آنجا که به من مربوط است",
    "back": "concerned (as far as I'm)"
  },
  {
    "id": "8c2787e9-7384-4313-becc-4f8032a5764b",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning put oneself deliberately into a place or situation where one is unwelcome or uninvited.\n**Farsi**: مزاحم شدن، تجاوز کردن",
    "back": "intrude"
  },
  {
    "id": "ded1d839-73d1-4aeb-bf60-7a8155e8b053",
    "front": "**Def**: To a certain degree; comparatively.\n**Farsi**: نسبتاً، تا حدودی",
    "back": "relatively/somewhat"
  },
  {
    "id": "cac0b486-5c58-4735-922c-c2a5bd0bf1c9",
    "front": "**Def**: Only; merely; for no other reason.\n**Farsi**: صرفاً، فقط",
    "back": "simply/purely"
  },
  {
    "id": "98bc1830-6fff-4193-8b7f-7c1ff0a764d3",
    "front": "**Def**: Mainly; mostly.\n**Farsi**: عمدتاً، در اصل",
    "back": "primarily/chiefly/predominantly"
  },
  {
    "id": "56192ecd-4deb-4338-a1dd-a12703a6cab9",
    "front": "**Def**: To dismiss someone from employment; to sack (euphemism).\n**Farsi**: اخراج کردن، مرخص کردن (با احترام)",
    "back": "let him go"
  },
  {
    "id": "419c3f19-dba5-4135-934b-34170c0c7574",
    "front": "**Def**: Died (euphemism).\n**Farsi**: فوت کردن، درگذشتن",
    "back": "passed away"
  },
  {
    "id": "14d68a2b-2699-4e5c-9fe7-3027c64ad4b5",
    "front": "**Def**: To euthanize an animal (euphemism).\n**Farsi**: خواباندن (اوتانایز حیوان)",
    "back": "put it to sleep"
  },
  {
    "id": "5c8404f9-611a-424e-ba04-188308bc922b",
    "front": "**Def**: Weakened or damaged (often related to sight or mobility) (euphemism).\n**Farsi**: مختل، آسیب دیده",
    "back": "impaired"
  },
  {
    "id": "9e889ab1-d5b3-41c2-b27b-ac130ed51fa6",
    "front": "**Def**: To take something, often without permission (euphemism for steal).\n**Farsi**: برداشتن چیزی (بدون اجازه)",
    "back": "help herself to"
  },
  {
    "id": "3f6af8ad-6c23-456e-be54-5c4be1667b26",
    "front": "**Def**: To euthanize an animal.\n**Farsi**: یوتانایز کردن (حیوان)",
    "back": "put down (an animal)"
  },
  {
    "id": "a663ec70-618a-41e2-9695-99960473c89e",
    "front": "**Def**: Getting old (euphemism).\n**Farsi**: پیر شدن، مسن شدن",
    "back": "getting on"
  },
  {
    "id": "70913276-d3b3-440c-af33-7338a0c0d781",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning against something.\n**Farsi**: مخالف",
    "back": "opposed"
  },
  {
    "id": "bf613f5a-0523-4d2b-98fb-b403f7b35537",
    "front": "**Def**: To defeat or succeed in dealing with a problem or difficulty.\n**Farsi**: غلبه کردن، فائق آمدن",
    "back": "overcome"
  },
  {
    "id": "6a15db35-d099-4c43-8966-7240ca7ffe25",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the state of having, owning, or controlling something.\n**Farsi**: تملک، دارایی",
    "back": "possession"
  },
  {
    "id": "17c5d48d-c412-459f-b763-67e9a4c982ce",
    "front": "**Def**: To succeed in doing something, but only by a very small margin.\n**Farsi**: به سختی قبول شدن/رد شدن",
    "back": "scrape/get through"
  },
  {
    "id": "238f11a2-7c2c-41db-a939-443feea87bb0",
    "front": "**Def**: Tricked or defrauded (informal).\n**Farsi**: فریب داده شده، سرش کلاه رفته",
    "back": "conned"
  },
  {
    "id": "065021e3-1032-462f-8994-11b68a8467d8",
    "front": "humiliated",
    "back": "**Def**: feeling ashamed because you have lost the respect of other people. humiliate sb v. humiliation N.\n**Farsi**: تحقیرشده، خجالت‌زده"
  },
  {
    "id": "d45f2f6d-ea7e-4877-82a8-4e8253f95ce3",
    "front": "**Def**: selling very quickly or in large numbers.\n**Farsi**: مثل برق فروخته شدن/پرطرفدار بودن",
    "back": "selling like hot cakes"
  },
  {
    "id": "9163816f-a9bf-45aa-b0ca-7e4e86ab7d16",
    "front": "**Def**: buildings for people to live in.\n**Farsi**: مسکن، خانه‌سازی",
    "back": "housing (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "629ffd3f-50ae-4ad6-a24d-2b2b8cb94958",
    "front": "**Def**: To give a brief statement of the main points of something.\n**Farsi**: خلاصه کردن، جمع‌بندی کردن",
    "back": "sum up / summarize"
  },
  {
    "id": "7dffaaa9-6463-49c1-9f43-43c60d426ed1",
    "front": "**Def**: behave towards sb as if you find them sexually attractive, but not in a serious way.\n**Farsi**: لاس زدن، عشوه آمدن",
    "back": "flirt (with sb) (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "85c716e5-4e90-4414-a538-c18d59ff3120",
    "front": "**Def**: make a decision about sth too quickly, before you have thought about all the facts. SYN leap to conclusions.\n**Farsi**: نتیجه‌گیری عجولانه کردن",
    "back": "jump to conclusions (PHR)"
  },
  {
    "id": "412e0670-88c1-49fa-a44e-be89207bd3f8",
    "front": "**Def**: walk with difficulty, being almost unable to stand up.\n**Farsi**: تلوتلو خوردن",
    "back": "stagger (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "ca69f23b-8231-4cd2-a22f-02f5ddc844a7",
    "front": "گیرا، قانه‌کننده)از دید احساسی(",
    "back": "Compelling "
  },
  {
    "id": "682293b8-d7a1-4182-bff8-6e24bc581acb",
    "front": "**Def**: continuous attention/looking after.\n**Farsi**: مراقبت مداوم",
    "back": "constant care"
  },
  {
    "id": "4dbae7de-4f5e-450d-a229-726b2d05b0de",
    "front": "1️⃣ To remove or form something by cutting — «تراشیدن»\n\n2️⃣ To create or reserve something for yourself — «اختصاص دادن» یا «جایگاه ساختن برای خود»",
    "back": "He carved out a piece of wood to make a bowl.\nShe managed to carve out a niche in the design industry."
  },
  {
    "id": "b108a20b-5b91-4dc5-bd07-ef9628fc6d57",
    "front": "معنی: خلافِ شهود، برخلاف انتظار یا منطق معمول (در فارسی)\nMeaning: something that goes against what you would normally expect or believe to be true (in English)",
    "back": "\nCounterintuitive /ˌkaʊn.tər.ɪnˈtjuː.ɪ.tɪv/ — Example: “It may seem counterintuitive, but taking breaks can actually increase productivity.” — Formal/Academic"
  },
  {
    "id": "a5342fdd-ab27-4d5e-98d4-e7f98fa60f34",
    "front": "**Def**: Communicated (a message or information).\n**Farsi**: منتقل شده، رسانده شده",
    "back": "conveyed"
  },
  {
    "id": "70b63905-22ff-4e28-949c-8fe2af925a8f",
    "front": "معنی: کاهش دادن، سبک کردن، کم کردن شدت چیزی (در فارسی)\nMeaning: to make something less severe, harmful, or painful (in English",
    "back": "Mitigate /ˈmɪt.ɪ.ɡeɪt/ — Example: “The government took steps to mitigate the effects of inflation.” — Formal"
  },
  {
    "id": "b87f9b51-50c6-4abe-aecb-5ee8afce2814",
    "front": "**Def**: no negative consequence if you fail.\n**Farsi**: چیزی برای از دست دادن نداشتن",
    "back": "nothing to lose"
  },
  {
    "id": "8511e8f9-290d-47c1-88c7-a9e607704aa0",
    "front": "\nمعنی: دنبال کردن، پیگیری کردن، تعقیب کردن (در فارسی)\nMeaning: to follow, chase, or try to achieve something over a period of time (in English)\n\n\n",
    "back": "Pursue /pərˈsuː/ — Example: “She decided to pursue a career in medicine.” — Neutral (often formal in academic/professional use)"
  },
  {
    "id": "54950e9c-6747-47d3-a495-996cabeda707",
    "front": "**Def**: The state of being successful, especially financially.\n**Farsi**: رونق، رفاه، کامیابی",
    "back": "prosperity"
  },
  {
    "id": "67a0343f-e28e-4157-964f-4e539ea5c43d",
    "front": "**Def**: If sth dawns on you, you begin to realize it for the first time.\n**Farsi**: متوجه شدن، دریافتن",
    "back": "dawn on sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "2d12f4b0-2bff-412b-bdd4-0aeb6666e748",
    "front": "**Def**: a number of benefits that are offered together.\n**Farsi**: بسته مزایای شغلی",
    "back": "benefits package"
  },
  {
    "id": "d357f472-10b6-4cc3-89cd-e3e673af5de9",
    "front": "**Def**: money paid to sb to help them, either on a regular basis or for a particular purpose (food/fuel allowance).\n**Farsi**: کمک هزینه نقل مکان",
    "back": "relocation allowance"
  },
  {
    "id": "c621d9e9-8e18-458d-bba3-6aa077343ad9",
    "front": "**Def**: linked to how well sb does in their job.\n**Farsi**: مرتبط با عملکرد",
    "back": "performance-related"
  },
  {
    "id": "22531756-f0f3-4df2-a5dd-a43345f0605d",
    "front": "**Def**: extra money paid to sb, often annually or as a reward for sth. scheme an official plan.\n**Farsi**: طرح پاداش",
    "back": "bonus scheme"
  },
  {
    "id": "2fef14ca-17fa-42a8-bfca-148f3457214f",
    "front": "**Def**: money paid regularly by a company to help sb when they retire (also government pension or personal/private pension).\n**Farsi**: طرح بازنشستگی شرکت",
    "back": "company pension scheme"
  },
  {
    "id": "ffc5252b-38f1-4181-b207-a87ccdf9d669",
    "front": "**Def**: a period when a woman temporarily leaves her job to have a baby.\n**Farsi**: مرخصی زایمان",
    "back": "maternity leave"
  },
  {
    "id": "0ae8ef33-db16-4169-8abf-9f875b4f05b3",
    "front": "**Def**: a short period off work allowed to a new father.\n**Farsi**: مرخصی پدری",
    "back": "paternity leave"
  },
  {
    "id": "82aa9143-9020-42be-b8de-f2f60f9bdd25",
    "front": "**Def**: the money sb spends while working that the employer pays back to them later (travel/travelling expenses).\n**Farsi**: هزینه‌ها (قابل بازپرداخت)",
    "back": "expenses"
  },
  {
    "id": "616bc87f-b759-4dbb-9e60-2d1e4421f084",
    "front": "**Def**: a thing sb has a right to (often expressed as an amount sb has a right to receive). be entitled to sth v.\n**Farsi**: حق ۳۰ روز مرخصی",
    "back": "30 days' holiday entitlement"
  },
  {
    "id": "1e9fbd35-685a-4f37-90be-3308d605eac5",
    "front": "**Def**: If sth is subsidized, it is partly paid for by an organization in order to make it cheaper for the people who use it. canteen a place where food is served in a company or school.\n**Farsi**: سلف سرویس یارانه‌ای",
    "back": "subsidized canteen"
  },
  {
    "id": "394921cf-30dd-4505-b579-4e796dcda868",
    "front": "**Def**: the advantages and disadvantages/drawbacks.\n**Farsi**: مزایا و معایب",
    "back": "the pros and cons"
  },
  {
    "id": "968c8526-929a-450c-a8b5-61f960f193ef",
    "front": "**Def**: expected to explain all your actions to sb if asked (if you are not accountable to anyone you are your own boss).\n**Farsi**: پاسخگو بودن به کسی",
    "back": "accountable to sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "21efdb74-c9c5-49bb-8171-c1a95ebeba59",
    "front": "**Def**: a clear understanding of what sth is like.\n**Farsi**: بینش نسبت به چیزی",
    "back": "insight into sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "8d4787fb-2a9a-4774-9393-f9d41367ae0f",
    "front": "**Def**: producing a large amount of money.\n**Farsi**: سودآور، پرمنفعت",
    "back": "lucrative"
  },
  {
    "id": "3b1582cf-e303-4321-9d5b-1ab4f0c72035",
    "front": "**Def**: only; not involving sb/sth else (be solely responsible for sth).\n**Farsi**: منحصراً، صرفاً",
    "back": "solely"
  },
  {
    "id": "f7e17e3e-9a33-4910-9864-7de537eed525",
    "front": "**Def**: try to manage and balance different jobs and activities in order to fit them successfully into your life.\n**Farsi**: همزمان چند کار را مدیریت کردن، موازنه کردن",
    "back": "juggle sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "4aaf2f1c-165e-44ee-8994-9005b069f4a2",
    "front": "**Def**: promise that sth will happen. guarantee N.\n**Farsi**: تضمین کردن",
    "back": "guarantee sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "266804d7-28e9-4857-a5ee-53198d352656",
    "front": "**Def**: more than has been experienced or mentioned before. SYNS extra, further.\n**Farsi**: اضافی، بیشتر",
    "back": "additional"
  },
  {
    "id": "d3c73df2-3059-496d-8612-b954b4bddb7b",
    "front": "**Def**: experience sth, especially problems or opposition.\n**Farsi**: مواجه شدن با چیزی",
    "back": "encounter sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "b4e9e59a-b54d-4c6c-b373-c89dc6259105",
    "front": "**Def**: FML affect or use up too much of sb's time, rights, personal life, etc.\n**Farsi**: تجاوز کردن به (زمان، حقوق و غیره)",
    "back": "encroach upon sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "c91331ea-4a4e-4847-a6fa-d85ce70450a4",
    "front": "**Def**: A degree of sth is a certain level or amount of sth, and it is commonly used in certain expressions or patterns.\n**Farsi**: میزان، درجه",
    "back": "degree"
  },
  {
    "id": "2061922b-1e70-4702-9758-9afe02ef4f4f",
    "front": "**Def**: a goal shared by two or more people.\n**Farsi**: هدف مشترک",
    "back": "common goal"
  },
  {
    "id": "313bf59a-ce8a-4872-a784-3256296280de",
    "front": "**Def**: the feeling of confidence and enthusiasm that a person or group has at a particular time (boost morale = improve morale).\n**Farsi**: روحیه، مورال",
    "back": "morale"
  },
  {
    "id": "888cf8d2-83a0-4a32-847c-0ebc3e479e85",
    "front": "**Def**: help sth to develop. SYNS encourage sth, promote sth.\n**Farsi**: تقویت کردن، پروراندن",
    "back": "foster sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "5d9bc836-3645-4d17-961e-0d0102173c1f",
    "front": "**Def**: the desire among a group to work together and help each other.\n**Farsi**: روحیه تیمی",
    "back": "team spirit"
  },
  {
    "id": "9cab1e39-f8cc-425a-9412-b46f6a378e88",
    "front": "**Def**: the act of working with others to produce sth.\n**Farsi**: همکاری",
    "back": "collaboration (with sb)"
  },
  {
    "id": "4d8db3a7-00a2-4b5f-9a74-e587506e7438",
    "front": "**Def**: used to describe a feeling that two people have for each other equally (mutual respect/trust).\n**Farsi**: متقابل، دوطرفه",
    "back": "mutual"
  },
  {
    "id": "7eda0fc0-8cf3-4c46-aeb3-3a8dbbacde5c",
    "front": "**Def**: giving personal satisfaction. SYN rewarding.\n**Farsi**: رضایت‌بخش، ارضاکننده",
    "back": "fulfilling"
  },
  {
    "id": "475951d8-4d8e-4ac8-b5ed-6462e6d16835",
    "front": "**Def**: think that sb/sth is important.\n**Farsi**: قدر قائل شدن، ارزش قائل شدن برای",
    "back": "value sb/sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "7f8b6fa7-c72d-4848-9835-502bff6635c5",
    "front": "**Def**: collect money, ideas, etc. from different people so it or they can be used by all of them (pool resources).\n**Farsi**: جمع‌آوری و به اشتراک گذاشتن (منابع، ایده‌ها)",
    "back": "pool sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "c025c44a-32c2-4f71-987a-7e83574f86ae",
    "front": "**Def**: be accepted in a situation by the others in a group.\n**Farsi**: جا افتادن، وفق دادن خود",
    "back": "fit in (with sb/sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b50a2bc0-a338-4019-ae9d-e49c69891098",
    "front": "**Def**: causing problems, and making it hard to continue with sth. disrupt sth v.\n**Farsi**: اخلال‌گر، مختل‌کننده",
    "back": "disruptive"
  },
  {
    "id": "6a249a23-60c6-40e5-8b35-4ad2573fbe85",
    "front": "**Def**: make sb/sth gradually weaker or less effective (undermine sb's confidence/authority).\n**Farsi**: تضعیف کردن، از بین بردن",
    "back": "undermine sb/sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "6789d058-d762-4fe8-b58d-879baab950e5",
    "front": "**Def**: stop sth from happening or developing (stifle creativity).\n**Farsi**: خفه کردن، سرکوب کردن",
    "back": "stifle sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "8d7a0d01-d075-4ba4-93d2-27805f089391",
    "front": "**Def**: the ability to take decisions and act alone (use your initiative).\n**Farsi**: ابتکار، پیشقدمی",
    "back": "initiative"
  },
  {
    "id": "eef16d25-afb3-427a-ad3a-a0ba7bfc049b",
    "front": "**Def**: likely to happen soon.\n**Farsi**: قریب‌الوقوع، حتمی",
    "back": "imminent"
  },
  {
    "id": "06c6ab33-b086-4cad-b262-623b4af91905",
    "front": "**Def**: having a particular position in the past (former president/boss).\n**Farsi**: سابق، پیشین",
    "back": "former"
  },
  {
    "id": "16ec378b-484d-4bf7-b8ca-90628461e21d",
    "front": "**Def**: organize and begin sth (mount a challenge/campaign).\n**Farsi**: ترتیب دادن، آغاز کردن",
    "back": "mount sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "01363981-18b8-4f16-b904-6cd3b0c6a979",
    "front": "**Def**: involving two or more people (joint account/venture). jointly ADV.\n**Farsi**: مشترک",
    "back": "joint"
  },
  {
    "id": "f32b303c-c143-4d59-88dd-fffb9c0c50a3",
    "front": "**Def**: an offer to pay a particular price for sth (make a bid for sth). bid v.\n**Farsi**: پیشنهاد (خرید)",
    "back": "bid"
  },
  {
    "id": "8bd9ddd8-0288-4e92-9c89-cf9921003058",
    "front": "**Def**: help. SYN support. back sb/sth v.\n**Farsi**: حمایت، پشتیبانی",
    "back": "backing"
  },
  {
    "id": "fd02e7fa-8460-42b5-a85a-f0106e36dff6",
    "front": "**Def**: refuse to accept sth. SYN turn sth down. rejection N.\n**Farsi**: رد کردن",
    "back": "reject sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "ef19a3ed-d0e7-4129-b575-16e22c9e940a",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who owns shares in a business or company.\n**Farsi**: سهامدار",
    "back": "shareholder"
  },
  {
    "id": "72aecf57-1ce5-46f2-839c-48cbf7908f84",
    "front": "**Def**: a portion of a company's profits that is given to shareholders.\n**Farsi**: سود سهام، عایدی",
    "back": "dividend"
  },
  {
    "id": "0aa30ca7-f4a5-487a-bf89-0b13422716b8",
    "front": "**Def**: succeed in achieving or winning sth (clinch a deal/victory).\n**Farsi**: قطعی کردن، به دست آوردن",
    "back": "clinch sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "4f1ee817-5e3e-4d3d-877d-3803e29afb24",
    "front": "**Def**: start a process or series of events.\n**Farsi**: به راه انداختن، آغاز کردن",
    "back": "set sth off"
  },
  {
    "id": "82552136-392e-4a67-8f32-fe9a51fcf0ba",
    "front": "**Def**: two companies agree to join and form a single company.\n**Farsi**: ادغام",
    "back": "merger"
  },
  {
    "id": "19114449-72d2-4906-a115-d08ae039f7ac",
    "front": "**Def**: one company buys the shares of another public company.\n**Farsi**: تملک، تصاحب (شرکت)",
    "back": "takeover"
  },
  {
    "id": "d905d2cb-4f2b-47a4-8bc3-347086ecc7d1",
    "front": "**Def**: one company buys another company which cannot offer its shares for sale to the public.\n**Farsi**: خریداری (شرکت)",
    "back": "acquisition"
  },
  {
    "id": "85dc80e9-4293-4e6d-8773-bdbccf1cf492",
    "front": "**Def**: The companies may or may not agree to the deal. If they agree, it is a friendly takeover.\n**Farsi**: تملک دوستانه",
    "back": "friendly takeover"
  },
  {
    "id": "be077e38-17ef-4ed2-a0ba-46a9e5651dd2",
    "front": "**Def**: If they do not agree, it is a hostile takeover.\n**Farsi**: تملک خصمانه",
    "back": "hostile takeover"
  },
  {
    "id": "0edf1bca-766d-4b0e-920a-5630980c84a2",
    "front": "**Def**: INF go out of business. SYN go bankrupt.\n**Farsi**: ورشکست شدن، از بین رفتن",
    "back": "go under"
  },
  {
    "id": "a0051250-8176-491d-a191-b02ae05d9ccb",
    "front": "**Def**: stop running a business and close it completely.\n**Farsi**: منحل کردن (شرکت)",
    "back": "wind sth up"
  },
  {
    "id": "d9161139-60bb-48b0-8df0-c96101afbda8",
    "front": "**Def**: leave an important job.\n**Farsi**: کنار رفتن، استعفا دادن",
    "back": "step down/aside"
  },
  {
    "id": "6b2772d1-496b-438d-9dee-482c523e3676",
    "front": "**Def**: take a particular course of action.\n**Farsi**: آن مسیر خاص را دنبال کردن",
    "back": "go down that road"
  },
  {
    "id": "2bf4cdda-eed8-4ae8-8846-2f39ad0b6a2b",
    "front": "**Def**: INF, DISAPPROVING avoid doing sth that you should do.\n**Farsi**: شانه خالی کردن از زیر چیزی",
    "back": "wriggle out of sth / doing sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "f74592a6-5290-421a-ac14-76faa2f0ec5b",
    "front": "**Def**: DISAPPROVING persuade or tempt sb to do sth by offering them a reward. SYN entice sb.\n**Farsi**: اغوا کردن، وسوسه کردن",
    "back": "lure sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "17eada44-e112-4062-8bed-72bfaaa20113",
    "front": "**Def**: not accept a bad situation without a fight or protest.\n**Farsi**: بی‌تفاوت نماندن، اعتراض کردن",
    "back": "not take sth lying down"
  },
  {
    "id": "e9f8efae-6fcf-4210-99e2-52662c3fcd42",
    "front": "**Def**: affect the result of sth in one way rather than another.\n**Farsi**: تعادل را بر هم زدن، نتیجه را تغییر دادن",
    "back": "tip the balance"
  },
  {
    "id": "626d514e-d5f7-4723-8c7d-e7f2e5096673",
    "front": "**Def**: increase sth and make it stronger (fuel fears/inflation).\n**Farsi**: دامن زدن به، تشدید کردن",
    "back": "fuel sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "79d6d8ce-faac-488c-abe3-bcf87f9266c9",
    "front": "**Def**: the situation becomes clearer and less disturbed.\n**Farsi**: آرام شدن اوضاع، فرو نشستن گرد و غبار",
    "back": "the dust settles"
  },
  {
    "id": "a3212136-a605-4d3a-878a-20a7f294617d",
    "front": "**Def**: rise suddenly and quickly. SYN rocket.\n**Farsi**: اوج گرفتن، جهش کردن",
    "back": "soar"
  },
  {
    "id": "fc79c951-8c6f-4a8c-b9ce-09f642715240",
    "front": "**Def**: a large and sudden increase in the amount or value of sth. surge v.\n**Farsi**: افزایش ناگهانی، موج",
    "back": "surge (in sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "dffded35-55a4-453c-8d8b-7c43fd8656b7",
    "front": "**Def**: an improvement or increase. OPP loss.\n**Farsi**: افزایش، سود",
    "back": "gain"
  },
  {
    "id": "64cb13ed-d5ec-4510-b05d-606a34acc49b",
    "front": "**Def**: INF a sudden or significant increase in the level or amount of sth. OPP cut.\n**Farsi**: افزایش شدید و ناگهانی",
    "back": "hike"
  },
  {
    "id": "e849d350-e959-483b-ae19-39e93607f6bb",
    "front": "**Def**: become stronger. OPP weaken.\n**Farsi**: تقویت شدن",
    "back": "strengthen"
  },
  {
    "id": "1946c82b-e5fa-47a0-8655-f4ef2d95df5a",
    "front": "**Def**: increase in value after a period when it has fallen. SYN recover / bounce back.\n**Farsi**: بازگشت (ارزش)، افزایش دوباره",
    "back": "rally"
  },
  {
    "id": "51a33fbe-4d68-4e33-8baa-8d6bf0964e88",
    "front": "**Def**: confident, successful, and staying at a high level. SYN healthy.\n**Farsi**: پررونق، با نشاط",
    "back": "buoyant"
  },
  {
    "id": "bf8f9ec5-01d4-45bb-8bb3-ff8449e1ebf7",
    "front": "**Def**: buy sth quickly, usually while it is cheap or available.\n**Farsi**: سریع خریدن، قاپیدن",
    "back": "snap sth up"
  },
  {
    "id": "c1173b31-88c3-46cb-84dd-24b519ecfd72",
    "front": "**Def**: fall suddenly and quickly. SYN plunge.\n**Farsi**: سقوط کردن، به شدت کاهش یافتن",
    "back": "plummet"
  },
  {
    "id": "235db595-449d-4fc9-bb22-7159c32b3eb6",
    "front": "**Def**: fall by a large amount. slump N (economic slump OPP economic boom).\n**Farsi**: سقوط شدید، رکود",
    "back": "slump"
  },
  {
    "id": "87fd9c1e-aef5-4951-814e-c856cf117db0",
    "front": "**Def**: reduce sth by a large amount.\n**Farsi**: به شدت کاهش دادن",
    "back": "slash sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "3e8be685-c11c-432c-bc74-132ad28da420",
    "front": "**Def**: remove sth from sth, quickly and completely.\n**Farsi**: حذف کردن، از بین بردن (مقدار پول)",
    "back": "wipe sth off sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "26ccc55b-c5c8-4130-b6a4-c88d84838741",
    "front": "**Def**: a state of great confusion.\n**Farsi**: آشفتگی، هرج و مرج",
    "back": "turmoil"
  },
  {
    "id": "fa29285b-d0c6-46f0-a8dd-c32204a311ec",
    "front": "**Def**: likely to change suddenly. volatility N.\n**Farsi**: بی‌ثبات، نوسان‌پذیر",
    "back": "volatile"
  },
  {
    "id": "f09d21af-1099-43b1-b7df-dd1e002854ec",
    "front": "**Def**: a lot of sudden change (also a bumpy ride INF). turbulent ADJ.\n**Farsi**: تلاطم، نوسانات شدید",
    "back": "turbulence"
  },
  {
    "id": "c2dc705d-e040-4e52-bc59-171d1a761b68",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who buys land, shares, etc. in order to make a profit. invest v.\n**Farsi**: سرمایه‌گذار",
    "back": "investor"
  },
  {
    "id": "25822321-9790-4238-8a50-45ffce50ae42",
    "front": "**Def**: saying two different and opposing things. SYN conflicting. contradiction N. contradict sb/sth v.\n**Farsi**: متناقض، ضد و نقیض",
    "back": "contradictory"
  },
  {
    "id": "1f653875-d3fe-4543-b822-45a3cfe87528",
    "front": "**Def**: PL company shares which do not pay a fixed rate of interest.\n**Farsi**: سهام (شرکت‌ها)",
    "back": "equities"
  },
  {
    "id": "cc52eb3c-82ab-4474-8f6a-34314dee010d",
    "front": "**Def**: support or form the basis of sth.\n**Farsi**: تقویت کردن، زیربنا قرار دادن",
    "back": "underpin sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "985985f0-844d-411a-9682-0d7df4a9f2c0",
    "front": "**Def**: connected with a large business company. corporation N.\n**Farsi**: شرکتی، مربوط به شرکت‌های بزرگ",
    "back": "corporate"
  },
  {
    "id": "ea3d5cd7-d7c9-4582-bea8-ebd3d82bc578",
    "front": "**Def**: the responsibility of having to pay back a lot of money.\n**Farsi**: بار بدهی",
    "back": "debt burden"
  },
  {
    "id": "827710fe-5a9a-453e-a45f-68f0e696b5bf",
    "front": "**Def**: the total profit or income you get from a business or investment.\n**Farsi**: بازده، سود",
    "back": "yield"
  },
  {
    "id": "3d5ddce9-801f-4775-8a68-f039929550ec",
    "front": "**Def**: (in finance) An underlying number or situation shows what the true amount or level of sth is.\n**Farsi**: اساسی، زمینه‌ای",
    "back": "underlying"
  },
  {
    "id": "9f5a37fa-af47-42b9-b8d1-91b6dec756c7",
    "front": "**Def**: the probable future for sth.\n**Farsi**: چشم‌انداز، آینده محتمل",
    "back": "outlook"
  },
  {
    "id": "67eff5a8-cc18-41f1-aa18-74489220c0d9",
    "front": "**Def**: (in finance) a temporary and fragile situation caused by a rapid increase in sth (the bubble will burst = the situation will end, and people will lose money).\n**Farsi**: حباب (مالی)",
    "back": "bubble"
  },
  {
    "id": "07f13156-c1b7-42c8-8f77-4a945d0eb345",
    "front": "**Def**: If sth dries up, there is gradually less and less of it.\n**Farsi**: خشک شدن، تمام شدن (منابع)",
    "back": "dry up"
  },
  {
    "id": "472069b3-1acd-4ba5-bc12-89598489cfc4",
    "front": "**Def**: cause sth to happen.\n**Farsi**: به راه انداختن، باعث شدن",
    "back": "trigger sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "38480b72-afc7-44de-826d-b47d9358ba31",
    "front": "**Def**: PL the money a person or business has to spend regularly. OPP income.\n**Farsi**: مخارج، هزینه‌ها",
    "back": "outgoings"
  },
  {
    "id": "96f25fb0-7740-4e1a-9f07-1cc14451fa15",
    "front": "**Def**: a plastic card used for taking money directly from your bank account.\n**Farsi**: کارت بانکی (بدهی)",
    "back": "debit card"
  },
  {
    "id": "d3f1dc77-6161-4af1-bf30-fe7115950373",
    "front": "**Def**: defeat sb very heavily (often used when talking about sport). (SYN thrash sb).\n**Farsi**: کسی را به سختی شکست دادن",
    "back": "hammer sb (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "ad2ed41a-fa37-4497-b1d0-a2efaf1cf749",
    "front": "**Def**: not have information about what is happening or where sth/sb is. OPP keep track of sth/sb.\n**Farsi**: رد چیزی را گم کردن، بی‌اطلاع بودن",
    "back": "lose track of sth/sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "83695ccf-d304-4b69-9461-33e475e180d9",
    "front": "**Def**: If you are in credit, there is money in your account. OPP overdrawn / in the red INF.\n**Farsi**: بستانکار، دارای موجودی",
    "back": "credit"
  },
  {
    "id": "f32ec446-1529-4aa4-be3f-d693822346ad",
    "front": "**Def**: increase gradually in size. SYN build up/accumulate.\n**Farsi**: تلنبار شدن، انباشته شدن",
    "back": "mount up"
  },
  {
    "id": "7a8a11d4-5a5d-4000-baf2-2f1fd33fb19a",
    "front": "**Def**: a piece of business between people.\n**Farsi**: تراکنش، معامله",
    "back": "transaction"
  },
  {
    "id": "c99d0453-4e30-4cc0-a54b-cdfc6907489f",
    "front": "**Def**: a record of the money paid into and out of a bank account.\n**Farsi**: صورتحساب بانکی",
    "back": "bank statement"
  },
  {
    "id": "81f786c9-037b-4880-bff0-a9f3d66545e6",
    "front": "**Def**: careful about spending money. OPP extravagant.\n**Farsi**: مقتصد، صرفه‌جو",
    "back": "thrifty"
  },
  {
    "id": "7ac9f667-4413-4d55-bac2-69af2fa0d8cc",
    "front": "**Def**: waste sth, especially money or time, in a careless way.\n**Farsi**: هدر دادن، تلف کردن",
    "back": "squander sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "4baa7294-297a-4326-8027-9663a4fa88fd",
    "front": "**Def**: an amount of money.\n**Farsi**: مبلغی (از چیزی)",
    "back": "sum (of sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f5f85842-f5ad-4306-ae91-c3779fb840a9",
    "front": "**Def**: gives immediate access to your money, but pays little interest.\n**Farsi**: حساب جاری",
    "back": "current account"
  },
  {
    "id": "649b725c-9760-4bf4-b919-183300c282ec",
    "front": "**Def**: pays more interest but without such quick access.\n**Farsi**: حساب پس‌انداز",
    "back": "deposit or savings account"
  },
  {
    "id": "f1230442-b7ea-4cf0-bc70-4d8cb1da2746",
    "front": "**Def**: use numbers to find a total number, amount, or distance. SYN work sth out. calculation N.\n**Farsi**: محاسبه کردن",
    "back": "calculate sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "bde997b1-6d55-40b0-9712-21a698df5fd4",
    "front": "**Def**: for each (used to express the cost or amount of sth for each person, period of time, etc.).\n**Farsi**: در هر، به ازای هر",
    "back": "per"
  },
  {
    "id": "d5ec0ab9-e2ae-4fa7-b04b-791718572a24",
    "front": "**Def**: take one number from another to calculate the difference. SYN take sth away from sth.\n**Farsi**: کم کردن، تفریق کردن",
    "back": "subtract sth from sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "19defe4f-89b3-4bda-9c30-2cbd59c67bc9",
    "front": "**Def**: A surplus is more of something than is necessary. If it is money, the opposite is a deficit.\n**Farsi**: مازاد، اضافه",
    "back": "surplus"
  },
  {
    "id": "df261c53-2477-4af5-bea1-5b31647fe671",
    "front": "**Def**: an amount of money available for a particular purpose.\n**Farsi**: صندوق مالی، وجه",
    "back": "fund"
  },
  {
    "id": "78058025-c9aa-4be3-ab4d-659858355410",
    "front": "**Def**: sth that may or may not happen (contingency plans/a contingency fund).\n**Farsi**: پیشامد، موارد احتمالی",
    "back": "contingency"
  },
  {
    "id": "6908cd0d-bde0-4490-8877-fb120676c539",
    "front": "**Def**: the difference between what you have and what you need.\n**Farsi**: کمبود، کسری (مالی)",
    "back": "shortfall"
  },
  {
    "id": "7355ddab-e6d4-42d1-9515-55647712d500",
    "front": "**Def**: reduce the amount of money, time, goods, etc. that you use. SYN make cutbacks.\n**Farsi**: صرفه‌جویی کردن",
    "back": "economize"
  },
  {
    "id": "45a1b01e-b5aa-41fb-9702-c11c93f33c7d",
    "front": "**Def**: give money to sb to help them pay for sth. subsidy N.\n**Farsi**: یارانه دادن به کسی",
    "back": "subsidize sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "afe24ce5-efa4-4bf3-a2fa-11d2c30cc070",
    "front": "**Def**: rescue sb from a difficult situation, often with money.\n**Farsi**: با پول نجات دادن کسی",
    "back": "bail sb out"
  },
  {
    "id": "95b3b298-b7f9-40a7-8b6d-be9f1da48093",
    "front": "**Def**: write sth quickly.\n**Farsi**: سریع یادداشت کردن",
    "back": "jot sth down"
  },
  {
    "id": "57a61c7c-217b-42a9-b685-a44e3a5351e3",
    "front": "**Def**: a particular way in which sth is organized or done (on a day-to-day basis, on a daily/weekly/regular basis).\n**Farsi**: مبنا، اساس",
    "back": "basis"
  },
  {
    "id": "76e39a55-e7d7-4541-b4ad-552fa5129ccf",
    "front": "**Def**: put tasks, problems, etc. in order of importance and do the most important first. priority N (high/low/top priority).\n**Farsi**: اولویت‌بندی کردن",
    "back": "prioritize"
  },
  {
    "id": "036e371f-fd77-41d2-a3e6-e706a6e25cfe",
    "front": "**Def**: in a determined and firm way.\n**Farsi**: بی‌رحمانه، قاطعانه",
    "back": "ruthlessly"
  },
  {
    "id": "76fdc44c-d0a1-4c30-a34c-ae97f271b652",
    "front": "**Def**: succeed in doing or completing sth. SYN achieve sth.\n**Farsi**: به انجام رساندن، موفق شدن در",
    "back": "accomplish sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "c6452c09-8e98-4860-926b-e41b53286c8f",
    "front": "**Def**: continue doing sth despite difficulties.\n**Farsi**: به چیزی پایبند بودن",
    "back": "stick to sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "30fb4b6c-3866-4810-b74d-8c6a6e27d99a",
    "front": "**Def**: expect sth will happen and prepare for it. anticipation N.\n**Farsi**: پیش‌بینی کردن",
    "back": "anticipate sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "0a2152fd-c531-40dc-896e-890a10f2f21b",
    "front": "**Def**: arrange for sth to happen at a particular time. schedule N.\n**Farsi**: برنامه‌ریزی زمانی کردن",
    "back": "schedule sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "37744ffc-f38c-40d4-adaf-0116466b1aad",
    "front": "**Def**: give part of your work to sb, especially sb in a lower position.\n**Farsi**: واگذار کردن، محول کردن (مسئولیت)",
    "back": "delegate sth (to sb)"
  },
  {
    "id": "14e78441-801b-4d69-ad57-24a6677fecdd",
    "front": "**Def**: strict and severe.\n**Farsi**: دقیق، سختگیرانه",
    "back": "rigorous"
  },
  {
    "id": "e58ed5f5-ba3f-4a09-806c-66be34fa89cc",
    "front": "**Def**: given so many things that you cannot deal with them. SYNS overwhelmed, swamped.\n**Farsi**: غرق در چیزی، لبریز از چیزی",
    "back": "inundated (with sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "5d2772f7-a26b-47b8-98f2-58a55b1844d7",
    "front": "**Def**: INF too anxious and tired to be able to relax.\n**Farsi**: تحت فشار عصبی، خسته و مضطرب",
    "back": "stressed out"
  },
  {
    "id": "fbce51a7-8dba-4ac8-9827-9cee38c6f08e",
    "front": "**Def**: quickly; without delay. prompt ADJ.\n**Farsi**: سریعاً، بی‌درنگ",
    "back": "promptly"
  },
  {
    "id": "17344c5e-75c2-4d72-b612-434dbbd2f2e9",
    "front": "**Def**: not producing good results. OPP productive.\n**Farsi**: غیرمولد، بی‌نتیجه",
    "back": "unproductive"
  },
  {
    "id": "57f49e47-5851-482e-8364-50507d11da7b",
    "front": "**Def**: badly affected by sth (also severely/badly hit).\n**Farsi**: به شدت آسیب دیده",
    "back": "hard-hit"
  },
  {
    "id": "5092d191-a0ef-4bfa-b669-7b27cca4a406",
    "front": "**Def**: be/become impossible to control. OPP be under control.\n**Farsi**: از کنترل خارج شدن",
    "back": "be/get out of hand"
  },
  {
    "id": "16239390-3a4a-4a78-82d1-af263742b104",
    "front": "**Def**: stop speaking or doing sth for a time.\n**Farsi**: دست کشیدن از، متوقف کردن (کار)",
    "back": "break off (from sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "a92626b8-9ff6-4c59-a7fd-0bff44f2cc4e",
    "front": "**Def**: a linked series of thoughts in your head at one time.\n**Farsi**: رشته افکار",
    "back": "train of thought"
  },
  {
    "id": "0ee8c435-8783-4fd8-9c9b-8898d64f3218",
    "front": "**Def**: keep sth, especially money or time, for a purpose.\n**Farsi**: اختصاص دادن، کنار گذاشتن",
    "back": "set sth aside"
  },
  {
    "id": "7c4c443e-7aa6-43a7-8c9a-a4cbf7caed19",
    "front": "**Def**: a fast-spreading disease which often results in death; in the title it is something that causes irritation.\n**Farsi**: بلای فراگیر (استعاری)",
    "back": "plague (metaphorical)"
  },
  {
    "id": "6c1aedaa-5a54-4c53-a440-ab82e7454ccd",
    "front": "**Def**: a small river, but here it means a continuous flow of things.\n**Farsi**: جریان، سیل (ایمیل)",
    "back": "stream (metaphorical)"
  },
  {
    "id": "1cbcbacd-81ae-404c-84f5-47f5455445dd",
    "front": "**Def**: a flood or heavy rain, but in the text it means a great quantity of something arriving at the same time.\n**Farsi**: سیل عظیم، هجوم (ایمیل)",
    "back": "deluge (metaphorical)"
  },
  {
    "id": "bfdeadae-d1dd-4fe5-afa5-145b66851f3d",
    "front": "**Def**: a failure to reach an agreement or settle an argument (be unable to break the deadlock).\n**Farsi**: بن‌بست، گره کور",
    "back": "deadlock"
  },
  {
    "id": "569db8c4-6d7c-445f-8fb9-c42cdae59378",
    "front": "**Def**: a system of voting in which votes are made in secret (ballot (v)).\n**Farsi**: رای‌گیری، اخذ رأی مخفی",
    "back": "ballot"
  },
  {
    "id": "cf1fc08d-5bb8-4c08-85a6-225d234d910f",
    "front": "**Def**: a disagreement, often official, between people or groups (a pay/industrial dispute, settle a dispute).\n**Farsi**: اختلاف، مناقشه (صنعتی)",
    "back": "dispute"
  },
  {
    "id": "f356daaa-8568-4d5c-92fb-db7dfe9b9069",
    "front": "**Def**: prevent sth from continuing.\n**Farsi**: متوقف کردن",
    "back": "halt sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "9f053e34-78af-413f-9b2a-467bfcd6836d",
    "front": "**Def**: a situation in which a school, factory, etc. is permanently shut.\n**Farsi**: تعطیلی، بسته شدن",
    "back": "closure"
  },
  {
    "id": "d7fc499d-96db-4bd5-9ce3-a9813642d502",
    "front": "**Def**: the process of selling an industry so it is no longer owned by the government. OPP nationalization. privatize sth v.\n**Farsi**: خصوصی‌سازی",
    "back": "privatization"
  },
  {
    "id": "6408830e-3830-4bb7-b601-65b754e595e7",
    "front": "**Def**: If sth is at stake, you will lose it if a plan or action is not successful (there's a lot at stake / the stakes are high).\n**Farsi**: در معرض خطر، مطرح",
    "back": "at stake"
  },
  {
    "id": "36fc487f-f2f3-4fb7-97e9-175f440e70d7",
    "front": "**Def**: a thing that happened in the past which is seen as a rule or example to be followed by others in a similar situation.\n**Farsi**: سابقه، الگو، رویه",
    "back": "precedent"
  },
  {
    "id": "27cee6cd-3c2f-4fca-9e03-dc32c99205cf",
    "front": "**Def**: likely to do sth or tending to do sth. inclination N.\n**Farsi**: متمایل بودن به انجام کاری",
    "back": "inclined to do sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "3e4a218d-d36d-4d5e-b0c7-0cec3fc32434",
    "front": "**Def**: increase the amount of an activity in order to achieve sth.\n**Farsi**: افزایش دادن، بالا بردن",
    "back": "step sth up"
  },
  {
    "id": "924fcc2f-dbfc-48e7-9bbb-a550ad5d66ab",
    "front": "**Def**: Set is used with many nouns, often meaning to fix something for others to copy, e.g. set an example, set a standard, set a record, set a precedent. It can also mean to decide on something, as in set a date/limit.\n**Farsi**: تعیین کردن (تاریخ/محدودیت/رویه)",
    "back": "set a date/limit/precedent"
  },
  {
    "id": "61693b7f-8463-4b72-b858-bc3c3c3c821d",
    "front": "**Def**: get involved in a situation in order to help. intervention N.\n**Farsi**: مداخله کردن، پادرمیانی کردن",
    "back": "intervene in sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "ceaaa5c0-515f-4b2d-8c5f-7e94a3c6cabf",
    "front": "**Def**: FML find an acceptable solution to a problem. resolution N.\n**Farsi**: حل و فصل کردن، رفع کردن",
    "back": "resolve sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "7c300903-28e7-4101-9942-11b043a80a36",
    "front": "**Def**: slept very well.\n**Farsi**: مثل کنده خوابیدن (خواب عمیق)",
    "back": "slept like a log"
  },
  {
    "id": "a9c6e726-c894-4dab-a866-c22153c68f71",
    "front": "**Def**: do sth to solve a problem.\n**Farsi**: رسیدگی کردن به یک مشکل، حل کردن",
    "back": "tackle a problem"
  },
  {
    "id": "ea3d8fe1-4b95-4545-b40a-90fbbfeff9b5",
    "front": "**Def**: make sth more serious than it is.\n**Farsi**: بزرگنمایی کردن، غلو کردن",
    "back": "blow sth (up) out of (all) proportion"
  },
  {
    "id": "503d23da-ff82-4638-af29-bef3a4b5ba89",
    "front": "**Def**: deal with a problem successfully (if sth sorts itself out, the problem is resolved without the need for action from anyone).\n**Farsi**: حل و فصل کردن (مشکل)",
    "back": "sort sth out"
  },
  {
    "id": "29152faf-c428-4682-a152-591bb88c3797",
    "front": "**Def**: make sb else deal with sth that you should deal with.\n**Farsi**: مسئولیت را به گردن دیگری انداختن",
    "back": "pass the buck"
  },
  {
    "id": "0c0bbfd6-c71a-41f2-bf37-e99bdaf7d407",
    "front": "**Def**: get involved in a situation in a way that annoys others. interference N.\n**Farsi**: دخالت آزاردهنده کردن",
    "back": "interfere (in sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "1f1fe749-ff55-474c-97e4-b9e252ed04ea",
    "front": "**Def**: sensible; showing good judgement. wisdom N. SYN prudent. prudence N.\n**Farsi**: عاقلانه، محتاطانه",
    "back": "wise (of actions)"
  },
  {
    "id": "ba2f54de-9eb7-4afb-83bd-0840eb2608a4",
    "front": "**Def**: FML delay doing sth until later, often because you don't want to do it. procrastination N.\n**Farsi**: امروز و فردا کردن، به تعویق انداختن",
    "back": "procrastinate"
  },
  {
    "id": "e8273e96-97eb-4c1b-ba27-ec21cb7e01d6",
    "front": "**Def**: pretend a difficult situation doesn't exist.\n**Farsi**: نادیده گرفتن مشکل، سر در برف فرو بردن",
    "back": "bury your head in the sand"
  },
  {
    "id": "e6427e22-2c2b-4fbe-8836-476bc993e69b",
    "front": "**Def**: a thing you particularly dislike or find annoying.\n**Farsi**: چیزی که به شدت آزاردهنده است، مورد تنفر شخصی",
    "back": "pet hate"
  },
  {
    "id": "78cce957-0bf1-43c9-871f-afa3131cb22b",
    "front": "**Def**: a situation in which a machine doesn't work because sth is stuck in one position (a paper jam). jam v (the photocopier keeps jamming).\n**Farsi**: گیر کردن، انسداد (مثلاً کاغذ در دستگاه)",
    "back": "jam"
  },
  {
    "id": "d8dd1a88-a897-407c-80bd-f4b53467edf1",
    "front": "**Def**: make a situation better after a mistake has been made.\n**Farsi**: درست کردن، رفع اشکال کردن",
    "back": "put sth right"
  },
  {
    "id": "3106238e-19f7-4825-8f31-6ba7b53614e8",
    "front": "**Def**: not in a place, e.g. because of illness. absence N.\n**Farsi**: غایب، حاضر نبودن",
    "back": "absent (from sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "461658a2-6467-4e6d-b916-183c4e7b112b",
    "front": "**Def**: become larger in quantity or amount. SYN accumulate.\n**Farsi**: تلنبار شدن، روی هم جمع شدن",
    "back": "pile up"
  },
  {
    "id": "9a944009-26a2-4025-8e50-825a72da6bec",
    "front": "**Def**: very busy.\n**Farsi**: پر مشغله، شلوغ",
    "back": "hectic"
  },
  {
    "id": "43262ba8-d3ad-44b3-8e5f-a431d4e6b953",
    "front": "**Def**: not do sth, or not give enough attention to sth. neglect N.\n**Farsi**: نادیده گرفتن، بی‌توجهی کردن",
    "back": "neglect sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "a6ded8f3-faea-4610-a085-d424976849b0",
    "front": "**Def**: INF become involved in sth that does not concern you.\n**Farsi**: فضولی کردن، دخالت کردن",
    "back": "poke/stick your nose in(to) sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "b314bbd3-46d2-41e9-aa93-7d3b7bd5ce8f",
    "front": "**Def**: not do sth that people expect you to do. SYN neglect to do sth.\n**Farsi**: کوتاهی کردن در انجام کاری",
    "back": "fail to do sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "e0470a01-2628-4a29-9933-b64675a6936e",
    "front": "**Def**: the act of making sb else responsible for sth. hand sth over (to sb) v.\n**Farsi**: واگذاری (مسئولیت)",
    "back": "handover"
  },
  {
    "id": "824746cf-cc16-42c3-9812-76863256aa77",
    "front": "**Def**: sing a tune with your lips closed.\n**Farsi**: زمزمه کردن، زیر لب آواز خواندن",
    "back": "hum"
  },
  {
    "id": "9392f097-03e1-4817-9ca6-809e804e2e21",
    "front": "**Def**: laugh in a silly way when you're embarrassed, amused, or nervous.\n**Farsi**: ریز خندیدن، خنده احمقانه کردن",
    "back": "giggle"
  },
  {
    "id": "fcd87333-4305-460a-b3ad-f5097dcfe7e2",
    "front": "**Def**: take a quick, noisy breath in through your nose, e.g. when you have a cold.\n**Farsi**: بو کشیدن، فین فین کردن",
    "back": "sniff"
  },
  {
    "id": "94a95ee4-4343-48ac-8c0e-50060a4b9156",
    "front": "**Def**: angry or violent behaviour by one driver towards another driver.\n**Farsi**: خشم جاده‌ای",
    "back": "road rage"
  },
  {
    "id": "daf7b414-f5f7-423a-b2d4-34739381d659",
    "front": "**Def**: cause sth to start or develop suddenly.\n**Farsi**: باعث شروع شدن چیزی شدن، جرقه‌ای زدن",
    "back": "spark sth (off)"
  },
  {
    "id": "07ace1be-b2fa-4a1b-8ea3-05bf7c4dfc2b",
    "front": "**Def**: sth that happens, especially sth unusual or unpleasant.\n**Farsi**: حادثه، واقعه",
    "back": "incident"
  },
  {
    "id": "9a0df3fc-d810-4e33-af0c-2c9f996eba2a",
    "front": "**Def**: make sb very angry, crazy, etc.\n**Farsi**: کسی را دیوانه/عصبانی کردن",
    "back": "drive sb mad/crazy/insane"
  },
  {
    "id": "0bc21b8d-9c41-4b8c-b7eb-1b1477d8db8b",
    "front": "**Def**: INF encourage sb to do sth, especially sth they should not do.\n**Farsi**: تحریک کردن کسی به کار بد",
    "back": "egg sb on"
  },
  {
    "id": "b1e4bb6e-3309-40bb-9996-bd17a9747b4a",
    "front": "**Def**: used to suggest that the way one event leads to another is so obvious that it does not need to be stated.\n**Farsi**: یک چیز به چیز دیگری منجر می‌شود (تسلسل وقایع)",
    "back": "one thing leads to another"
  },
  {
    "id": "1d0872ca-84aa-430a-8da3-9417475c0ec1",
    "front": "**Def**: say or do sth that you know will annoy sb so that they react angrily. SYN goad sb. provocation N.\n**Farsi**: تحریک کردن، برانگیختن خشم",
    "back": "provoke sb (into sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "1237295e-bd10-4d1e-b2db-01df1af636ee",
    "front": "**Def**: react too strongly to sth, especially sth unpleasant.\n**Farsi**: واکنش بیش از حد نشان دادن",
    "back": "overreact (to sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "e7798cd6-0da8-4c5a-ab0d-2c30d85e9cf7",
    "front": "**Def**: INF (of a situation) have sth as a main or basic part.\n**Farsi**: خلاصه شدن در، علت اصلی بودن",
    "back": "boil down to sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "7284f7c5-b02e-497e-950e-80035c5d17e2",
    "front": "**Def**: a number of connected events that happen one after the other. SYN sequence of events.\n**Farsi**: زنجیره وقایع",
    "back": "chain of events"
  },
  {
    "id": "68bae5f3-a51c-4b2b-b658-8a4d5d1baa58",
    "front": "**Def**: make sb have a particular feeling or attitude. arouse (sb's) suspicion/curiosity.\n**Farsi**: برانگیختن، تحریک کردن (شک/کنجکاوی)",
    "back": "arouse sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "02f4fd09-c6ab-4282-8d48-84db52af5df6",
    "front": "**Def**: a reason for doing sth.\n**Farsi**: انگیزه، دلیل",
    "back": "motive"
  },
  {
    "id": "4c851c3b-23a1-4f73-98ce-c72a2df1907e",
    "front": "**Def**: the result of a situation or event (final outcome SYN end result).\n**Farsi**: نتیجه، برآیند",
    "back": "outcome"
  },
  {
    "id": "f03fb02d-294f-448f-998c-f8f57f8ce054",
    "front": "**Def**: FML force sb to do sth. coercion N.\n**Farsi**: مجبور کردن کسی به انجام کاری",
    "back": "coerce sb (into doing sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "8cd0b9b3-6908-49cb-90c6-fab037601000",
    "front": "**Def**: unintended and usually unwelcome results of an action or event. SYN consequences.\n**Farsi**: پیامدهای ناخواسته، عواقب",
    "back": "repercussions"
  },
  {
    "id": "c5b27930-1152-4a70-be6e-881cd49ce260",
    "front": "**Def**: make sb decide to do sth.\n**Farsi**: ترغیب کردن، باعث تصمیم‌گیری شدن",
    "back": "prompt sb to do sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "b937ea36-6473-47c5-8740-7c69813b6243",
    "front": "**Def**: often used when you do not want to say why you have done sth.\n**Farsi**: بدون دلیل خاصی، همینطوری",
    "back": "no reason"
  },
  {
    "id": "7344e779-1457-4ef1-bc78-0bc53228ebd0",
    "front": "**Def**: a new product that is based on another that already exists.\n**Farsi**: محصول فرعی، مشتق",
    "back": "spin-off"
  },
  {
    "id": "2b836f39-370e-4c81-9658-c4e4dec8be33",
    "front": "**Def**: produce or create sth (generate income/profit/jobs).\n**Farsi**: تولید کردن، ایجاد کردن (درآمد)",
    "back": "generate sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "b5dbdfa0-4231-47f4-ae12-1d3f6a4d3a7a",
    "front": "**Def**: have an effect on sth, usually a good effect.\n**Farsi**: تفاوت ایجاد کردن، مؤثر بودن",
    "back": "make a difference"
  },
  {
    "id": "bf32549d-eb47-41b0-b775-f4de07d0704b",
    "front": "**Def**: If a law or regulation comes into effect, it begins to apply or be used.\n**Farsi**: اجرایی شدن (قانون)",
    "back": "come into effect"
  },
  {
    "id": "62a49808-22ea-4c67-9405-fb85abc3f1a2",
    "front": "**Def**: cause events to happen one after another in a series.\n**Farsi**: اثرات زنجیره‌ای، پیامدهای ثانویه",
    "back": "knock-on effects"
  },
  {
    "id": "69c58ee8-8f87-4dd3-903e-8fc5b6ad3423",
    "front": "**Def**: a negative or unpleasant one (OPP a beneficial effect).\n**Farsi**: اثر نامطلوب یا مضر",
    "back": "adverse or detrimental effect"
  },
  {
    "id": "c5d7d6bf-f856-4248-af70-f4385a62d1a7",
    "front": "**Def**: say things that are only partially true (used as a euphemism for 'lie').\n**Farsi**: حقیقت را ناگفته گذاشتن (کم‌گویی کردن)",
    "back": "be economical with the truth"
  },
  {
    "id": "296d42c5-a7ee-4aed-aeb5-d4b8e3b6d559",
    "front": "**Def**: describe sth in a way that makes it sound better than it is.\n**Farsi**: چیزی را تعریف و تمجید کردن/بزرگنمایی کردن",
    "back": "talk sth up"
  },
  {
    "id": "c0dcab1e-6b1a-4dc3-be0d-c4f23cc60215",
    "front": "**Def**: make a statement or story more interesting by adding details that are not always true.\n**Farsi**: چیزی را شاخ و برگ دادن/آراستن",
    "back": "embellish sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "cd335c6a-f98e-470e-90f3-63ee28140f10",
    "front": "**Def**: deliberately avoid talking about sth unpleasant, or say as little as possible about it.\n**Farsi**: چیزی را لاپوشانی کردن/سرسری رد شدن",
    "back": "gloss over sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "ac78f13a-a53e-4db1-aacc-0b8c63198cda",
    "front": "**Def**: unpleasant and hard to accept.\n**Farsi**: ناخوشایند/غیرقابل پذیرش",
    "back": "unpalatable"
  },
  {
    "id": "e2e4992c-8dee-4d11-80e9-dd8a9e68b708",
    "front": "**Def**: used to introduce more exact information about a subject.\n**Farsi**: یعنی/به عبارت دیگر",
    "back": "namely"
  },
  {
    "id": "2000ccd4-c3f8-4e81-9fdf-32a5634d8a8e",
    "front": "**Def**: make sth continue for some time.\n**Farsi**: چیزی را حفظ کردن/ادامه دادن",
    "back": "sustain sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "2122c856-a5ce-487d-a73d-5824d6c86591",
    "front": "**Def**: discover or notice sth, especially sth that is hard to see or hear.\n**Farsi**: چیزی را کشف کردن/متوجه شدن",
    "back": "detect sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "7c0edb7f-2ea5-4491-afee-94b4c94106e5",
    "front": "**Def**: announce the start of war or a ceasefire.\n**Farsi**: اعلان جنگ/آتش‌بس کردن",
    "back": "declare war / a ceasefire"
  },
  {
    "id": "f02cf1b2-1dd7-436e-84fd-8231cd8e1a0a",
    "front": "**Def**: sth that is destroyed or sb who suffers when sth else happens.\n**Farsi**: تلفات/قربانی",
    "back": "casualty"
  },
  {
    "id": "caad9d0c-c0c7-41e8-816d-746dcd87e1ab",
    "front": "**Def**: tell the truth and not hide any important facts.\n**Farsi**: با کسی روراست بودن/صادق بودن",
    "back": "level with sb (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "de35736e-e045-4ff7-afee-9625d5aa8718",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who is not honest or sincere. (Adj: phoney)\n**Farsi**: ریاکار/قلابی",
    "back": "phoney (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b6865444-bbab-4b90-b814-c46e09988ff0",
    "front": "**Def**: in such a way that the speaker's name is kept secret. (N: anonymity)\n**Farsi**: به طور ناشناس",
    "back": "anonymously"
  },
  {
    "id": "2de9326c-ff1a-4efa-b4f4-a990c324b8c2",
    "front": "**Def**: after sb has died.\n**Farsi**: پس از مرگ",
    "back": "posthumously"
  },
  {
    "id": "dc5ba3d7-3e27-4893-8c49-8f238c9e661e",
    "front": "**Def**: make sb feel confused because they don't understand sth. (Syns: baffle sb, confound sb FML. Adj: puzzled)\n**Farsi**: کسی را گیج کردن/متحیر ساختن",
    "back": "puzzle sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "0d52bd15-4c23-4d17-883d-244a4626d723",
    "front": "**Def**: an enemy or opponent.\n**Farsi**: دشمن/حریف",
    "back": "adversary (FML)"
  },
  {
    "id": "aab16177-a11d-4201-a20e-5daf4280c292",
    "front": "**Def**: trick sb by behaving dishonestly (also deceive yourself refuse to admit that sth unpleasant is true SYN delude yourself). (N: deceit, deception)\n**Farsi**: کسی را فریب دادن/اغفال کردن",
    "back": "deceive sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "9af53068-8c73-4a4b-8a54-890224f9c591",
    "front": "**Def**: is a lie.\n**Farsi**: نادرستی/دروغ",
    "back": "A falsehood (FML)"
  },
  {
    "id": "dae82c28-ad47-4fea-a970-0c8f5672eea2",
    "front": "**Def**: a small lie, especially one you tell to avoid hurting someone.\n**Farsi**: دروغ مصلحتی",
    "back": "A white lie"
  },
  {
    "id": "e3d2fb78-e516-416d-b602-7637c189e1b1",
    "front": "**Def**: a statement which only gives some of the facts.\n**Farsi**: نیمه حقیقت",
    "back": "A half-truth"
  },
  {
    "id": "322d4242-a508-44b3-8266-2f0770fbb782",
    "front": "**Def**: an unimportant lie.\n**Farsi**: دروغ کوچک/سرهم بندی",
    "back": "A fib (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "c4cee529-47ed-4117-bd12-7bf922f157ea",
    "front": "**Def**: not important. (Opp: major).\n**Farsi**: جزئی/کوچک",
    "back": "minor"
  },
  {
    "id": "5409bd27-ada3-4e87-aded-57f63f3468b4",
    "front": "**Def**: increasing in size, amount, or degree.\n**Farsi**: رو به رشد/فزاینده",
    "back": "growing"
  },
  {
    "id": "7f484596-f18c-42d9-b443-f85a6b5034cb",
    "front": "**Def**: requiring immediate action.\n**Farsi**: فوری/ضروری",
    "back": "urgent"
  },
  {
    "id": "5e13a7b3-d9a9-4b18-8b2d-c7a8125c5870",
    "front": "**Def**: always existing and not seeming to change.\n**Farsi**: همیشگی/دیرپا",
    "back": "perennial"
  },
  {
    "id": "8ea8afde-83f8-4bcf-8955-63d15b92c7cc",
    "front": "**Def**: unable to be solved. (SYN insurmountable FML).\n**Farsi**: حل نشدنی/لا ینحل",
    "back": "insoluble"
  },
  {
    "id": "dd07cee8-7533-49fe-9b10-53d1a93bf750",
    "front": "**Def**: start to exist. (SYN occur / come up).\n**Farsi**: بوجود آمدن/پیش آمدن",
    "back": "arise"
  },
  {
    "id": "d8d8e5d5-59fd-4d25-a23b-ea62c26dd4bf",
    "front": "**Def**: mention sth for people to discuss.\n**Farsi**: چیزی را مطرح کردن",
    "back": "raise sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "a32429ef-118e-45f1-ab25-41c7ae129780",
    "front": "**Def**: If problems confront sb, they appear and have to be dealt with by sb. (SYN face sb).\n**Farsi**: روبرو شدن (مشکلات با کسی)",
    "back": "confront sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "c2ba58f1-e6e6-4131-ad08-94d4163145d1",
    "front": "**Def**: deal with a problem or difficult situation. (SYN face up to sth).\n**Farsi**: با چیزی مقابله کردن/مواجه شدن",
    "back": "confront sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "a2643794-3c37-46dd-bed5-19bf1c2aca01",
    "front": "**Def**: think about a difficult situation and decide how to deal with it.\n**Farsi**: به چیزی پرداختن/رسیدگی کردن",
    "back": "address sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "76ff7613-96af-4e8e-bc91-03fa32db846e",
    "front": "**Def**: begin to understand and deal with sth difficult.\n**Farsi**: با چیزی دست و پنجه نرم کردن/مسلط شدن",
    "back": "get to grips with sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "41daa357-a79a-49c0-a0c4-6cddba032452",
    "front": "**Def**: make a big effort to deal with a problem.\n**Farsi**: با چیزی دست و پنجه نرم کردن/اقدام کردن",
    "back": "tackle sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "ca683e9d-0bc6-438b-8e04-f57b628cc8ba",
    "front": "**Def**: succeed in dealing with a problem that has been preventing you from achieving sth.\n**Farsi**: بر چیزی فائق آمدن/غلبه کردن",
    "back": "overcome sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "7965b469-e20b-41fb-82bf-831386fc1cb1",
    "front": "**Def**: make an existing problem worse. (SYN aggravate sth).\n**Farsi**: چیزی را تشدید کردن/وخیم‌تر کردن",
    "back": "exacerbate sth (FML)"
  },
  {
    "id": "9f02adb8-594d-4058-be34-09df1f09f0ef",
    "front": "**Def**: damage sb's confidence, etc.\n**Farsi**: (اعتماد به نفس) کسی را تضعیف کردن",
    "back": "dent (sb's confidence, reputation, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b65921f3-ba62-4104-a287-7d86681c7e66",
    "front": "**Def**: the way you feel about yourself (high/low self-esteem).\n**Farsi**: عزت نفس",
    "back": "self-esteem"
  },
  {
    "id": "6be9b3bc-3ef9-4f40-9445-6a4b8decb033",
    "front": "**Def**: treat sth as unimportant. (OPP take sth seriously).\n**Farsi**: چیزی را دست کم گرفتن",
    "back": "make light of sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "631725f3-5d2c-4db0-b312-66adf9c2eac6",
    "front": "**Def**: not important or serious.\n**Farsi**: بی اهمیت/ناچیز",
    "back": "trivial"
  },
  {
    "id": "36516734-9eb4-42cf-b293-c8d51a339b94",
    "front": "**Def**: If sth gets you down it makes you feel sad or depressed.\n**Farsi**: کسی را افسرده کردن/مایوس کردن",
    "back": "get sb down"
  },
  {
    "id": "3722a391-4f8b-4340-a404-772085d0aae0",
    "front": "**Def**: not allow a problem to have too much importance.\n**Farsi**: چیزی را در چارچوب درست دیدن/اهمیت واقعی دادن",
    "back": "keep sth in perspective"
  },
  {
    "id": "b8cb1710-be8b-4821-a46f-ca53d0c08972",
    "front": "**Def**: a problem that delays or prevents progress.\n**Farsi**: شکست/عقب‌گرد",
    "back": "setback"
  },
  {
    "id": "2242d78d-2a29-4065-b0f1-434dd3759ff0",
    "front": "**Def**: say or do sth that makes sb less worried. (SYN set sb's mind at rest).\n**Farsi**: به کسی اطمینان خاطر دادن/دلگرمی دادن",
    "back": "reassure sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "4f1590db-a059-46c4-95a3-699aba9bd5be",
    "front": "**Def**: give your support to sb/sth.\n**Farsi**: از کسی/چیزی حمایت کردن",
    "back": "be behind sb/sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "11f424ce-1575-404d-99af-c861c4e82d02",
    "front": "**Def**: without being affected or influenced by sth.\n**Farsi**: صرف نظر از چیزی",
    "back": "regardless of sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "7872b0a3-8517-482f-8011-9c684016cf2d",
    "front": "**Def**: express your thoughts clearly in words. (Adj: articulate).\n**Farsi**: چیزی را به وضوح بیان کردن",
    "back": "articulate sth (FML)"
  },
  {
    "id": "6e953a8b-5fef-4d5d-ae06-ee76a4b278a6",
    "front": "**Def**: a system or method for sending or obtaining information.\n**Farsi**: کانال ارتباطی",
    "back": "channel of communication"
  },
  {
    "id": "dbe92e56-d35a-4707-aff5-092bcd5bc10d",
    "front": "**Def**: (of a building) old and in very bad condition. (SYNS run-down, ramshackle).\n**Farsi**: مخروبه/فرسوده",
    "back": "dilapidated"
  },
  {
    "id": "3029c4c7-a216-47ef-9ff9-b57498cfd31e",
    "front": "**Def**: in earlier times. (SYN previously).\n**Farsi**: قبلاً/در گذشته",
    "back": "formerly"
  },
  {
    "id": "9decfe71-6b13-4ad3-ae58-05aa501c31e0",
    "front": "**Def**: leave a place, vehicle, etc. empty without planning to return.\n**Farsi**: چیزی را ترک کردن/رها کردن",
    "back": "abandon sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "2c930a8f-db06-4c2e-93ef-0756248b6489",
    "front": "**Def**: keep sth in its original state or in good condition. (N: preservation).\n**Farsi**: چیزی را حفظ کردن",
    "back": "preserve sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "589fc36d-f26b-4ca8-b6cb-4cc7d3b08fbb",
    "front": "**Def**: gradually be destroyed through lack of care.\n**Farsi**: دچار پوسیدگی/خرابی شدن",
    "back": "fall into decay/disrepair"
  },
  {
    "id": "6c73e606-0525-45cb-9b7e-0a1fc4cfb608",
    "front": "**Def**: repair and decorate an old building, car, etc. (SYN do sth up INF).\n**Farsi**: چیزی را بازسازی کردن/نوسازی کردن",
    "back": "renovate sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "b225bf17-c333-42ef-9420-f3359f96c3df",
    "front": "**Def**: buildings in which horses are kept.\n**Farsi**: اصطبل",
    "back": "stables"
  },
  {
    "id": "8719e84f-a8d1-4ccf-9a34-60bd33880859",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely (modern) (also ultra-cautious).\n**Farsi**: فوق‌العاده (مدرن)/بسیار",
    "back": "ultra-(modern)"
  },
  {
    "id": "77bea739-a79b-402e-99ff-8c8485598ba1",
    "front": "**Def**: parts of a building that remain after it has been destroyed.\n**Farsi**: ویرانه‌ها/آثار باستانی",
    "back": "ruins"
  },
  {
    "id": "941d0725-858b-48d0-b570-c33bc614ac39",
    "front": "**Def**: connected with the Middle Ages (= about 1000 to 1450).\n**Farsi**: قرون وسطایی",
    "back": "medieval"
  },
  {
    "id": "a5cd1b09-0302-4b03-8f70-89fd9bf9d129",
    "front": "**Def**: find the origin or cause of sth.\n**Farsi**: منشأ چیزی را پیدا کردن/ردیابی کردن",
    "back": "trace sth (back) (to sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "d734ae68-8bff-4c8a-9bfd-d79949fa7f9e",
    "front": "**Def**: completely new.\n**Farsi**: کاملاً نو/آکبند",
    "back": "brand new"
  },
  {
    "id": "9f6a959e-d29d-49a6-b393-a878723d7d98",
    "front": "**Def**: the most advanced (technology) in the field.\n**Farsi**: تکنولوژی پیشرفته/مدرن‌ترین",
    "back": "cutting-edge (technology)"
  },
  {
    "id": "774eab07-098f-41d8-8539-652e468717de",
    "front": "**Def**: featuring or introducing new ideas, methods, etc.\n**Farsi**: نوآورانه/خلاقانه",
    "back": "innovative"
  },
  {
    "id": "80b9dd8c-a231-4822-93ce-0d930dadc9ca",
    "front": "**Def**: an object or piece of equipment designed to do a particular job.\n**Farsi**: دستگاه/ابزار",
    "back": "device"
  },
  {
    "id": "8e775dc0-ec18-4200-9c0f-5fbc11d1761c",
    "front": "**Def**: modern (out of date = old-fashioned, or without the most recent information and therefore no longer useful).\n**Farsi**: به روز/مدرن",
    "back": "up to date"
  },
  {
    "id": "0ebd5bc2-6392-49f7-a72c-38f70ea28e67",
    "front": "**Def**: not new; owned by sb else before.\n**Farsi**: دست دوم",
    "back": "second-hand"
  },
  {
    "id": "b860df7b-a6b3-4260-98c4-49ac575c6a3d",
    "front": "**Def**: in very good condition (also like new ADV). (SYN in perfect condition)\n**Farsi**: مثل روز اول/بسیار سالم",
    "back": "(as) good as new"
  },
  {
    "id": "ec8f7bdb-2a08-448f-8107-099b37b10c6c",
    "front": "**Def**: exactly what it appears to be; real. (SYN authentic).\n**Farsi**: اصل/معتبر",
    "back": "genuine"
  },
  {
    "id": "9f008376-2e8f-4d6b-bf51-45950f80e75a",
    "front": "**Def**: old, and often very valuable. (N: antique).\n**Farsi**: عتیقه/قدیمی",
    "back": "antique"
  },
  {
    "id": "1ddafce4-ac2f-4d89-b796-dd0ad68aac8b",
    "front": "**Def**: new or as good as new. (SYN in perfect condition).\n**Farsi**: در وضعیت عالی/کاملاً نو",
    "back": "in mint condition"
  },
  {
    "id": "3dba047c-c560-480a-9021-a2507dd336f0",
    "front": "**Def**: a thing made as a copy of an earlier object or style. (V: reproduce sth).\n**Farsi**: بازتولید/کپی",
    "back": "reproduction"
  },
  {
    "id": "919c1d62-66b0-4861-b2a5-151c61fea630",
    "front": "**Def**: belonging to a period of history from thousands of years ago.\n**Farsi**: باستانی/کهن",
    "back": "ancient"
  },
  {
    "id": "32dc93a6-e299-4415-9c09-1d87e078f2db",
    "front": "**Def**: (of a machine) repaired so that it is in good condition.\n**Farsi**: تعمیر شده/بازسازی شده",
    "back": "reconditioned"
  },
  {
    "id": "aace8865-e83a-46b8-8a1a-045e0df10f1e",
    "front": "**Def**: materials used to wrap and protect goods sold in shops.\n**Farsi**: بسته‌بندی",
    "back": "packaging"
  },
  {
    "id": "d1a44826-afa0-4078-a499-414bab090981",
    "front": "**Def**: very great (a resounding success/defeat/win/victory).\n**Farsi**: چشمگیر/بسیار زیاد",
    "back": "resounding"
  },
  {
    "id": "da245d9d-1956-4836-9ce1-d184ebf4b41e",
    "front": "**Def**: happen in a particular way, often unexpectedly.\n**Farsi**: (چیزی) نتیجه دادن/رخ دادن",
    "back": "turn out (well/badly)"
  },
  {
    "id": "c405057c-4d2a-4f25-ae6f-1066d7df6a0a",
    "front": "**Def**: a way of doing things that has brought success.\n**Farsi**: راز موفقیت (شما)",
    "back": "the secret of (your) success"
  },
  {
    "id": "7874ea65-2c0a-4835-acf7-455e32689b30",
    "front": "**Def**: an unexpected but important event (a stroke of luck).\n**Farsi**: یک شانس/موفقیت ناگهانی",
    "back": "a stroke of sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "70e451f9-7461-4319-b1c9-a51eb41979f0",
    "front": "**Def**: not make a single mistake.\n**Farsi**: هرگز اشتباه نکردن/سیر درست را پیمودن",
    "back": "not put a foot wrong"
  },
  {
    "id": "21af3d0f-a001-4a49-b166-ce55d68bfe56",
    "front": "**Def**: a situation or event that makes it hard for you to achieve sth.\n**Farsi**: مانع/مشکل",
    "back": "obstacle"
  },
  {
    "id": "1eaddd52-b729-45e3-832f-17d18aa555cf",
    "front": "**Def**: stopping sb from doing sth.\n**Farsi**: مزاحم کسی/چیزی بودن",
    "back": "in sb's/the way"
  },
  {
    "id": "c01bceb3-6f6e-431c-86d6-d85902249b12",
    "front": "**Def**: fail completely.\n**Farsi**: شکست خوردن/خراب شدن",
    "back": "come unstuck (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "980398b2-2abf-41b3-9817-f60a427507b5",
    "front": "**Def**: succeed in achieving a goal; become successful.\n**Farsi**: موفق شدن/به هدف رسیدن",
    "back": "make it"
  },
  {
    "id": "4d21c013-1641-4146-ad78-57f711819c98",
    "front": "**Def**: an important development that may lead to an achievement or agreement (make/achieve a breakthrough).\n**Farsi**: موفقیت بزرگ/دستاورد مهم",
    "back": "breakthrough"
  },
  {
    "id": "b21850a2-5c45-479f-a338-ccd6210ebcf9",
    "front": "**Def**: become more and more successful.\n**Farsi**: موفقیت بیشتری کسب کردن/قوی‌تر شدن",
    "back": "go from strength to strength"
  },
  {
    "id": "97f507f1-136e-435d-8e78-0b7a90c88224",
    "front": "**Def**: make sth succeed, especially a business or marriage.\n**Farsi**: (در کسب و کار) موفق شدن",
    "back": "make a go of sth (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b23fe3ab-6b96-4739-8998-d3c9b3795bdc",
    "front": "**Def**: unable to do or understand sth because it is too hard.\n**Farsi**: از عهده کاری برنیامدن/درک نکردن",
    "back": "out of your depth"
  },
  {
    "id": "3fab6df3-ee10-419b-9782-21c72621f155",
    "front": "**Def**: difficult to do or deal with (a tricky situation/question/problem).\n**Farsi**: دشوار/پیچیده",
    "back": "tricky"
  },
  {
    "id": "42288904-292d-4e34-97f6-a2dc2e8934fc",
    "front": "**Def**: facing difficult problems or opposition.\n**Farsi**: با مشکلات جدی مواجه بودن",
    "back": "up against it (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "26d416b1-cdbc-459f-bc34-0ee3ad0de1f4",
    "front": "**Def**: get worse in quality, health, etc. (SYN deteriorate).\n**Farsi**: رو به زوال رفتن/بدتر شدن",
    "back": "go downhill"
  },
  {
    "id": "8855733f-9a30-4438-9d12-9ebaf7fdad57",
    "front": "**Def**: receive the lowest score in an exam. (OPP come top).\n**Farsi**: کمترین نمره را آوردن",
    "back": "come bottom"
  },
  {
    "id": "9687422d-6a53-4093-a40e-416fe2c20723",
    "front": "**Def**: only just succeed in passing an exam.\n**Farsi**: به سختی قبول شدن/با نمره لب مرزی قبول شدن",
    "back": "scrape through (an exam)"
  },
  {
    "id": "5dbe38a4-d7ce-48df-b7f4-86754ac36950",
    "front": "**Def**: be too old to do what you used to be able to do.\n**Farsi**: (عمر) کسی گذشته بودن/پیرتر از آن بودن",
    "back": "be past it (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "ed94e602-81c7-425a-9226-ed2d3bdf3b20",
    "front": "**Def**: If a person in public life makes a comeback, they start doing sth again which they had stopped doing.\n**Farsi**: بازگشت به صحنه/فعالیت مجدد",
    "back": "comeback"
  },
  {
    "id": "d504e6a7-7ce3-4670-9cf3-14531b63b727",
    "front": "**Def**: a film, play, book, party, etc. that is not successful. (V: flop).\n**Farsi**: شکست/ناموفقیت",
    "back": "flop (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "810bb53c-5c08-4271-b612-422f7ad4a359",
    "front": "**Def**: complete (used to describe sth bad). (SYN absolute).\n**Farsi**: مطلق/تمام عیار",
    "back": "unmitigated"
  },
  {
    "id": "e2c5f833-02bc-4542-8c32-4dbbd2b91304",
    "front": "**Def**: by a large amount or 'very far'.\n**Farsi**: بسیار/خیلی زیاد",
    "back": "way (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "971fa54f-c765-4f98-9c20-85e1f94e68f5",
    "front": "**Def**: time seems to pass very quickly.\n**Farsi**: زمان به سرعت می‌گذرد",
    "back": "time flies"
  },
  {
    "id": "5cd26528-1770-4b8c-b3b2-1117c6f72a6d",
    "front": "**Def**: sometimes but not regularly. (SYN now and again).\n**Farsi**: گهگاه/هر از گاهی",
    "back": "from time to time"
  },
  {
    "id": "60e20ef9-2c13-4a2a-9bf8-aaa46602cacf",
    "front": "**Def**: at the right time and not before.\n**Farsi**: در زمان مناسب/به موقع",
    "back": "in due course"
  },
  {
    "id": "50e06084-80f2-439a-84a4-d38cc96e4bb2",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say that sth should happen soon or should have happened already. (SYN it's high time).\n**Farsi**: وقتش رسیده است (که...)",
    "back": "it's about time"
  },
  {
    "id": "9d9b15ca-7f0e-4eb9-98ec-cfcca12dcac5",
    "front": "**Def**: in the past but not now.\n**Farsi**: در یک مقطع زمانی (در گذشته)",
    "back": "at one time"
  },
  {
    "id": "fa5e7ebe-87ae-47d7-bbdc-0018df5d0444",
    "front": "**Def**: do sth at the latest possible time before sth else happens. (SYN leave sth to/till the last minute).\n**Farsi**: کاری را در آخرین لحظه انجام دادن",
    "back": "do sth at the last minute"
  },
  {
    "id": "51e1a02f-56a5-41f7-90af-03950a4b49c8",
    "front": "**Def**: thinking now about the past, often with a different view from the one you had then. (SYN looking back).\n**Farsi**: با نگاهی به گذشته",
    "back": "in retrospect"
  },
  {
    "id": "96525805-8a04-4831-bdf2-61a40f9339ee",
    "front": "**Def**: for a short period of time but not permanently.\n**Farsi**: فعلاً/در حال حاضر",
    "back": "for the time being"
  },
  {
    "id": "0b8a2ad9-d014-4c03-9e5b-26e6e72e5703",
    "front": "**Def**: old-fashioned in ideas, ways, etc.\n**Farsi**: عقب افتاده/قدیمی",
    "back": "behind the times"
  },
  {
    "id": "e8a515c6-de08-4d79-b80f-fbd6f4c3e591",
    "front": "**Def**: gradually.\n**Farsi**: به مرور زمان",
    "back": "over time"
  },
  {
    "id": "b709e096-7857-4a84-b5d7-c31e7f72c450",
    "front": "**Def**: before you were born or before you can remember.\n**Farsi**: قبل از دوران (زندگی) شما",
    "back": "before your time"
  },
  {
    "id": "51ea000a-5ce6-46f7-8b48-5325c663084d",
    "front": "**Def**: at a point within a period of time.\n**Farsi**: در طول (یک مقطع زمانی)",
    "back": "during"
  },
  {
    "id": "cbf9de51-ba3c-496f-b22e-a54f8418fbb2",
    "front": "**Def**: continuously within a period of time.\n**Farsi**: در سرتاسر/در تمام مدت",
    "back": "throughout"
  },
  {
    "id": "26e2a04d-e457-4602-a8bf-e00908a9f79f",
    "front": "**Def**: a particular period of history.\n**Farsi**: عصر/دوران",
    "back": "age"
  },
  {
    "id": "fcdca3b3-7836-4253-836c-256c2858390c",
    "front": "**Def**: increase the length of time of sth. (OPP curtail FML).\n**Farsi**: چیزی را تمدید کردن/طولانی‌تر کردن",
    "back": "extend sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "0bacc874-19e6-49fb-a372-ed63aebf99e7",
    "front": "**Def**: make sth last longer. (OPP curtail FML).\n**Farsi**: چیزی را طولانی کردن",
    "back": "prolong sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "bf905106-3037-499d-bfc4-c3bfefb95e99",
    "front": "**Def**: a period of time between two events or two parts of sth, e.g. a play.\n**Farsi**: فاصله/بازه زمانی",
    "back": "interval"
  },
  {
    "id": "a60f492d-727b-4f11-b95b-35cbc4fbc978",
    "front": "**Def**: a period of time when sth stops.\n**Farsi**: وقفه/شکاف زمانی",
    "back": "gap"
  },
  {
    "id": "93883f20-016e-4583-8797-d30f403818a5",
    "front": "**Def**: a short period of time when you stop what you are doing and rest.\n**Farsi**: استراحت/تنفس",
    "back": "break"
  },
  {
    "id": "2eaccf46-4bd4-41cc-b947-8a21c84b5a21",
    "front": "**Def**: a short period of time or of a particular activity.\n**Farsi**: دوره کوتاه/مدت",
    "back": "spell"
  },
  {
    "id": "84e7fffb-fe66-4247-9200-a1a5d3aa28ef",
    "front": "**Def**: a period that forms part of an activity. A difficult period of time that sb/sth passes through (stage is also possible).\n**Farsi**: مرحله",
    "back": "stage"
  },
  {
    "id": "6f16d5ac-02ab-4254-9879-f04cb850ca48",
    "front": "**Def**: a period of time that forms part of a process or the development of sth.\n**Farsi**: فاز/مرحله",
    "back": "phase"
  },
  {
    "id": "f71c07e4-3d68-41d8-bcd5-ed21db450fd5",
    "front": "**Def**: all the verbs describe the process of time; elapse is FML; pass and go by are often used with an adverb to describe how time happens.\n**Farsi**: (زمان) گذشتن/سپری شدن",
    "back": "pass / elapse / go by"
  },
  {
    "id": "937daf97-4f82-4a56-9bb6-7a944da6b126",
    "front": "**Def**: quickly (after sth happens). In a short period of time from now. A short period after sb/sth. A short period before sb/sth.\n**Farsi**: به زودی/بیدرنگ",
    "back": "soon or shortly"
  },
  {
    "id": "da0bd041-c8f7-4ee0-afd5-873a15a3e077",
    "front": "**Def**: a friendly informal meeting or party. (Syn: get-together).\n**Farsi**: مهمانی/دورهمی",
    "back": "do (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "dd7c6b27-6225-4c25-852e-dea2736d59d0",
    "front": "**Def**: an enjoyable experience.\n**Farsi**: تجربه سرگرم‌کننده/خنده دار",
    "back": "a (good) laugh (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "d51bd287-142a-4242-ac28-f05287d868b7",
    "front": "**Def**: a boring or annoying occasion or situation.\n**Farsi**: کسالت‌آور/خسته‌کننده",
    "back": "a (bit of a) drag (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "3d086f4b-c8ee-4041-b7cc-0ece526f8c28",
    "front": "**Def**: bad, unpleasant, or of poor quality (a lousy film, lousy weather).\n**Farsi**: مزخرف/افتضاح",
    "back": "lousy (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "44dc2598-5fd0-4887-af96-9bdb9425afd8",
    "front": "**Def**: a pound (£) in money (PL quid NOT quids).\n**Farsi**: پوند (اصطلاح عامیانه)",
    "back": "quid (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "d843288f-adcc-42e5-bdbc-b0d2dd8ea5fe",
    "front": "**Def**: a thing that is not worth what you pay for it. (V: rip sb off).\n**Farsi**: گرانفروشی/کلاهبرداری",
    "back": "rip-off (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "dde86ef2-3f21-4eb1-af0d-798e1c720d86",
    "front": "**Def**: not generous with money. (SYNS tight, stingy).\n**Farsi**: خسیس/پول دوست",
    "back": "tight-fisted (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "516e37c9-7b68-47b6-a4d1-ce84da6cdc22",
    "front": "**Def**: very bad or unpleasant (a vile smell). (SYN disgusting).\n**Farsi**: نفرت‌انگیز/خیلی بد",
    "back": "vile (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b3563fb0-eeab-456d-b81a-69f4dffa7710",
    "front": "**Def**: a man. (SYN guy).\n**Farsi**: مرد/آدم (عام)",
    "back": "bloke (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "8d91bf01-c8e7-4f24-8bd5-6b14cb697672",
    "front": "**Def**: complain (about sth) in a way that annoys people.\n**Farsi**: ناله و شکایت کردن",
    "back": "moan (about sth) (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "2e782ced-f814-433a-94e2-94d83f09d754",
    "front": "**Def**: a toilet.\n**Farsi**: دستشویی",
    "back": "loo (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f099880e-d803-44dc-b487-4c218fcfe278",
    "front": "**Def**: steal sth. (SYN nick sth).\n**Farsi**: چیزی را کش رفتن/دزدیدن",
    "back": "pinch sth (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "dc1dcae1-8249-4fca-8eab-92747e9f78f9",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say you think sb's behaviour is rude or inappropriate. (SYN What a cheek!).\n**Farsi**: چه رویی!/عجب جرأتی!",
    "back": "What a nerve! (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "9f78881b-9423-4d1e-8bcf-4df04c6ec52f",
    "front": "**Def**: used to address sb you love, and by some people in shops as a friendly way of addressing customers, particularly women.\n**Farsi**: عزیزم/عشق من (خطاب محبت‌آمیز)",
    "back": "darling/love (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "79d4395f-e17c-48a2-b438-77c0462e3d19",
    "front": "**Def**: not having any money.\n**Farsi**: بی‌پول/ورشکسته",
    "back": "broke (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "5ec04455-0d18-4eb7-9d3f-bb29520f6148",
    "front": "**Def**: very hungry. (SYN dying for sth to eat).\n**Farsi**: گرسنه (خیلی)",
    "back": "starving (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "41f62325-fcda-488e-a787-372bcdb1f7e2",
    "front": "**Def**: a short sleep.\n**Farsi**: چرت زدن/خواب کوتاه",
    "back": "kip (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "7b7b66d3-a9e1-4abb-889e-f89b501abfa1",
    "front": "**Def**: elegant and expensive.\n**Farsi**: شیک و گران/لاکچری",
    "back": "posh (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "6b9321ca-947a-4c2d-99b6-71ee26cf08b6",
    "front": "**Def**: interested in things that don't concern you.\n**Farsi**: فضول/دخالت کننده",
    "back": "nosy (also nosey) (DISAPPROVING, INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "38ca9631-076c-4045-b052-577bf2b93ae7",
    "front": "**Def**: an infectious illness.\n**Farsi**: بیماری عفونی/ویروس",
    "back": "bug (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "27b30912-0c24-40ad-9880-79f61367e422",
    "front": "**Def**: deceive and trick sb, especially in order to get money from them.\n**Farsi**: کسی را فریب دادن/کلاهبرداری کردن",
    "back": "con sb (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "0945c219-1d35-4232-bd60-58995480c0fa",
    "front": "**Def**: criticism. (SYN stick).\n**Farsi**: انتقاد/توبیخ",
    "back": "flak (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "1edf3d63-a5f5-48ed-aa45-73f09bb4fdd0",
    "front": "**Def**: silly (sometimes in an amusing way).\n**Farsi**: احمقانه/مسخره",
    "back": "daft (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "ec3dc08f-26f9-4230-a149-b2539a4e2454",
    "front": "**Def**: thanks. (SYN cheers).\n**Farsi**: ممنون (کوتاه شده)",
    "back": "ta (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "5065413b-0daa-40a2-90f2-1d09d082d2d2",
    "front": "**Def**: causing suspicion; possibly dishonest.\n**Farsi**: مشکوک/ناصادق",
    "back": "dodgy (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "02f7f03c-685a-4400-9c76-65ada46c89de",
    "front": "**Def**: calm and relaxed. (SYN easy-going).\n**Farsi**: ریلکس/آرام",
    "back": "laid-back (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "8455a811-838b-4015-b8bf-5d3596a3e16c",
    "front": "**Def**: a large amount of noise. (SYN din).\n**Farsi**: سر و صدای زیاد/غوغا",
    "back": "racket (INF)"
  },
  {
    "id": "33b5ee6c-3284-4885-beb8-cc319176f097",
    "front": "**Def**: an action you will take if there is no other option (as a last resort SYN if all else fails).\n**Farsi**: آخرین چاره/مأمن",
    "back": "a last/final resort"
  },
  {
    "id": "dfaa2d1c-ac3a-4f8d-87a8-785843f4ea7b",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say the disadvantages of sth are greater than the advantages.\n**Farsi**: زحمتش بیشتر از ارزشش است",
    "back": "it's more trouble than it's worth"
  },
  {
    "id": "613a9b76-104c-4dc5-afca-a3e3a2bae091",
    "front": "**Def**: a situation in which you have the advantages of two things without any disadvantages.\n**Farsi**: بهترین وضعیت ممکن/هر دو جنبه خوب را داشتن",
    "back": "the best of both worlds"
  },
  {
    "id": "8c958880-0a43-4323-9319-08ee1915c1ab",
    "front": "**Def**: look stupid or be less respected because of sth you have done.\n**Farsi**: آبرو ریزی کردن/اعتبار خود را از دست دادن",
    "back": "lose face"
  },
  {
    "id": "6889ae20-ad42-4404-968e-82fdd9c4da87",
    "front": "**Def**: remain sensible and realistic about life.\n**Farsi**: واقع‌بین بودن/خاکی ماندن",
    "back": "keep your feet on the ground"
  },
  {
    "id": "c400f785-028e-49ef-963a-1d3d3a583e39",
    "front": "**Def**: relax and enjoy yourself.\n**Farsi**: راحت بودن/خوش گذراندن",
    "back": "let your hair down"
  },
  {
    "id": "0d4234ea-d58c-4616-9bf0-d066e36c0b24",
    "front": "**Def**: try to do sth that will almost certainly fail.\n**Farsi**: نبرد شکست خورده را ادامه دادن/تلاش بیهوده کردن",
    "back": "fight a losing battle"
  },
  {
    "id": "578b072a-5046-4f3e-abe3-c542d8b94796",
    "front": "**Def**: was very successful.\n**Farsi**: عالی کار کردن/مثل رؤیا عمل کردن",
    "back": "worked like a dream"
  },
  {
    "id": "9ba2a291-50a7-4afa-8c8f-d9d581ae9b41",
    "front": "**Def**: spend your time imagining things, and not be aware of things around you.\n**Farsi**: در عالم خود بودن/غرق در تخیلات بودن",
    "back": "live/be in a world of your own"
  },
  {
    "id": "1c87664d-bdef-4a53-9e29-7072c0532a73",
    "front": "**Def**: an action you will take if there is no other option. (SYN as a last resort)\n**Farsi**: اگر هیچ چیز دیگری کار نکند",
    "back": "if all else fails"
  },
  {
    "id": "3cad2d93-0e8f-45b3-b8f2-183a325a13dc",
    "front": "**Def**: If sth goes in one ear and out of the other, you forget it very quickly.\n**Farsi**: از این گوش شنیدن و از آن گوش در کردن",
    "back": "go in one ear and out (of) the other"
  },
  {
    "id": "a6c3f69b-d2a1-4357-ade6-76cf9753c643",
    "front": "**Def**: suddenly I cannot remember sth.\n**Farsi**: ذهن کاملاً خالی شدن/مطلب را فراموش کردن",
    "back": "my mind goes (a complete) blank"
  },
  {
    "id": "0c65872e-67a6-4abd-9966-967c405aa504",
    "front": "**Def**: be successful (get somewhere = make progress; get nowhere = make no progress).\n**Farsi**: موفق شدن/به هدف رسیدن",
    "back": "get there"
  },
  {
    "id": "a16ebb0f-fedd-4f16-8508-84f7e4a46040",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say that it is not useful doing sth. (SYNS there's no point in + -ing, it's no use + -ing).\n**Farsi**: بیهوده است که...",
    "back": "it's no good + -ing"
  },
  {
    "id": "65fbbb1d-1cad-4bf7-bd7d-7033385726cc",
    "front": "**Def**: I (/you/he, etc.) need sth.\n**Farsi**: احتیاج داشتن به چیزی",
    "back": "I (you/he, etc.) could do with sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "0d40554a-c423-4e01-b694-4db4ff411838",
    "front": "**Def**: be thinking of sb/sth for a particular purpose.\n**Farsi**: کسی/چیزی را در نظر داشتن",
    "back": "have sb/sth in mind"
  },
  {
    "id": "62eb644d-8728-4c23-9582-569cd7b0870e",
    "front": "**Def**: without thinking about sth carefully.\n**Farsi**: بدون فکر/همینطوری",
    "back": "off the top of my head"
  },
  {
    "id": "bf06fd2e-77b9-4dc2-81fa-7d4ae404456f",
    "front": "**Def**: used when advising sb what to do. (SYN the best thing (to do is ...)).\n**Farsi**: بهترین کار (برای شما) این است که",
    "back": "your best bet (is to ...)"
  },
  {
    "id": "09489e24-7d1e-49a7-9cda-df88681ac1c8",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say you don't expect sth to happen even though sb said it would.\n**Farsi**: زیاد امیدوار نباش",
    "back": "Don't hold your breath"
  },
  {
    "id": "fb4a58f4-6c05-4a94-8382-2c2ab740d7f8",
    "front": "**Def**: used to emphasize you are keen to do sth.\n**Farsi**: حتماً/بله که",
    "back": "You bet"
  },
  {
    "id": "a9c9315d-db8f-4b11-b56b-74c7c6f3d26e",
    "front": "**Def**: used to agree completely with what sb has just said.\n**Farsi**: حرفت کاملاً درست است",
    "back": "You can say that again"
  },
  {
    "id": "f2d6a16e-b92a-459c-9f29-b6964e7a251c",
    "front": "**Def**: used to express your disappointment that sth is not going to happen.\n**Farsi**: از این شانس‌ها نداریم",
    "back": "No such luck"
  },
  {
    "id": "459cbe9e-151e-48d8-a7a6-6e458d92c613",
    "front": "**Def**: used ironically to say you don't believe what sb has told you.\n**Farsi**: داستان احتمالی (کنایه: دروغ محضه)",
    "back": "A likely story"
  },
  {
    "id": "d9d47ce7-6945-4842-a3e0-b504884749c9",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say you don't know sth. (SYNS Don't ask me, Your guess is as good as mine).\n**Farsi**: کوچکترین ایده‌ای ندارم",
    "back": "I haven't the faintest idea"
  },
  {
    "id": "264f7e0c-8345-4297-838c-d716db0d9577",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say you have had a hard day.\n**Farsi**: امروز روز سختی بود",
    "back": "it's been one of those days"
  },
  {
    "id": "f4523310-00db-4ba3-9033-fd691ebf545f",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say there is no reason for sb not to do sth.\n**Farsi**: چیزی برای از دست دادن نداری",
    "back": "You've got nothing to lose"
  },
  {
    "id": "b46dc5ad-38e7-491f-8cd3-e20ea006b73d",
    "front": "**Def**: used when several unpleasant or unfortunate things happen on the same day.\n**Farsi**: امروز روز تو نیست",
    "back": "It's not your day"
  },
  {
    "id": "99e30606-cd10-4ea5-8198-684290242911",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say that sth is not at all possible or not allowed. (SYN no chance).\n**Farsi**: محال است/به هیچ وجه",
    "back": "No way"
  },
  {
    "id": "736239a6-7eff-4bb0-a6f1-6881dc1267b0",
    "front": "**Def**: used to add politeness to a question. (Also: Do you happen to know if they're married?).\n**Farsi**: احتمالاً/اگر شانسی باشد",
    "back": "by any chance"
  },
  {
    "id": "f57a6042-d3de-4cfe-aa3b-536c3b281ae5",
    "front": "**Def**: used before a question which you think may be sensitive.\n**Farsi**: اگر ناراحت نمی‌شوی بپرسم",
    "back": "If you don't mind my/me asking"
  },
  {
    "id": "44a83581-02ff-4f70-ac51-9a05aad51427",
    "front": "**Def**: used to introduce an explanation, and often one that suggests there is a problem.\n**Farsi**: نکته این است که",
    "back": "the thing is"
  },
  {
    "id": "880bf376-e720-4020-8db1-050a319555e4",
    "front": "**Def**: used to emphasize the comparative; equally good, bad, interesting, etc.\n**Farsi**: کاملاً به اندازه... خوب است",
    "back": "every bit as good as"
  },
  {
    "id": "c69573e3-c05b-40e4-91f0-9273737c82f2",
    "front": "**Def**: very embarrassed.\n**Farsi**: مثل لبو سرخ (خیلی شرمنده)",
    "back": "as red as a beetroot"
  },
  {
    "id": "55cc7634-0828-41fc-a9bc-9d2da199a13c",
    "front": "**Def**: used before giving sb surprising or exciting news.\n**Farsi**: حدس بزن چی شده!",
    "back": "Guess what!"
  },
  {
    "id": "c3e66aa0-7c01-493b-b689-847f22aa408f",
    "front": "**Def**: used to introduce information which is true but surprising.\n**Farsi**: باور کنی یا نه",
    "back": "believe it or not"
  },
  {
    "id": "63a877bc-84de-4f02-a2c3-61112954c937",
    "front": "**Def**: used to emphasize the fact that sth is not surprising.\n**Farsi**: جای تعجب نیست که",
    "back": "no wonder"
  },
  {
    "id": "4a808372-f3c7-45af-a39e-b55263a3b1b9",
    "front": "**Def**: used after wh- questions to indicate surprise, and sometimes annoyance, about sth.\n**Farsi**: در کجای زمین (تاکید بر تعجب)",
    "back": "Where on earth"
  },
  {
    "id": "02fa19d4-c2e2-4272-aa7b-caaba01f53a9",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say that sth is true if there are no other factors affecting it.\n**Farsi**: اگر همه شرایط مساوی باشد",
    "back": "all things being equal"
  },
  {
    "id": "4f12199b-794e-49fb-baaf-c6335615ecb5",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say, often with slight annoyance, that you don't know the reason or don't understand it.\n**Farsi**: به دلایلی (که نمی‌دانم)",
    "back": "for some reason"
  },
  {
    "id": "ddb88fe9-41da-4269-a825-22b8db3d0624",
    "front": "**Def**: used to agree reluctantly that sth is true.\n**Farsi**: باید اعتراف کنم",
    "back": "I have to admit"
  },
  {
    "id": "4f867a15-acb2-4f4b-9884-5dcf969a654c",
    "front": "**Def**: from one place to another and then back again, many times.\n**Farsi**: عقب و جلو/مرتب رفت و آمد کردن",
    "back": "back and forth"
  },
  {
    "id": "b031b3f7-e5eb-4ed4-a309-4ff1b516b65f",
    "front": "**Def**: for a long time.\n**Farsi**: طولانی و سخت/با دقت زیاد",
    "back": "long and hard"
  },
  {
    "id": "4cd75c28-b223-4d42-b7f3-f7866a94a48e",
    "front": "**Def**: at some time in the future.\n**Farsi**: دیر یا زود",
    "back": "sooner or later"
  },
  {
    "id": "a17b4b6e-cb59-4757-b4a0-acb566859d5a",
    "front": "**Def**: with the back where the front should be.\n**Farsi**: پشت و رو/برعکس",
    "back": "back to front"
  },
  {
    "id": "c108c492-38e8-4c2e-8860-f3276098641b",
    "front": "**Def**: busy and noisy activity.\n**Farsi**: شلوغی و هیاهو",
    "back": "hustle and bustle"
  },
  {
    "id": "dd903d48-cb5d-4e4c-b7dd-a315816cd20b",
    "front": "**Def**: a process of trying to solve a problem in different ways until you are successful.\n**Farsi**: آزمون و خطا",
    "back": "trial and error"
  },
  {
    "id": "855ebbbc-eebc-47f9-b55e-9b6a34697633",
    "front": "**Def**: things you want to achieve.\n**Farsi**: اهداف و مقاصد",
    "back": "aims and objectives"
  },
  {
    "id": "dba88300-d21e-4c7a-a249-af6a4b470e76",
    "front": "**Def**: rules.\n**Farsi**: قواعد و مقررات",
    "back": "rules and regulations"
  },
  {
    "id": "37a4cbfb-50dc-4cd5-b59a-bc98b520bc1e",
    "front": "**Def**: safe and peaceful conditions in society when people obey the law.\n**Farsi**: نظم و قانون",
    "back": "law and order"
  },
  {
    "id": "20854a0b-8dea-45b7-809e-928425aab8e3",
    "front": "**Def**: happy and lively.\n**Farsi**: شاد و سرزنده",
    "back": "bright and cheerful"
  },
  {
    "id": "8dea23dc-f8ba-4587-9dd4-6a916d4ff42d",
    "front": "**Def**: safely; not harmed, damaged, lost, etc.\n**Farsi**: سالم و سلامت",
    "back": "safe and sound"
  },
  {
    "id": "49147b13-3741-4fea-931a-da55ebf948be",
    "front": "**Def**: bored with or annoyed about sth, and wanting it to stop.\n**Farsi**: خسته و دلزده از",
    "back": "sick and tired of (SYN fed up with sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "28e7c46e-b1e1-4d77-a5f6-aec9cd30d447",
    "front": "**Def**: choose only those things that you like or want.\n**Farsi**: گلچین کردن/انتخاب کردن (بدون محدودیت)",
    "back": "pick and choose"
  },
  {
    "id": "c859c7b5-6464-4848-86ef-eaa38da33a23",
    "front": "**Def**: push in a rough way.\n**Farsi**: هل دادن و تنه زدن",
    "back": "pushing and shoving"
  },
  {
    "id": "118cb692-f4bd-447a-8b3a-ccbf406c9b2b",
    "front": "**Def**: well behaved.\n**Farsi**: مثل طلا بودن (خیلی خوب رفتار کردن)",
    "back": "as good as gold"
  },
  {
    "id": "54806c7e-1744-4dd0-856f-ffa2f5dcdce5",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely light.\n**Farsi**: مثل پر سبک",
    "back": "as light as a feather"
  },
  {
    "id": "874c813a-5020-4c18-b307-038a3fa8b776",
    "front": "**Def**: cannot see well.\n**Farsi**: مثل خفاش کور (خیلی ضعیف دیدن)",
    "back": "blind as a bat (humorously)"
  },
  {
    "id": "46ddda5b-5c10-475a-a14a-e1221edfd978",
    "front": "**Def**: cannot hear well.\n**Farsi**: مثل ستون کر (هیچ چیز نشنیدن)",
    "back": "deaf as a post (humorously)"
  },
  {
    "id": "45cd4787-e69e-462b-aa7d-4f7be403b0d7",
    "front": "**Def**: very strong.\n**Farsi**: مثل گاو نر قوی",
    "back": "as strong as an ox"
  },
  {
    "id": "a0e3cbfc-3b7e-491a-ad14-2ad194cde598",
    "front": "**Def**: very thin.\n**Farsi**: مثل چنگک لاغر",
    "back": "as thin as a rake"
  },
  {
    "id": "4ed21b22-e6d5-4fd6-8429-d7e17d4dc772",
    "front": "**Def**: very quiet.\n**Farsi**: مثل موش ساکت",
    "back": "as quiet as a mouse"
  },
  {
    "id": "8111807c-1c9a-4373-82e7-7e18b8276cea",
    "front": "**Def**: white with fear or illness.\n**Farsi**: مثل گچ سفید (از ترس یا بیماری)",
    "back": "as white as a sheet"
  },
  {
    "id": "145834be-591d-4af2-bf4b-9aff5a257241",
    "front": "**Def**: dissuade them from doing it.\n**Farsi**: کسی را از انجام کاری منصرف کردن",
    "back": "talk someone out of doing something"
  },
  {
    "id": "d7ed26b3-a06d-4224-a97d-1d0944561eba",
    "front": "**Def**: raise the topic.\n**Farsi**: موضوعی را مطرح کردن",
    "back": "bring a topic up"
  },
  {
    "id": "ff230c16-1348-4c75-8909-c726474be231",
    "front": "**Def**: communicate with them clearly.\n**Farsi**: منظور خود را واضح رساندن، تفهیم کردن",
    "back": "get your ideas across"
  },
  {
    "id": "22b759fc-36fb-49d3-a14c-3611cba956e7",
    "front": "**Def**: interrupt a conversation.\n**Farsi**: میان صحبت کسی پریدن، دخالت کردن",
    "back": "butt in (on a conversation)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b9ede7f3-e5af-4f56-9e6f-98fedbc9922d",
    "front": "**Def**: prolong it (= make it longer than necessary).\n**Farsi**: به درازا کشاندن، طول دادن",
    "back": "drag out (a discussion)"
  },
  {
    "id": "9c3ec86d-981f-4e3e-ae2b-d0e844909c23",
    "front": "**Def**: confess to it (= admit you did sth wrong).\n**Farsi**: اعتراف کردن، گردن گرفتن (خطا)",
    "back": "own up (to something)"
  },
  {
    "id": "3fc0a6e3-a9d8-4e17-a533-49b2aa4d19ee",
    "front": "**Def**: criticize you for sth you have done.\n**Farsi**: سرزنش کردن، ایراد گرفتن، غر زدن",
    "back": "go on at you"
  },
  {
    "id": "7c48ca16-ff0e-455e-9020-be82862268b6",
    "front": "**Def**: retaliate (against them).\n**Farsi**: تلافی کردن، مقابله به مثل کردن",
    "back": "hit back at someone"
  },
  {
    "id": "e3068a20-3907-435a-8ed0-d55e4be7fa64",
    "front": "**Def**: abolish it.\n**Farsi**: لغو کردن، منسوخ کردن",
    "back": "do away with (a tax)"
  },
  {
    "id": "bb7aeafb-f42d-4b9b-a854-73d2bc71b449",
    "front": "**Def**: cancel it.\n**Farsi**: لغو کردن",
    "back": "call off (a meeting)"
  },
  {
    "id": "07e222bb-f3bb-4b13-bbb0-347cbeaafefa",
    "front": "**Def**: compensate for it (= do sth good to balance the bad effects of it).\n**Farsi**: جبران کردن",
    "back": "make up for something"
  },
  {
    "id": "cf1af4ff-8e97-4099-8fc7-78f6c8cde7f4",
    "front": "**Def**: claim that they are rich (= say that they are rich even though it may not be true).\n**Farsi**: ادعا کردن، وانمود کردن",
    "back": "make out that they're rich"
  },
  {
    "id": "1a5dc02e-69b0-45f7-bdfe-3b8b5df46086",
    "front": "**Def**: be deceived by it.\n**Farsi**: فریب خوردن، گول خوردن",
    "back": "be taken in by charm"
  },
  {
    "id": "c793973e-770f-4707-ab04-582bef3a088f",
    "front": "**Def**: be reconciled with them (= become friends with them after a disagreement).\n**Farsi**: آشتی کردن، دوباره دوست شدن",
    "back": "make it up (with them)"
  },
  {
    "id": "5bc2b517-e54c-41e6-a4a6-65a5b5e23a27",
    "front": "**Def**: dismantle it (also take it to pieces).\n**Farsi**: از هم باز کردن، پیاده کردن (دستگاه)",
    "back": "take a machine apart"
  },
  {
    "id": "04447445-7187-4228-9916-3518330d9759",
    "front": "**Def**: meet sb by chance.\n**Farsi**: تصادفاً کسی را دیدن",
    "back": "bump into sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "20d4363a-cbae-4d6a-82cd-443145c65250",
    "front": "**Def**: ask sb how sb else is, or what they are doing.\n**Farsi**: احوال کسی را پرسیدن",
    "back": "ask after sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "7b56faba-60e4-4ea2-a10a-251b0bf9a307",
    "front": "**Def**: arrive where you have arranged to meet sb. SYN turn up.\n**Farsi**: حاضر شدن، آمدن",
    "back": "show up"
  },
  {
    "id": "b1e53ea9-2d8f-4f8a-a035-de3abae6c517",
    "front": "**Def**: happen unexpectedly. SYN come up.\n**Farsi**: ناگهانی رخ دادن، پیش آمد کردن",
    "back": "crop up"
  },
  {
    "id": "2321e376-2086-43f6-b22d-df8b6b525506",
    "front": "**Def**: become sick or ill with sth. SYN catch sth.\n**Farsi**: مریض شدن، مبتلا شدن",
    "back": "go down with sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "c2cb8cbb-ece6-4136-81d1-cf5218953d64",
    "front": "**Def**: get rid of sth, such as an illness or a problem.\n**Farsi**: از شر چیزی خلاص شدن، رفع کردن (بیماری)",
    "back": "shake sth off"
  },
  {
    "id": "666d6bfc-05f5-424e-9667-860ccab2979d",
    "front": "**Def**: (of a pain, a feeling, or an effect) gradually disappear or stop.\n**Farsi**: از بین رفتن تدریجی (اثر، درد)",
    "back": "wear off"
  },
  {
    "id": "cb66f642-0b96-4bf8-99d3-a6d27e138b0d",
    "front": "**Def**: miss an opportunity to do or have sth.\n**Farsi**: فرصتی را از دست دادن",
    "back": "miss out on sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "499f4152-25c0-4429-9048-fddaf7d62c99",
    "front": "**Def**: learn a new skill easily and without effort.\n**Farsi**: یاد گرفتن، آموختن (مهارت)",
    "back": "pick sth up (skill)"
  },
  {
    "id": "783300cf-f8d4-4c8c-bb50-b9d7386a564c",
    "front": "**Def**: If you get by in a language, you can speak at a basic level.\n**Farsi**: در حد پایه از پس زبانی برآمدن",
    "back": "get by (language)"
  },
  {
    "id": "c9a3e8d8-36fb-46b1-8a26-69f84246146e",
    "front": "**Def**: become completely understood or able to be remembered.\n**Farsi**: کاملاً درک شدن، جا افتادن (مطلب)",
    "back": "sink in"
  },
  {
    "id": "5b6915d9-f0bd-46e0-bcde-13a89d2c50d5",
    "front": "**Def**: continue to work in a determined way to achieve sth.\n**Farsi**: با پشتکار ادامه دادن، به کاری چسبیدن",
    "back": "stick at sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "bde0ad76-e8db-43be-b11b-dae5935f83e9",
    "front": "**Def**: used to change the conversation to a different topic. SYN by the way.\n**Farsi**: راستی، اتفاقاً (تغییر موضوع)",
    "back": "incidentally"
  },
  {
    "id": "ff98dd7c-a430-47b6-be1b-b8e745ef255a",
    "front": "**Def**: used to start talking about sb or sth new that is connected with what you were talking about before.\n**Farsi**: در مورد، اما در خصوص",
    "back": "as for"
  },
  {
    "id": "91eae5b0-8221-4a78-bb47-6fe479a1e2a1",
    "front": "**Def**: used to introduce an idea that is a second choice or possibility.\n**Farsi**: یا به عنوان جایگزین، متناوباً",
    "back": "alternatively"
  },
  {
    "id": "e4799f1c-d19c-4863-912d-65a59a0b564b",
    "front": "**Def**: used to agree with an idea made by the previous speaker (but often before disagreeing). SYN I agree.\n**Farsi**: حقیقت این است که، درست است که",
    "back": "it's true"
  },
  {
    "id": "d7be2eaf-b676-4e22-b1e3-c6655f93b090",
    "front": "**Def**: used to introduce a counter-argument or return to one the speaker has already made. SYNS all the same, nevertheless.\n**Farsi**: با این وجود، حتی با این حال",
    "back": "even so"
  },
  {
    "id": "5aa95822-be73-4476-80dc-67b0127f8238",
    "front": "**Def**: used to introduce a generalization. SYNS to a large extent, on the whole, broadly speaking.\n**Farsi**: روی هم رفته، به طور کلی، عمدتاً",
    "back": "by and large"
  },
  {
    "id": "fa018e7b-218d-41db-b473-ce5805290c4c",
    "front": "**Def**: used to introduce an additional point and one that is often conclusive or the most important. SYNS besides, anyway.\n**Farsi**: در هر صورت، به هر حال",
    "back": "in any case"
  },
  {
    "id": "bc7c8d46-2082-4e41-9919-e976e0d829f8",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say that sth is true or sth will happen in spite of other things mentioned. SYNS anyway, anyhow.\n**Farsi**: دست کم، به هر حال",
    "back": "at any rate"
  },
  {
    "id": "97b6d756-9659-4f65-bf0f-db5728e9e449",
    "front": "**Def**: used to return the conversation to sth you said earlier.\n**Farsi**: همانطور که می‌گفتم",
    "back": "as I was saying"
  },
  {
    "id": "41e039e1-ad28-4a55-ac4d-3a81dd2b972c",
    "front": "**Def**: commonly used to change the topic of conversation.\n**Farsi**: خلاصه، بگذریم (برای تغییر موضوع)",
    "back": "anyway (topic change)"
  },
  {
    "id": "ec6fcbd0-b0f3-4075-87b8-3b4f76a0b34e",
    "front": "**Def**: used after a number, quantity, etc. to show that it is approximate. SYN or so.\n**Farsi**: حدوداً، تقریباً",
    "back": "or thereabouts"
  },
  {
    "id": "65c137d8-b0a1-4257-b2b0-29b5ce811b47",
    "front": "**Def**: INF a large quantity of sth. SYNS tons/loads/bags of sth INF.\n**Farsi**: مقدار زیادی، توده ای از چیزی",
    "back": "stacks of sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "72b9477a-6ec4-46a6-bdcf-1ba95dde1cf7",
    "front": "**Def**: (used before a number) approximately. SYN round about.\n**Farsi**: حدوداً، در حوالی (یک عدد)",
    "back": "(somewhere) in the region of"
  },
  {
    "id": "32c32d2a-6cac-43b9-a232-cd099b22f2e2",
    "front": "**Def**: in some way connected with (sth).\n**Farsi**: مربوط به چیزی بودن، در ارتباط با چیزی بودن",
    "back": "something to do with (sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "3f5d1f52-472b-4019-a539-eeb5c03adeb4",
    "front": "**Def**: INF to some extent, but in a way that is hard to explain. SYN sort of.\n**Farsi**: تا حدی، تقریباً، یک جورهایی",
    "back": "kind of"
  },
  {
    "id": "5b56e697-5fd9-4f72-9938-172a88ced678",
    "front": "**Def**: in some way or by some means, although you don't know exactly how.\n**Farsi**: به هر حال، به هر طریقی",
    "back": "somehow (or other)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f7ea7c33-9f40-45a6-8b88-361ad2a939af",
    "front": "**Def**: used for talking about numbers which are not exact.\n**Farsi**: با کمی اختلاف، کم و بیش",
    "back": "give or take sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "8cedbc1e-dfcb-4e0e-a4a6-36265a1bddc4",
    "front": "**Def**: INF used to refer to things when it is obvious what you are talking about, or you don't know the name, or the name isn't important.\n**Farsi**: وسایل، چیزها، خرت و پرت",
    "back": "stuff"
  },
  {
    "id": "e509bed5-0553-45d5-b784-2c04189cf826",
    "front": "**Def**: INF (after a number) a little more or less than the number (thirty-odd people).\n**Farsi**: خورده‌ای، اندکی بیشتر یا کمتر از آن عدد",
    "back": "(-)odd"
  },
  {
    "id": "226061cd-628d-4625-81b8-e617db3767f8",
    "front": "**Def**: used when being vague.\n**Farsi**: یا چیزی شبیه آن",
    "back": "or something"
  },
  {
    "id": "e8e48f9b-0a98-44e0-8f45-36e0e8c4c458",
    "front": "**Def**: used when being vague.\n**Farsi**: یا چیزی از آن قبیل",
    "back": "or something of that sort"
  },
  {
    "id": "86cf174f-c668-4b69-b4f3-21054a50b254",
    "front": "**Def**: used when you think sb is being too confident about something that is going to happen.\n**Farsi**: (کنایه): این حرف را نزن، صبر کن ببینیم چه می‌شود!",
    "back": "famous last words"
  },
  {
    "id": "e823de10-6e7d-4f85-816a-486e8b4f8836",
    "front": "**Def**: people will be served or dealt with in the order in which they arrive or ask for sth.\n**Farsi**: اولویت با کسی است که زودتر می‌رسد",
    "back": "first come, first served"
  },
  {
    "id": "872ab582-83ad-4888-b4a9-026e9a0e7566",
    "front": "**Def**: write or say sth clearly or firmly.\n**Farsi**: اظهار کردن، بیان کردن",
    "back": "state sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "b75d5a71-f5c1-40eb-a1f9-88d3f6f7a2a9",
    "front": "**Def**: after an unpleasant experience, you are careful to avoid sth similar.\n**Farsi**: مارگزیده از ریسمان سیاه و سفید می‌ترسد",
    "back": "once bitten, twice shy"
  },
  {
    "id": "aa3cd31b-b928-4e65-bc7c-7ef1d1d8b1b3",
    "front": "**Def**: it is easy to talk about something, but it is much more difficult to do it.\n**Farsi**: گفتنش آسان‌تر از عمل کردن به آن است",
    "back": "easier said than done"
  },
  {
    "id": "83cc13e2-63b6-4baf-a934-907107b32993",
    "front": "**Def**: if there are more people or things, the situation will be better and more enjoyable.\n**Farsi**: هرچه بیشتر، بهتر",
    "back": "the more the merrier"
  },
  {
    "id": "ef3429fb-7cfa-4fad-b1bf-e59e23f000ac",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say that everything is fine at the moment but you know things may become more difficult.\n**Farsi**: تا اینجای کار خوب پیش رفته است",
    "back": "so far, so good"
  },
  {
    "id": "f1923a03-718a-4f58-84b4-2c0384bba8dd",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say that sb stops thinking about people when they are not with them.\n**Farsi**: از دل برود هر آنکه از دیده رود",
    "back": "out of sight, out of mind"
  },
  {
    "id": "ecc18401-86c3-4a02-b630-f284445b6fce",
    "front": "**Def**: used to express your surprise when you meet sb you know unexpectedly.\n**Farsi**: دنیا خیلی کوچک است",
    "back": "it's a small world"
  },
  {
    "id": "c922b1b5-a66e-40fa-99a0-2d85bcdb46c0",
    "front": "**Def**: used about sb who criticizes people for faults that they have themselves.\n**Farsi**: دیگ به دیگ می‌گوید رویت سیاه است",
    "back": "the pot calling the kettle black"
  },
  {
    "id": "762a819e-f7d5-47e7-80bd-c1342f6a3272",
    "front": "**Def**: If you have a lot of money, you will have more power and influence than other people.\n**Farsi**: پول حرف اول را می‌زند",
    "back": "money talks"
  },
  {
    "id": "8b84067e-4b8d-4611-b8bc-0e5066c335da",
    "front": "**Def**: When you love somebody, you cannot see their faults.\n**Farsi**: عشق کور است",
    "back": "love is blind"
  },
  {
    "id": "a6655922-cd53-4f85-9ca3-f36c5a15e092",
    "front": "**Def**: An unusual or unpleasant event won't happen in the same place or to the same person twice.\n**Farsi**: بلا و حادثه دو بار در یک جا یا برای یک نفر رخ نمی‌دهد",
    "back": "lightning never strikes twice (in the same place)"
  },
  {
    "id": "9b8e8730-b718-4c14-b24f-fbef1b83fb33",
    "front": "**Def**: Avoid mentioning a particularly difficult subject which may cause trouble.\n**Farsi**: سر به سر موضوعات حساس نگذار",
    "back": "let sleeping dogs lie"
  },
  {
    "id": "1b3a223c-b139-42f2-99ae-431449fdb351",
    "front": "**Def**: If you do sth repeatedly, you will become very good at it.\n**Farsi**: کار نیکو کردن از پر کردن است، تمرین باعث کمال می‌شود",
    "back": "practice makes perfect"
  },
  {
    "id": "db0bda80-5429-4a15-8e41-89d9d8b646b8",
    "front": "**Def**: If you haven't had any news, then it's probable that nothing has gone wrong and things are fine.\n**Farsi**: بی‌خبری، خوش خبری است",
    "back": "no news is good news"
  },
  {
    "id": "17b2f99f-ba08-4dea-b5a3-6289f1f7baa2",
    "front": "**Def**: Bad or unfair methods of doing sth are acceptable if the results of the action are good or positive.\n**Farsi**: هدف وسیله را توجیه می‌کند",
    "back": "the end justifies the means"
  },
  {
    "id": "d55d751c-9e8b-48b8-b14f-a955d30893b8",
    "front": "**Def**: If sb does sth bad to you, that is not a reason to do sth bad to them.\n**Farsi**: بدی را با بدی جواب نمی‌دهند",
    "back": "two wrongs don't make a right"
  },
  {
    "id": "7f6b18ba-8b01-4c6d-b4f1-acb2042a0c18",
    "front": "**Def**: Two people can achieve more than one person working alone.\n**Farsi**: دو مغز بهتر از یکی کار می‌کند، همکاری بهتر است",
    "back": "two heads are better than one"
  },
  {
    "id": "7edc5221-4971-4a9b-978d-4b5812c267c6",
    "front": "**Def**: Family relationships are stronger than any other.\n**Farsi**: خون از آب غلیظ‌تر است، خویشاوندی از هر چیز دیگری مهم‌تر است",
    "back": "blood is thicker than water"
  },
  {
    "id": "1294176f-7453-46c4-9034-9bc1dc8dc842",
    "front": "**Def**: What a person actually does is more important than what they say they will do.\n**Farsi**: عمل مهم‌تر از حرف است، دو صد گفته چون نیم کردار نیست",
    "back": "actions speak louder than words"
  },
  {
    "id": "4440112f-f663-4e40-80f1-0b89169d5402",
    "front": "**Def**: Used to say that you should punish somebody by doing to them what they have done to you.\n**Farsi**: چشم در برابر چشم، قصاص",
    "back": "an eye for an eye (and a tooth for a tooth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "c9ea9698-cb6b-4c97-b953-d97109677f0a",
    "front": "**Def**: You should help and care for your own family first before you start helping others.\n**Farsi**: چراغی که به خانه رواست به مسجد حرام است",
    "back": "charity begins at home"
  },
  {
    "id": "84cade54-b0dd-4d26-a596-98c314f1e10a",
    "front": "**Def**: How someone looks is less important than their character.\n**Farsi**: زیبایی ظاهری مهم نیست، زیبایی باطنی مهم‌تر است",
    "back": "beauty is only skin-deep"
  },
  {
    "id": "552aff4e-683b-4be7-a4b9-46695415a1c6",
    "front": "**Def**: It is better to arrive late or achieve sth late, than not arrive or achieve anything at all.\n**Farsi**: دیر رسیدن بهتر از هرگز نرسیدن است",
    "back": "better late than never"
  },
  {
    "id": "627c5763-5af7-4e0f-9c4c-a0321c3ba466",
    "front": "**Def**: Accept other people's opinions and ways of life, even if they are different from your own. A motto is a phrase which expresses the beliefs of a person or organization.\n**Farsi**: بگذار دیگران هم زندگی کنند، تحمل عقاید دیگران",
    "back": "live and let live"
  },
  {
    "id": "1ddd2f33-2cfe-48c9-bf4e-b43ecd4d68c0",
    "front": "**Def**: Young people should enjoy themselves because in later life they will have more to worry about.\n**Farsi**: جوانی یک بار است، از جوانی‌ات لذت ببر",
    "back": "you're only young once"
  },
  {
    "id": "3538868c-fab5-4168-ae66-2cb1ab210def",
    "front": "**Def**: It is better to stop something bad from happening than try to deal with it after it has happened.\n**Farsi**: پیشگیری بهتر از درمان است",
    "back": "prevention is better than cure"
  },
  {
    "id": "8f500026-d384-4280-9183-bc64be79b33a",
    "front": "**Def**: used for giving information.\n**Farsi**: به اطلاع شما می‌رسانم که",
    "back": "inform you that"
  },
  {
    "id": "2b2305b6-d6db-4346-9ba8-daf2f62972dd",
    "front": "**Def**: a plan to do sth.\n**Farsi**: قصد، نیت",
    "back": "intention"
  },
  {
    "id": "bcd6c65f-b91c-45bc-96f1-77e44d6052e6",
    "front": "**Def**: end or stop sth.\n**Farsi**: خاتمه دادن، پایان دادن",
    "back": "terminate sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "00ec828b-7135-4ed0-ab82-1643f57e671d",
    "front": "**Def**: a legal agreement for renting a property.\n**Farsi**: اجاره‌نامه، قرارداد اجاره",
    "back": "lease"
  },
  {
    "id": "d25acf0e-d01b-487f-8e6f-da13e64d5f80",
    "front": "**Def**: used for asking a question or making a request.\n**Farsi**: پرسیدن، استعلام کردن (که آیا...)",
    "back": "enquire whether"
  },
  {
    "id": "4ce30656-d7af-4de9-a1a6-9173be35653a",
    "front": "**Def**: used for giving bad news.\n**Farsi**: متأسفانه به اطلاع شما می‌رسانم که",
    "back": "regret to inform you that"
  },
  {
    "id": "e48967c6-7688-4f8c-9d5b-e77cd992e80f",
    "front": "**Def**: used for giving good news.\n**Farsi**: بسیار خوشحالم به اطلاع شما برسانم که",
    "back": "delighted to inform you that"
  },
  {
    "id": "271811db-7129-4ffe-a116-919a4a8af4b8",
    "front": "**Def**: used for replying to an advertisement, etc.\n**Farsi**: در پاسخ به",
    "back": "in response to"
  },
  {
    "id": "6358bec7-29a5-4aa8-bc84-5536a43b959a",
    "front": "**Def**: an urgent or sincere request for people to give money, help, etc.\n**Farsi**: درخواست کمک، تقاضا",
    "back": "appeal for sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "d90ce789-0057-4a62-b2d6-f9ef61d2a727",
    "front": "**Def**: used for expressing apologies, sympathy, etc.\n**Farsi**: تسلیت صمیمانه",
    "back": "sincere condolences"
  },
  {
    "id": "8fa41b4b-49d7-4070-8925-cd4c1994c398",
    "front": "**Def**: expressing what you really think or feel. SYN genuine.\n**Farsi**: صمیمانه، قلبی، واقعی",
    "back": "sincere (adj)"
  },
  {
    "id": "c2574a24-8547-4830-82e5-6c8dbc4e5c60",
    "front": "**Def**: the things you say to show sympathy when sb has just died.\n**Farsi**: تسلیت",
    "back": "condolences (n)"
  },
  {
    "id": "05f0af72-9934-4173-bd79-94adc376baac",
    "front": "**Def**: used to refer to a previous conversation with the receiver, or a letter/email from them.\n**Farsi**: پیرو (مذاکره/نامه قبلی)",
    "back": "further to"
  },
  {
    "id": "944d2b45-9fde-4d2d-987f-f10bb36e9304",
    "front": "**Def**: used to refer to a previous conversation. SYN Further to.\n**Farsi**: متعاقب، بعد از",
    "back": "following (our conversation)"
  },
  {
    "id": "14f9e0f9-fe76-49d4-8e20-8d57ca1c0f68",
    "front": "**Def**: used to refer to a previous letter.\n**Farsi**: در جواب، در پاسخ به",
    "back": "in reply to"
  },
  {
    "id": "e98d6158-f1c8-4398-b9ec-83b18b4c6510",
    "front": "**Def**: used to refer to a previous letter.\n**Farsi**: با اشاره به",
    "back": "with reference to"
  },
  {
    "id": "0875d62b-2fe3-486a-a01b-b8475e860624",
    "front": "**Def**: about. SYN regarding.\n**Farsi**: در خصوص، راجع به",
    "back": "concerning"
  },
  {
    "id": "246d54b2-4440-4bd6-9986-9a0f38f6e588",
    "front": "**Def**: used to refer to sth in the body of the letter or included with it.\n**Farsi**: لطفاً ضمیمه را ملاحظه فرمایید",
    "back": "please find enclosed"
  },
  {
    "id": "b52fab98-ca80-4c95-89c0-5ee25faa553c",
    "front": "**Def**: used to refer to sth in the body of the letter.\n**Farsi**: همانطور که در (رزومه) مشاهده خواهید کرد",
    "back": "as you will see from"
  },
  {
    "id": "a5fec115-d876-4f52-9a46-1e5fea3fd898",
    "front": "**Def**: used to refer to sth that is relevant to the subject of the letter.\n**Farsi**: توجه شما را به ... جلب می‌کنم",
    "back": "draw your attention to"
  },
  {
    "id": "6ae3ed5a-86ea-49f9-829c-00c3471be67d",
    "front": "**Def**: commonly used at the end of a formal letter or offer (more formal equivalent of if).\n**Farsi**: در صورت نیاز به اطلاعات بیشتر",
    "back": "should you require"
  },
  {
    "id": "4904dd2d-c228-4a96-b31d-7cc6672041b3",
    "front": "**Def**: used at the end of a formal letter.\n**Farsi**: در تماس گرفتن با من تردید نکنید",
    "back": "do not hesitate to contact me"
  },
  {
    "id": "982a9274-ea07-45b6-a690-030df7390745",
    "front": "**Def**: used to make a request, or ask for action to be taken.\n**Farsi**: ممنون می‌شوم اگر بتوانید با من تماس بگیرید",
    "back": "I would be grateful if you could contact me"
  },
  {
    "id": "530b8c98-5c66-4789-a1bc-e83cd09bb575",
    "front": "**Def**: used to end a formal letter.\n**Farsi**: مشتاق دیدار/شنیدن اخبار شما هستم",
    "back": "look forward to meeting/hearing"
  },
  {
    "id": "21de8a44-bee7-435d-ab1d-1cd6962e95ec",
    "front": "**Def**: the main part of a book, article, text, etc.\n**Farsi**: متن اصلی",
    "back": "body (of the letter)"
  },
  {
    "id": "927373fc-ea59-4eaa-a93e-86de909cb6ca",
    "front": "**Def**: the ideas or information in a book, letter, painting, etc.\n**Farsi**: موضوع، محتوا",
    "back": "subject matter"
  },
  {
    "id": "23e6a933-d40d-4bd4-b3b0-e31112852b9d",
    "front": "**Def**: explain the details of sth in a simple, clear way.\n**Farsi**: با جزئیات کامل توضیح دادن",
    "back": "spell sth out"
  },
  {
    "id": "95ce9843-46f6-4be7-b354-c070d0dfc911",
    "front": "**Def**: the general attitude or feeling expressed in a piece of writing.\n**Farsi**: لحن",
    "back": "tone"
  },
  {
    "id": "f91ec78e-b861-4df9-b90d-14b45d32c4f6",
    "front": "**Def**: expressed clearly and without using any unnecessary words.\n**Farsi**: مختصر و مفید، ایجاز",
    "back": "concise"
  },
  {
    "id": "1b6e433d-aabc-4746-83fb-538ee6133477",
    "front": "**Def**: relevant and without any extra information. SYN pertinent.\n**Farsi**: مرتبط، نکته‌ای، مفید",
    "back": "to the point"
  },
  {
    "id": "407fda1c-b966-4bd2-ad1c-5f06608a94da",
    "front": "**Def**: unnecessary.\n**Farsi**: اضافی، غیرضروری",
    "back": "superfluous"
  },
  {
    "id": "f4060061-4868-43a4-ba4c-9f23d374d9ce",
    "front": "**Def**: saying what you think even if it offends or upsets people.\n**Farsi**: رک و پوست کنده، بی‌پرده",
    "back": "blunt"
  },
  {
    "id": "3d579029-9909-4cfd-a9cc-1c2c4e2cff67",
    "front": "**Def**: speaking or acting with few words and in a way that seems unfriendly or rude. SYNS brusque, curt.\n**Farsi**: تند، گستاخانه",
    "back": "abrupt"
  },
  {
    "id": "b9b12a38-8ba7-46cc-a520-96e9534e08c9",
    "front": "**Def**: without unnecessary detail; clear.\n**Farsi**: ساده، واضح",
    "back": "plain (language)"
  },
  {
    "id": "dc8d1339-b839-43ee-b1b0-0a03ab92a059",
    "front": "**Def**: an example, or small amount, of sth to show what all of it is like.\n**Farsi**: نمونه",
    "back": "sample"
  },
  {
    "id": "4be4d79c-524d-4196-9cb7-1386925c2f06",
    "front": "**Def**: before sth.\n**Farsi**: قبل از، پیش از",
    "back": "prior to sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "fad24726-bb0a-479e-a8f4-af6057f31d5c",
    "front": "**Def**: therefore. SYN hence.\n**Farsi**: بنابراین، در نتیجه",
    "back": "thus"
  },
  {
    "id": "5b451adb-7d61-4f3d-a971-d4d44365d749",
    "front": "**Def**: relating to a particular person or subject. SYNS concerning sth, regarding sth.\n**Farsi**: در خصوص، با توجه به",
    "back": "with/in regard to sb/sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "1d51528b-2c41-495a-87d8-7f4e0683538f",
    "front": "**Def**: although.\n**Farsi**: اگرچه، هرچند",
    "back": "albeit"
  },
  {
    "id": "c59475cc-8e1e-434d-ba84-c9f021b86064",
    "front": "**Def**: in spite of.\n**Farsi**: علیرغم، با وجود",
    "back": "notwithstanding"
  },
  {
    "id": "34375d83-a878-4cde-b2d8-4123bd860fb2",
    "front": "**Def**: used in writing or a formal speech to show that you are about to finish what you are saying.\n**Farsi**: در نتیجه، در پایان",
    "back": "in conclusion"
  },
  {
    "id": "26ec9ec5-cb48-4986-b2b7-a74d97069566",
    "front": "**Def**: up to this time.\n**Farsi**: تا به امروز، تا کنون",
    "back": "hitherto"
  },
  {
    "id": "0b4de232-cc2e-4f9a-94e1-cd3473f0acdf",
    "front": "**Def**: from this time on.\n**Farsi**: از این پس، زین پس",
    "back": "henceforth"
  },
  {
    "id": "63ef178c-aaf9-4102-b113-231fca8a6566",
    "front": "**Def**: discussing different ideas.\n**Farsi**: استدلالی، گفتمانی",
    "back": "discursive (writing)"
  },
  {
    "id": "85d2db17-7b17-4d89-8f1e-d9cb9faab2d8",
    "front": "**Def**: a set of reasons that sb uses to show that sth is true or correct.\n**Farsi**: استدلال، برهان",
    "back": "argument"
  },
  {
    "id": "d5c97c31-e1be-44ed-b6cd-4f6ce35b84ff",
    "front": "**Def**: form an opinion of sth after careful thought. evaluation N. SYN assess sth.\n**Farsi**: ارزیابی کردن، سنجیدن",
    "back": "evaluate sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "77fcc6fc-5617-4ad0-bf0d-2bf76d391e70",
    "front": "**Def**: give a short statement that brings together the main points of sth. SYN sum sth up. summary N.\n**Farsi**: خلاصه کردن",
    "back": "summarize sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "c4719a32-04fc-4e13-b969-9f6d10d0e30f",
    "front": "**Def**: a standard or principle by which sth is judged.\n**Farsi**: معیار، ملاک (معیارها)",
    "back": "criterion (PL criteria)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f271a8aa-f2ac-414f-bed0-c217282c9439",
    "front": "**Def**: (of writing) clear and comprehensible, with each part following on logically from the one before. OPP incoherent. coherence N.\n**Farsi**: منسجم، پیوسته",
    "back": "coherent"
  },
  {
    "id": "e1d8bf29-a84b-4eb5-bbb2-a24606909877",
    "front": "**Def**: a knowledge of sth and an ability to use it well.\n**Farsi**: تسلط (به زبان یا مهارت)",
    "back": "command of sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "3233db4f-dbe4-4514-905c-7d78e29b49a8",
    "front": "**Def**: connected to the way a writer or artist does sth. style N.\n**Farsi**: سبکی، مربوط به شیوه نگارش",
    "back": "stylistic"
  },
  {
    "id": "e157b820-8b31-4496-8061-be6561bf6ad5",
    "front": "**Def**: the words, grammar, and style that sb uses in a particular situation, e.g. formal.\n**Farsi**: سطح زبان (رسمی یا غیررسمی)",
    "back": "register"
  },
  {
    "id": "57a4f010-708a-4dac-8203-92c797e59ac8",
    "front": "**Def**: a description of events, especially in a novel. SYN story (the person is a narrator).\n**Farsi**: روایت، داستان‌سرایی",
    "back": "narrative"
  },
  {
    "id": "8df14554-8d52-4b8d-9692-ed4b02cacbc1",
    "front": "**Def**: give a description of the main points involved in sth. outline N.\n**Farsi**: رئوس مطالب را بیان کردن",
    "back": "outline sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "4f42699c-1fa9-4113-905f-cae923ca4814",
    "front": "**Def**: examine, discuss, or think about sth carefully. SYN analyse sth.\n**Farsi**: موشکافی کردن، عمیقاً بررسی کردن",
    "back": "explore sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "c93f89d8-cf86-4cd5-9dfb-43a3425c2a9a",
    "front": "**Def**: emphasize sth to give it more attention.\n**Farsi**: برجسته کردن، تأکید کردن",
    "back": "highlight sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "edc52ef9-daa4-4674-a3a1-5e8ef371cdd4",
    "front": "**Def**: decide to take and support a particular point of view, plan, etc.\n**Farsi**: اتخاذ کردن، گرفتن (موضع)",
    "back": "adopt sth (stance)"
  },
  {
    "id": "77d5e527-e843-4fd5-9698-5b1ef4e585d6",
    "front": "**Def**: an opinion that sb has about sth and expresses publicly. SYN position.\n**Farsi**: موضع، دیدگاه",
    "back": "stance (on sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "3bd1150e-d407-4511-b537-72361623bb7f",
    "front": "**Def**: give an example to make sth clearer. SYN illustrate sth.\n**Farsi**: مثال آوردن، نمونه آوردن",
    "back": "exemplify sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "d278925f-f415-4442-a099-b8582c387d79",
    "front": "**Def**: a decision reached after discussion and examination of any evidence.\n**Farsi**: نتیجه‌گیری",
    "back": "conclusion (draw/reach/come to a ~)"
  },
  {
    "id": "a7440e31-6d55-41e4-b49a-187f34ec917a",
    "front": "**Def**: say publicly that you think sth or sb is bad or wrong. condemnation N.\n**Farsi**: محکوم کردن",
    "back": "condemn sth/sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "e033ddcf-d4d4-4169-b7d1-5d7d90ac51e4",
    "front": "**Def**: accept or forgive behaviour that most people think is wrong.\n**Farsi**: چشم‌پوشی کردن، بخشیدن (رفتار بد)",
    "back": "condone sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "ed45493c-ae8b-4577-9ddd-841a7cde454c",
    "front": "**Def**: suggest a possible explanation for sth, but without knowing whether it is really true. hypothesis N.\n**Farsi**: فرضیه‌سازی کردن",
    "back": "hypothesize"
  },
  {
    "id": "1078ccd0-7085-4eab-87d8-050612d90a6a",
    "front": "**Def**: state clearly that sth is true. SYN claim sth. assertion N.\n**Farsi**: قاطعانه ادعا کردن",
    "back": "assert sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "2bf8a033-55f8-45fd-a35f-5d7d80fa0d16",
    "front": "**Def**: IDIOM avoid deciding or saying which side of an argument you support.\n**Farsi**: بی‌طرف بودن، موضع نگرفتن",
    "back": "sit on the fence"
  },
  {
    "id": "d20d5d47-ca26-4529-aa13-2d4a329e11e0",
    "front": "**Def**: a short summary of the plot of a book, film, etc.\n**Farsi**: خلاصه داستان، چکیده",
    "back": "synopsis"
  },
  {
    "id": "aae09dd2-daa4-4657-9998-09afc7af39f6",
    "front": "**Def**: rich and successful. SYN affluent. prosperity N.\n**Farsi**: مرفه، موفق",
    "back": "prosperous"
  },
  {
    "id": "91441796-caaf-43c0-b510-4029836c8148",
    "front": "**Def**: the main character in a book, film, etc.\n**Farsi**: شخصیت اصلی، قهرمان داستان",
    "back": "protagonist"
  },
  {
    "id": "259c55ab-4416-4bd1-9c84-1ee548378ec5",
    "front": "**Def**: A person's downfall is the complete loss of their money, power, etc.\n**Farsi**: سقوط، نابودی",
    "back": "downfall"
  },
  {
    "id": "f61152de-4c1b-42b1-a775-19a95461644b",
    "front": "**Def**: a kind or forgiving attitude towards sb you have the power to harm or punish. merciful ADJ. OPP merciless.\n**Farsi**: ترحم، بخشش",
    "back": "mercy"
  },
  {
    "id": "71e3ad29-3578-424f-84b0-84122cff27c4",
    "front": "**Def**: the state of being seriously mentally ill. insane ADJ. OPP sane.\n**Farsi**: جنون، دیوانگی",
    "back": "insanity"
  },
  {
    "id": "1e000bdb-51f6-48b2-a680-aeb48df14da0",
    "front": "**Def**: a written explanation or discussion of sth such as a book.\n**Farsi**: تفسیر، شرح، نقد",
    "back": "commentary"
  },
  {
    "id": "32b0a3a5-5852-40ed-9fa9-46f5f8d6a05b",
    "front": "**Def**: deserving, or causing you to feel, pity.\n**Farsi**: رقت‌انگیز، غم‌انگیز",
    "back": "pitiful"
  },
  {
    "id": "0660dcea-fb7a-47fd-9ca8-efce2d0a758a",
    "front": "**Def**: communicate ideas and feelings.\n**Farsi**: منتقل کردن (ایده، احساس)",
    "back": "convey sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "d8ef2266-aa4c-4a6c-a551-95316b3aa6b4",
    "front": "**Def**: used to contrast one person or thing with another.\n**Farsi**: برخلاف",
    "back": "unlike"
  },
  {
    "id": "1b6f7b4e-e81c-4568-bedd-8cf864b5c68f",
    "front": "**Def**: a power that is believed to control everything and that cannot be changed.\n**Farsi**: سرنوشت، تقدیر",
    "back": "fate"
  },
  {
    "id": "9f88728b-b825-45fa-b965-21fcc70b5dd3",
    "front": "**Def**: strange, difficult to understand, and often unacceptable.\n**Farsi**: بیگانه، غریب، نامأنوس",
    "back": "alien (adj)"
  },
  {
    "id": "e20be336-806c-44bd-ba76-aedfdd55d5eb",
    "front": "**Def**: tell the true facts about sth and show it to be bad or wrong.\n**Farsi**: آشکار کردن، فاش کردن",
    "back": "expose sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "e299913d-43db-47b8-90a7-ae5ac985a871",
    "front": "**Def**: the act of being disloyal to sb who trusts you. betray v.\n**Farsi**: خیانت",
    "back": "betrayal"
  },
  {
    "id": "271796b3-1f6c-4213-927b-310da60f0541",
    "front": "**Def**: a friendly and comfortable relationship between people.\n**Farsi**: رفاقت، همدمی",
    "back": "companionship"
  },
  {
    "id": "183903a8-4dc3-49f4-9cc3-d4a4832b5cca",
    "front": "**Def**: describe sb/sth in a piece of writing. SYN depict sb/sth. portrayal N.\n**Farsi**: به تصویر کشیدن، مجسم کردن",
    "back": "portray sb/sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "8d1299a9-b548-4adc-945b-491f48d12a51",
    "front": "**Def**: the ability to recover and become strong again after a difficult or unpleasant situation. resilient ADJ.\n**Farsi**: انعطاف‌پذیری، توانایی بازیابی",
    "back": "resilience"
  },
  {
    "id": "6703b3a4-24e5-4cfc-a6ff-f6b454250009",
    "front": "**Def**: they show or express a particular idea or quality (embodiment N).\n**Farsi**: مظهر چیزی بودن، تجسم بخشیدن",
    "back": "embody/represent sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "5517223e-849c-42ca-9250-3da25373c6e0",
    "front": "**Def**: give the character a particular quality or feature.\n**Farsi**: اعطا کردن، موهبتی بخشیدن",
    "back": "endow sb with sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "703d8363-e0a7-4357-abb3-8d6638d04856",
    "front": "**Def**: a possible explanation of sth, based on a few facts but not yet proven to be true. SYN theory.\n**Farsi**: فرضیه (توضیح احتمالی برای چیزی، بر اساس چند واقعیت اما هنوز اثبات نشده. مترادف: نظریه)",
    "back": "hypothesis"
  },
  {
    "id": "10a27017-6754-4784-a0b1-57c08168d40c",
    "front": "**Def**: adjective form of hypothesis.\n**Farsi**: فرضی، احتمالی",
    "back": "hypothetical"
  },
  {
    "id": "44db4d1c-f4b5-4978-ba43-cfe00a6da918",
    "front": "**Def**: a thing that happens or exists, especially sth that is not fully understood.\n**Farsi**: پدیده (چیزی که رخ می‌دهد یا وجود دارد، به ویژه چیزی که کاملاً درک نشده است)",
    "back": "phenomenon"
  },
  {
    "id": "bbaaf577-71f9-4c9f-981c-bf17162fc341",
    "front": "**Def**: based on experiments or experience, not just ideas (empirical evidence/knowledge/research).\n**Farsi**: تجربی (مبتنی بر آزمایش‌ها یا تجربه، نه صرفاً ایده)",
    "back": "empirical"
  },
  {
    "id": "fcc436b8-d8f9-4b23-a1c9-717ace22581c",
    "front": "**Def**: noun form of empirical.\n**Farsi**: تجربه‌گرایی",
    "back": "empiricism"
  },
  {
    "id": "c546a9e7-3e2f-4d1d-9445-f0ff4937b1ca",
    "front": "**Def**: a particular part of sth. SYN aspect (of sth).\n**Farsi**: جنبه، بُعد (بخش خاصی از چیزی. مترادف: اَسپِکت)",
    "back": "facet (of sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f06e77ac-7af2-4766-bc4e-f1174fc37535",
    "front": "**Def**: a strong opinion or belief (political/moral conviction).\n**Farsi**: اعتقاد راسخ، باور قوی (یک عقیده یا باور قوی)",
    "back": "conviction"
  },
  {
    "id": "d58c844e-fcc4-4e34-a902-62d96efff2a0",
    "front": "**Def**: based on fact and not influenced by personal feelings or opinion. SYN unbiased. OPP subjective.\n**Farsi**: عینی، بی‌طرف (مبتنی بر واقعیت و تحت تأثیر احساسات یا نظرات شخصی قرار نگرفته. مترادف: بی‌غرض. متضاد: ذهنی/سوبژکتیو)",
    "back": "objective"
  },
  {
    "id": "60f371d3-7aff-45a6-b392-9d797b24f23e",
    "front": "**Def**: noun form of objective.\n**Farsi**: عینیت، بی‌طرفی",
    "back": "objectivity"
  },
  {
    "id": "573b2596-36fb-40fc-9fbe-d190a864f462",
    "front": "**Def**: influenced by personal feelings. OPP unbiased/objective.\n**Farsi**: مغرضانه، جهت‌دار (تحت تأثیر احساسات شخصی. متضاد: بی‌غرض/عینی)",
    "back": "biased"
  },
  {
    "id": "3f43b820-ea01-4a1f-a606-66e2dcc924db",
    "front": "**Def**: noun form of biased.\n**Farsi**: غرض‌ورزی، تعصب",
    "back": "bias"
  },
  {
    "id": "fcd74571-3915-48d6-95c7-d524c7393427",
    "front": "**Def**: put documents in an archive (a set of historical documents).\n**Farsi**: آرشیو کردن (قرار دادن اسناد در آرشیو)",
    "back": "archive sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "52cf405c-d8b9-4cc8-8ac8-736a798d3e3a",
    "front": "**Def**: careful and thorough examination (come under close/careful scrutiny). SYN inspection.\n**Farsi**: بررسی دقیق و موشکافانه (معاینه دقیق و کامل. مترادف: بازرسی)",
    "back": "scrutiny"
  },
  {
    "id": "ddde2a34-d63b-4001-a730-95b31147bf21",
    "front": "**Def**: verb form of scrutiny.\n**Farsi**: با دقت بررسی کردن",
    "back": "scrutinize sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "814af4bd-f95a-4f86-b5b3-294b2991799f",
    "front": "**Def**: check or show that sth is true and accurate.\n**Farsi**: تأیید کردن، صحت‌سنجی کردن (بررسی یا نشان دادن اینکه چیزی درست و دقیق است)",
    "back": "verify sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "987040db-e59e-469e-9808-d5cd59bb0ec0",
    "front": "**Def**: noun form of verify.\n**Farsi**: تأیید، صحت‌سنجی",
    "back": "verification"
  },
  {
    "id": "7a26b1cd-be88-46fb-9829-3e3db761625a",
    "front": "**Def**: copy sth exactly. SYN duplicate sth.\n**Farsi**: تکثیر کردن، تکرار کردن (کپی کردن دقیق چیزی. مترادف: duplicate کردن)",
    "back": "replicate sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "58ae6928-b687-41f6-978e-5f54fff43eb2",
    "front": "**Def**: the scientific study of the ways in which different characteristics are passed from one generation to the next.\n**Farsi**: ژنتیک (مطالعه علمی روش‌هایی که در آن ویژگی‌های مختلف از نسلی به نسل دیگر منتقل می‌شوند)",
    "back": "genetics"
  },
  {
    "id": "ab73e977-d2a4-44bb-8cd1-1e5c9bbc8df9",
    "front": "**Def**: adjective form of genetics.\n**Farsi**: ژنتیکی",
    "back": "genetic"
  },
  {
    "id": "1a80cb13-8893-4363-8a89-73399d19b7ee",
    "front": "**Def**: the process by which physical and mental characteristics are passed from parents to their children.\n**Farsi**: وراثت (فرآیندی که از طریق آن ویژگی‌های جسمی و ذهنی از والدین به فرزندان منتقل می‌شود)",
    "back": "heredity"
  },
  {
    "id": "3c3b43ae-9d74-4339-9412-b197a8932abb",
    "front": "**Def**: adjective form of heredity.\n**Farsi**: ارثی، وراثتی",
    "back": "hereditary"
  },
  {
    "id": "2c6db816-0507-4da6-a044-e7614389895a",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning actively resist or refuse to comply with.\n**Farsi**: مخالفت کردن",
    "back": "oppose"
  },
  {
    "id": "f3fe1b19-23b0-4fb9-927d-7520cf345b79",
    "front": "**Def**: having a fault or faults. SYN faulty.\n**Farsi**: معیوب، ناقص (داشتن نقص یا عیب. مترادف: faulty)",
    "back": "defective"
  },
  {
    "id": "a00af261-392b-4964-92e7-7ec0cb331abe",
    "front": "**Def**: noun form of defective.\n**Farsi**: نقص، عیب",
    "back": "defect"
  },
  {
    "id": "0487c6e1-9532-4eb0-b68a-656d65cf3d9b",
    "front": "**Def**: put sth into sth else or between two things.\n**Farsi**: وارد کردن، قرار دادن (چیزی را داخل چیز دیگری یا بین دو چیز قرار دادن)",
    "back": "insert sth (into sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "3d746e3f-95d1-4d16-8ca5-324d67db926b",
    "front": "**Def**: noun form of insert.\n**Farsi**: عمل وارد کردن",
    "back": "insertion"
  },
  {
    "id": "5e752209-c3d4-46f5-abe7-490c16aa1421",
    "front": "**Def**: different from what is expected, and often harmful or unwanted.\n**Farsi**: غیرطبیعی، ناهنجار (متفاوت از حد انتظار و اغلب مضر یا ناخواسته)",
    "back": "abnormal"
  },
  {
    "id": "6728654a-b3c6-4298-8040-09b9ebe8e6ce",
    "front": "**Def**: adjective form of molecule.\n**Farsi**: مولکولی",
    "back": "molecular"
  },
  {
    "id": "4bf69284-b7b5-477b-bcfb-8be7656a071f",
    "front": "**Def**: only lasting for a short time. OPP long-lived.\n**Farsi**: کوتاه‌مدت (فقط برای مدت کوتاهی دوام داشتن. متضاد: طولانی‌مدت)",
    "back": "short-lived"
  },
  {
    "id": "fe90060b-805c-465f-a023-115f9e0fec3f",
    "front": "**Def**: successfully fight or drive away sth that is attacking you.\n**Farsi**: دفع کردن، پس زدن (موفقیت‌آمیز مبارزه کردن یا دور کردن چیزی که به شما حمله می‌کند)",
    "back": "repel sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "240154d5-fe97-45a7-a532-8bf1965c2d8c",
    "front": "**Def**: the system in your body that produces substances to help it fight against infection and disease (giving immunity).\n**Farsi**: سیستم ایمنی (سیستم بدنی که موادی برای کمک به مبارزه با عفونت و بیماری تولید می‌کند)",
    "back": "immune system"
  },
  {
    "id": "a6f27802-67a0-4b24-8ab8-8eafa98d2161",
    "front": "**Def**: (in biology) a process in which genetic material changes in structure when it is passed on.\n**Farsi**: جهش (در زیست‌شناسی، فرآیندی که در آن ساختار مواد ژنتیکی هنگام انتقال تغییر می‌کند)",
    "back": "mutation"
  },
  {
    "id": "393fce58-8449-43c8-b01c-516e760b6409",
    "front": "**Def**: verb form of mutation.\n**Farsi**: جهش یافتن",
    "back": "mutate"
  },
  {
    "id": "df68a322-3207-495a-be10-22b948de694d",
    "front": "**Def**: A unit can be a thing, person, or group that is complete in itself but can also form part of something larger.\n**Farsi**: واحد (یک چیز، شخص یا گروه که به خودی خود کامل است اما می‌تواند بخشی از یک چیز بزرگتر نیز باشد)",
    "back": "unit"
  },
  {
    "id": "7876bb33-be64-424a-945b-c2873b418448",
    "front": "**Def**: a thing which limits your freedom to do sth. SYN restriction. constrain v.\n**Farsi**: محدودیت (چیزی که آزادی شما برای انجام کاری را محدود می‌کند. مترادف: restriction)",
    "back": "constraint"
  },
  {
    "id": "ed191bad-37eb-48e2-97e5-242e18a879f8",
    "front": "**Def**: verb form of constraint.\n**Farsi**: محدود کردن",
    "back": "constrain"
  },
  {
    "id": "f3f8c7ee-97c6-48b5-aaf2-d480ea7309e5",
    "front": "**Def**: obey a rule, order, law, etc. compliance N.\n**Farsi**: مطابقت داشتن با، پیروی کردن از (اطاعت از یک قانون، دستور، و غیره)",
    "back": "comply with sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "e39f6ddc-5c99-454a-aeaf-d93954552279",
    "front": "**Def**: noun form of comply.\n**Farsi**: انطباق، تبعیت",
    "back": "compliance"
  },
  {
    "id": "2f43a173-49d8-4fb1-9756-dd3c3f87b86e",
    "front": "**Def**: (of a law, rule, etc.) very strict.\n**Farsi**: سخت‌گیرانه (درباره قانون، مقررات و غیره، بسیار سخت)",
    "back": "stringent"
  },
  {
    "id": "b4d16590-3afd-4b89-b912-a1ab749335a3",
    "front": "**Def**: satisfy the needs of sb/sth.\n**Farsi**: نیازهای کسی/چیزی را برآورده کردن",
    "back": "meet the needs of sb/sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "42bc7801-007e-41aa-a677-4360c96dcd39",
    "front": "**Def**: a person who lives or works in a particular room or building.\n**Farsi**: ساکن، اشغال‌کننده (فردی که در یک مکان زندگی یا کار می‌کند)",
    "back": "occupant"
  },
  {
    "id": "f9fdfc86-9d6f-4f43-8d12-1f140dcee110",
    "front": "**Def**: calculate sth exactly. SYN establish sth.\n**Farsi**: تعیین کردن، مشخص کردن (چیزی را دقیقاً محاسبه کردن. مترادف: establish)",
    "back": "determine sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "d85d7394-341c-416b-95a0-2862124f48f2",
    "front": "**Def**: be strong enough to be unharmed by great heat, cold, pressure, etc. SYNS resist sth, stand up to sth.\n**Farsi**: مقاومت کردن در برابر (به اندازه کافی قوی بودن تا توسط گرما، سرما، فشار و غیره آسیب نبیند. مترادف: resist sth, stand up to sth)",
    "back": "withstand sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "367429cb-1030-4cd3-a84f-867854e2a363",
    "front": "**Def**: move slowly from side to side.\n**Farsi**: تاب خوردن، نوسان کردن (آهسته از یک طرف به طرف دیگر حرکت کردن)",
    "back": "sway"
  },
  {
    "id": "89a58d51-ecc8-4c57-9897-29f75f158ef5",
    "front": "**Def**: do sth to reduce or prevent the bad effects of sth.\n**Farsi**: خنثی کردن، مقابله کردن با (کاری برای کاهش یا جلوگیری از اثرات بد چیزی انجام دادن)",
    "back": "counteract sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "685c673a-15db-48a1-95ed-c99e2b1f18f6",
    "front": "**Def**: to, towards, or from the side.\n**Farsi**: به پهلو، جانبی (به سمت یا از یک طرف)",
    "back": "sideways"
  },
  {
    "id": "2e8deea6-1c53-46ef-afd4-f8826e5d93f2",
    "front": "**Def**: close sth very firmly so that nothing can get in or out.\n**Farsi**: مهر و موم کردن (چیزی را خیلی محکم بستن تا چیزی داخل یا خارج نشود)",
    "back": "seal sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "1790518b-e45e-4723-bd71-257cfeb12f33",
    "front": "**Def**: stamped (self-)addressed envelope\n**Farsi**: پاکت مهر شده با آدرس فرستنده (پاکت آدرس‌دار مهر و موم شده)",
    "back": "sae"
  },
  {
    "id": "bca3e6f2-167a-4334-b127-08f91540400a",
    "front": "**Def**: made stronger, especially by the addition of another material.\n**Farsi**: تقویت شده، مسلح شده (قوی‌تر شده، به ویژه با افزودن مواد دیگر)",
    "back": "reinforced"
  },
  {
    "id": "73b4ba2f-9257-49e1-a76a-086b58ccd822",
    "front": "**Def**: a mixture of sand, cement, small stones, and water, which forms a hard building material.\n**Farsi**: بتن، سیمان (مخلوطی از ماسه، سیمان، سنگ‌های کوچک و آب که یک مصالح ساختمانی سخت را تشکیل می‌دهد)",
    "back": "concrete"
  },
  {
    "id": "713e5917-4fcf-4d18-b2e5-853276445d52",
    "front": "**Def**: going straight up or down from a surface.\n**Farsi**: عمودی (مستقیم به سمت بالا یا پایین از یک سطح رفتن)",
    "back": "vertical"
  },
  {
    "id": "0161a978-6051-490f-abaa-bd179717a09f",
    "front": "**Def**: the amount of weight pressing down on sth (a vertical load).\n**Farsi**: بار، وزن (مقدار وزنی که بر چیزی فشار می‌آورد)",
    "back": "load"
  },
  {
    "id": "9eb7bdeb-b5db-4cd3-8ee8-ef1ffce5381b",
    "front": "**Def**: a long piece of wood or metal, used to support a weight above.\n**Farsi**: تیر (یک قطعه بلند چوب یا فلز که برای تحمل وزن در بالا استفاده می‌شود)",
    "back": "beam"
  },
  {
    "id": "88c51ef0-4620-4ab8-8d0d-a6125c229340",
    "front": "**Def**: a strong metal beam in large buildings.\n**Farsi**: شاه‌تیر (یک تیر فلزی قوی در ساختمان‌های بزرگ)",
    "back": "girder"
  },
  {
    "id": "8d5be9a2-2eb3-47cc-8fa9-4ae8e912589d",
    "front": "**Def**: the space between two lines or surfaces that join (angle sth v move or position sth so it is not straight; it is at an angle).\n**Farsi**: زاویه (فضای بین دو خط یا سطح که به هم می‌پیوندند)",
    "back": "angle"
  },
  {
    "id": "33745ef9-bf79-4274-9454-a442b5882f0a",
    "front": "**Def**: fasten sth to sth with a bolt (= a long piece of metal).\n**Farsi**: با پیچ و مهره بستن (چیزی را با یک پیچ و مهره به چیز دیگری محکم کردن)",
    "back": "bolt sth to sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "e8b62a6e-e3d9-4da7-a998-ea8e49a2ae30",
    "front": "**Def**: a piece of metal or wood fixed to a wall to support sth.\n**Farsi**: بست، نگهدارنده (یک قطعه فلز یا چوب که برای نگه داشتن چیزی به دیوار ثابت شده است)",
    "back": "bracket"
  },
  {
    "id": "17eda6bf-9887-46f3-a471-64d1d92fe5dd",
    "front": "**Def**: talk to you later\n**Farsi**: بعداً باهات صحبت می‌کنم",
    "back": "ttyl"
  },
  {
    "id": "8ddd4290-53ee-42b8-ab7d-2494d2b4fb88",
    "front": "**Def**: as soon as possible\n**Farsi**: در اسرع وقت",
    "back": "asap"
  },
  {
    "id": "b179def4-2569-4f9c-9556-fadbe8ea4982",
    "front": "**Def**: bye for now\n**Farsi**: فعلاً خداحافظ",
    "back": "bfn / b4n"
  },
  {
    "id": "a78226c8-b3d6-4f8d-b4cf-41b36534a5d5",
    "front": "**Def**: have a nice day\n**Farsi**: روز خوبی داشته باشی",
    "back": "hand"
  },
  {
    "id": "73c20835-9541-42f4-9fc0-d85be010b292",
    "front": "**Def**: see you later\n**Farsi**: بعداً می‌بینمت",
    "back": "cul8r"
  },
  {
    "id": "e72f55d1-31da-4647-8b63-1bc742680e88",
    "front": "**Def**: for your information\n**Farsi**: جهت اطلاع شما",
    "back": "fyi"
  },
  {
    "id": "517c5556-aa2f-43fe-b0c7-5cd7dc3f565f",
    "front": "**Def**: all the best\n**Farsi**: بهترین‌ها (آرزوی موفقیت)",
    "back": "atb"
  },
  {
    "id": "c9a7b524-fa9f-438b-825a-5e3785027efc",
    "front": "**Def**: by the way\n**Farsi**: راستی، ضمناً",
    "back": "btw"
  },
  {
    "id": "bb3d936b-f004-48c7-918c-f1f2de6d7d5e",
    "front": "**Def**: lots of love OR laughing out loud\n**Farsi**: عشق فراوان OR با صدای بلند خندیدن",
    "back": "lol"
  },
  {
    "id": "1f69bd1d-d75e-4a64-8895-18c73c041c59",
    "front": "**Def**: in my humble opinion (humorous, = in my opinion, though I am not an important person)\n**Farsi**: به نظر حقیرانه من (به نظر من، هرچند فرد مهمی نیستم)",
    "back": "imho"
  },
  {
    "id": "7b93c944-4869-4827-8f54-e03fdede971a",
    "front": "**Def**: kiss\n**Farsi**: بوسه",
    "back": "x"
  },
  {
    "id": "3a9b2ad9-38fb-4e06-a33f-1ef150d6c823",
    "front": "**Def**: mind your own business\n**Farsi**: سرت به کار خودت باشد",
    "back": "myob"
  },
  {
    "id": "8f7ff470-f9e5-4fbe-938e-8e5f126ab164",
    "front": "**Def**: if I remember/recall correctly\n**Farsi**: اگر درست به خاطر داشته باشم/به یاد بیاورم",
    "back": "iirc"
  },
  {
    "id": "d33839a9-f0d9-40c7-9361-5290d4c951b4",
    "front": "**Def**: (I've) got to go (now)\n**Farsi**: (الان) باید بروم",
    "back": "gtg"
  },
  {
    "id": "f4972b3a-c680-41e6-81da-152c3e366f2a",
    "front": "**Def**: probably\n**Farsi**: احتمالاً",
    "back": "prolly / prbly"
  },
  {
    "id": "f1c50b46-5f9a-482a-8a5f-3bd482be86b9",
    "front": "**Def**: a rude way of telling sb not to ask questions about or get involved in sth you don't want them to know about. SYN it's none of your business.\n**Farsi**: سر به کار خودت باشد (راهی گستاخانه برای گفتن اینکه کسی در کاری دخالت نکند)",
    "back": "mind your own business"
  },
  {
    "id": "611ddb34-b17a-432e-9124-a976f9bd7047",
    "front": "**Def**: remember sth. SYN recollect sth. recollection N.\n**Farsi**: به یاد آوردن، به خاطر آوردن (مترادف: recollect)",
    "back": "recall sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "c5bc1697-22c1-477b-aa6a-71445feaafd4",
    "front": "**Def**: noun form of recall.\n**Farsi**: یادآوری",
    "back": "recollection"
  },
  {
    "id": "0050835d-1d91-4f64-9a66-d3d573bfd6d3",
    "front": "**Def**: document(s) enclosed\n**Farsi**: پیوست (سند یا اسناد پیوست شده)",
    "back": "encl."
  },
  {
    "id": "6b45e0a1-a655-4c3f-ac22-56d5c7ed712f",
    "front": "**Def**: (in advertisements) included / including, e.g. batteries not inc.\n**Farsi**: شامل، از جمله (در تبلیغات)",
    "back": "inc."
  },
  {
    "id": "c3000815-b650-436e-a5d3-e26c8290822a",
    "front": "**Def**: inclusive, e.g. 12–24 June incl.\n**Farsi**: فراگیر، شامل (از جمله: مثال ۱۲ تا ۲۴ ژوئن شامل)",
    "back": "incl."
  },
  {
    "id": "cb0111b0-0db0-41d4-b981-bf0360c8cd67",
    "front": "**Def**: for the attention of, e.g. Sales Dept attn Doug Smith\n**Farsi**: جهت توجه (به ویژه در مورد بخش یا شخص خاصی در یک نامه)",
    "back": "attn or fao"
  },
  {
    "id": "df4f911e-e539-4c9c-ab96-390c669ea87e",
    "front": "**Def**: please turn over\n**Farsi**: لطفاً صفحه را برگردانید",
    "back": "PTO"
  },
  {
    "id": "839364ea-5908-45d2-a46b-2c46f8858f2d",
    "front": "**Def**: (on invitations) please reply (from French 'Répondez s'il vous plaît')\n**Farsi**: لطفاً پاسخ دهید (در دعوت‌نامه‌ها)",
    "back": "RSVP"
  },
  {
    "id": "92a3e366-f4cd-4abe-8b10-a611c8e6e0a7",
    "front": "**Def**: care of (used on a letter to sb staying at another person's house)\n**Farsi**: توسط (استفاده شده در نامه‌ای به شخصی که در خانه فرد دیگری اقامت دارد)",
    "back": "c/o"
  },
  {
    "id": "d02a7022-02ab-41fd-842d-aab5f7cb8c6f",
    "front": "**Def**: used to make sb notice some important information (from Latin 'nota bene')\n**Farsi**: توجه داشته باشید، نکته مهم (برای جلب توجه به اطلاعات مهم)",
    "back": "NB"
  },
  {
    "id": "c95bc165-6e1c-4273-8e4d-f30cfb72dc34",
    "front": "**Def**: bed and breakfast = a small hotel and the service provided.\n**Farsi**: محل اقامت با صبحانه (یک هتل کوچک و خدمات ارائه شده)",
    "back": "B & B"
  },
  {
    "id": "152c7206-2abb-46aa-977c-46f569325883",
    "front": "**Def**: chief executive officer\n**Farsi**: مدیر ارشد اجرایی",
    "back": "CEO"
  },
  {
    "id": "2fd701ec-7478-40a7-8bba-f68e68fa5aab",
    "front": "**Def**: politically correct (of language or behaviour) aiming to avoid offending anyone.\n**Farsi**: از نظر سیاسی درست (زبان یا رفتاری که هدف آن اجتناب از توهین به کسی است)",
    "back": "PC"
  },
  {
    "id": "1546dc3b-37e4-4fd5-b0df-f104b7f5dd3b",
    "front": "**Def**: headquarters = the main offices of an organization.\n**Farsi**: دفتر مرکزی، ستاد (دفاتر اصلی یک سازمان)",
    "back": "HQ"
  },
  {
    "id": "5a64263d-786b-4e69-b6cc-8ece109a75d1",
    "front": "**Def**: estimated time of arrival\n**Farsi**: زمان تخمینی ورود",
    "back": "ETA"
  },
  {
    "id": "74fb5aa0-6128-4287-a994-75dd9abd46f5",
    "front": "**Def**: intelligence quotient = a measure of sb's intelligence using special tests (a high/low IQ).\n**Farsi**: ضریب هوشی (اندازه‌گیری هوش کسی با استفاده از آزمون‌های ویژه)",
    "back": "IQ"
  },
  {
    "id": "505cc71b-6098-455a-964f-4647f9195b36",
    "front": "**Def**: tender loving care = the sympathy and support you show sb to make them feel better.\n**Farsi**: مراقبت با محبت و دلسوزی (حمایت و دلسوزی که برای بهتر شدن حال کسی نشان می‌دهید)",
    "back": "TLC"
  },
  {
    "id": "54e5667e-3df8-42a8-a987-c08fc0337301",
    "front": "**Def**: do-it-yourself = home repairs and decoration you do yourself rather than paying sb to do it.\n**Farsi**: خودت انجام بده (تعمیرات و دکوراسیون خانگی که خودتان انجام می‌دهید)",
    "back": "DIY"
  },
  {
    "id": "4365f9d3-458f-48ad-9b29-14fab28e3f5f",
    "front": "**Def**: estimate a time, amount, etc. wrongly.\n**Farsi**: اشتباه محاسبه کردن (زمان، مقدار و غیره را به اشتباه تخمین زدن)",
    "back": "miscalculate sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "869acd95-3edc-452d-9865-9c214854a247",
    "front": "**Def**: a concept (= idea) which is not based on correct information or is not clearly understood. misconceived ADJ.\n**Farsi**: تصور غلط، سوء برداشت (ایده‌ای که بر اساس اطلاعات درست نیست)",
    "back": "misconception"
  },
  {
    "id": "3b0423fa-efe8-4715-8407-af5cdd9bdc0a",
    "front": "**Def**: adjective form of misconception.\n**Farsi**: بدفهمی شده، نادرست درک شده",
    "back": "misconceived"
  },
  {
    "id": "24fa4279-4591-4154-aafe-0bcaa5d83672",
    "front": "**Def**: a small mistake, e.g. a spelling mistake in a book, paper, etc.\n**Farsi**: غلط چاپی (یک اشتباه کوچک، مانند اشتباه املایی)",
    "back": "misprint"
  },
  {
    "id": "a26ccbf6-9c95-4c85-83ed-b205731ac3be",
    "front": "**Def**: manage or deal with sth badly. SYN mishandle sth.\n**Farsi**: بد اداره کردن، سوء مدیریت کردن (مترادف: mishandle)",
    "back": "mismanage sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "790ecef3-b9e5-4f6f-9a3c-f924d334a18b",
    "front": "**Def**: make a wrong judgement about sth or sb.\n**Farsi**: قضاوت غلط کردن (قضاوت اشتباهی در مورد کسی یا چیزی کردن)",
    "back": "misjudge sth/sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "d717ebb9-47f4-419b-b051-6e3a7e4b94ee",
    "front": "**Def**: lose sth for a time. SYN misplace sth.\n**Farsi**: گم کردن، موقتاً جا گذاشتن (مترادف: misplace)",
    "back": "mislay sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "d98c96a0-f66f-4791-b009-bcab69d5f2a1",
    "front": "**Def**: go wrong.\n**Farsi**: نتیجه ندادن، اشتباه از کار درآمدن (در مورد یک نقشه یا شوخی، به خطا رفتن)",
    "back": "misfire (of a plan or joke)"
  },
  {
    "id": "79d8c40e-918c-4924-aeba-99e50129c1b7",
    "front": "**Def**: be wrong about what illness sb has.\n**Farsi**: تشخیص اشتباه دادن",
    "back": "misdiagnose sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "c5dd6f7f-35b8-4d67-b325-967af1ffe764",
    "front": "**Def**: give sb the wrong information about sth.\n**Farsi**: اطلاعات غلط دادن",
    "back": "misinform sb (about sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b33269fb-fbeb-4297-9e8c-b9f637c96938",
    "front": "**Def**: treat sth/sb in a bad or cruel way.\n**Farsi**: بدرفتاری کردن، با ظلم رفتار کردن",
    "back": "mistreat sth/sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "bb859c88-ce9c-4a5e-80c7-e36179629564",
    "front": "**Def**: in the process of being investigated.\n**Farsi**: تحت تحقیق/بازرسی",
    "back": "under investigation"
  },
  {
    "id": "5fdf7a00-e483-4dfd-8351-6843d76f80e1",
    "front": "**Def**: verb form of interaction.\n**Farsi**: تعامل داشتن",
    "back": "interact (with sb)"
  },
  {
    "id": "73238396-a356-41ed-af2c-e0190ceaa9ad",
    "front": "**Def**: consisting of parts that depend on each other.\n**Farsi**: وابسته به هم (شامل اجزایی که به یکدیگر وابسته هستند)",
    "back": "interdependent"
  },
  {
    "id": "707d4dda-3b7a-4c28-bf9b-c10cf58897d9",
    "front": "**Def**: (of two things) closely related and affecting each other.\n**Farsi**: مرتبط با هم (دو چیز که ارتباط نزدیک دارند و بر هم تأثیر می‌گذارند)",
    "back": "interrelated"
  },
  {
    "id": "43e0e8bc-6944-4f98-a579-7dd3b613e22d",
    "front": "**Def**: having little or no knowledge of sth.\n**Farsi**: کم اطلاع، ناآگاه (دانش کم یا هیچ در مورد چیزی داشتن)",
    "back": "ill-informed"
  },
  {
    "id": "72ac8852-8142-4353-85d0-c636f8adebf7",
    "front": "**Def**: badly planned or organized.\n**Farsi**: بد برنامه‌ریزی شده، نامنظم",
    "back": "ill-prepared"
  },
  {
    "id": "3e9bd860-4db2-4542-8326-9d13adf324cd",
    "front": "**Def**: treated in a cruel or unkind way.\n**Farsi**: بدرفتاری شده، مورد آزار قرار گرفته",
    "back": "ill-treated"
  },
  {
    "id": "bd0070dc-bbec-4a3a-9423-721a2bea9112",
    "front": "**Def**: not sensible; likely to have a bad effect.\n**Farsi**: نسنجیده، نامعقول (عاقلانه نیست؛ احتمالاً اثر بدی دارد)",
    "back": "ill-advised"
  },
  {
    "id": "aac77de0-4180-4a32-9c51-209f5b1ea257",
    "front": "**Def**: examine the idea again to see if it needs changing. SYN reassess.\n**Farsi**: بازنگری کردن، دوباره ارزیابی کردن (ایده‌ای را دوباره بررسی کردن. مترادف: reassess)",
    "back": "reappraise"
  },
  {
    "id": "99eaf3f3-78b7-4615-b1f4-56d4a99b816d",
    "front": "**Def**: put more fuel in a plane.\n**Farsi**: سوخت‌گیری مجدد کردن",
    "back": "refuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "1b854791-6a26-4b62-95aa-16b2d2ec4db2",
    "front": "**Def**: other words starting with re-.\n**Farsi**: بازنویسی، بازسازی، بازآفرینی، دوباره گفتن",
    "back": "rewrite, reconstruct, reinvent, retell"
  },
  {
    "id": "a1e1327a-ccbb-4dcd-9734-85281090f86c",
    "front": "**Def**: officially no longer secret. OPP classified.\n**Farsi**: از طبقه‌بندی خارج شده (رسماً دیگر محرمانه نیست. متضاد: classified)",
    "back": "declassified"
  },
  {
    "id": "adb21891-3a26-413e-a014-43405d2f62a0",
    "front": "**Def**: removed ice from the fridge.\n**Farsi**: یخ‌زدایی کردن (یخ را از چیزی حذف کردن)",
    "back": "defrost sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "25c53159-7ec1-42d7-8112-08d38ff71e83",
    "front": "**Def**: (of an area) from which all or most of the people have moved away. OPP populated.\n**Farsi**: خالی از سکنه (منطقه‌ای که اکثر مردم آنجا را ترک کرده‌اند. متضاد: populated)",
    "back": "depopulated"
  },
  {
    "id": "234bbfef-af2c-473f-9855-7a9359efe204",
    "front": "**Def**: other words starting with de- (reversal or removal).\n**Farsi**: غیرمتمرکز کردن، بی‌ثبات کردن، بدون کافئین",
    "back": "decentralize, destabilize, decaffeinated"
  },
  {
    "id": "ecfb0b05-7ab7-487e-aaec-60d5501d3aab",
    "front": "**Def**: the value of the currency was officially reduced.\n**Farsi**: کاهش ارزش داده شده (ارزش رسمی پول کاهش یافته)",
    "back": "devalued"
  },
  {
    "id": "14a822e1-1b33-4e35-9171-8c6f9776e734",
    "front": "**Def**: become less valuable over time.\n**Farsi**: مستهلک شدن، کم‌ارزش شدن",
    "back": "depreciate"
  },
  {
    "id": "e46352a7-6aed-463c-bdda-38872a985dfa",
    "front": "**Def**: opposed to war.\n**Farsi**: ضد جنگ (مخالف جنگ)",
    "back": "anti-war"
  },
  {
    "id": "6b68f422-c128-48d2-874e-114088cc33fe",
    "front": "**Def**: other words starting with anti- (opposed to).\n**Farsi**: ضد نژادپرستی، سیاست ضد مواد مخدر، نرم‌افزار ضد ویروس",
    "back": "anti-racism, anti-drugs policy, anti-virus software"
  },
  {
    "id": "86fd199f-b7d5-414c-93c6-cd08f9ca18b8",
    "front": "**Def**: used to reduce swelling and pain.\n**Farsi**: داروهای ضد التهاب (برای کاهش تورم و درد)",
    "back": "anti-inflammatory drugs"
  },
  {
    "id": "06a342f9-b512-42da-81dc-0ec09316148a",
    "front": "**Def**: drugs used to treat depression.\n**Farsi**: داروهای ضد افسردگی",
    "back": "anti-depressants"
  },
  {
    "id": "7867ae0d-8741-4000-a149-3ba7b9ed7552",
    "front": "**Def**: sell more tickets than are in fact available.\n**Farsi**: بیش از حد رزرو کردن (فروش بیش از حد بلیط)",
    "back": "overbook"
  },
  {
    "id": "114c7a35-c0ae-4856-9150-392fe28c37f2",
    "front": "**Def**: If sth is overrated, it is believed by some people to be better than it is. OPP underrated.\n**Farsi**: بیش از حد ارزش‌گذاری شده (متضاد: underrated)",
    "back": "overrated"
  },
  {
    "id": "2af725dc-48af-4543-a029-3f2b0f8c85d2",
    "front": "**Def**: excessive amount/dose.\n**Farsi**: مصرف بیش از حد",
    "back": "overdose"
  },
  {
    "id": "8962ba7e-f673-424a-af7f-4435d606e38e",
    "front": "**Def**: other words starting with over-.\n**Farsi**: بیش از حد تأکید کردن، بیش از حد بارگذاری کردن",
    "back": "overemphasize, overload"
  },
  {
    "id": "42604b40-1332-4a93-8f91-fae363846b70",
    "front": "**Def**: unhealthy because of a lack of food. SYNS malnourished, underfed.\n**Farsi**: دچار سوءتغذیه (ناسالم به دلیل کمبود غذا. مترادف: malnourished, underfed)",
    "back": "undernourished"
  },
  {
    "id": "62263ac0-00ff-4324-89bb-c2093b8f2670",
    "front": "**Def**: having less money and fewer advantages than most people. SYN disadvantaged.\n**Farsi**: محروم، کم برخوردار (داشتن پول کمتر و مزایای کمتر. مترادف: disadvantaged)",
    "back": "underprivileged"
  },
  {
    "id": "79696602-2478-48ee-befd-2cfa9c652973",
    "front": "**Def**: person who doesn't have a job.\n**Farsi**: بیکار",
    "back": "unemployed"
  },
  {
    "id": "83a01d13-2cc6-4e82-8833-0edcca64391f",
    "front": "**Def**: person who doesn't have enough work to do, or their skills are not made use of.\n**Farsi**: کم کار (کسی که کار کافی برای انجام ندارد یا از مهارت‌هایش استفاده نمی‌شود)",
    "back": "underemployed"
  },
  {
    "id": "9111f6f8-5f04-4e10-9acb-983687561c3f",
    "front": "**Def**: make sth legal.\n**Farsi**: قانونی کردن (چیزی را قانونی ساختن)",
    "back": "legalize"
  },
  {
    "id": "b52c77e5-c570-4eea-ab9f-d4d8fc31f05e",
    "front": "**Def**: put an industry or company under the control of the government. OPP privatize.\n**Farsi**: ملی کردن (صنعتی یا شرکتی را تحت کنترل دولت درآوردن. متضاد: privatize)",
    "back": "nationalize"
  },
  {
    "id": "d5453cd5-8b65-4b73-b3c3-65d0692b1d8d",
    "front": "**Def**: damage or destroy sth for no reason. vandalism N.\n**Farsi**: خرابکاری کردن، تخریب کردن (چیزی را بدون دلیل آسیب زدن یا نابود کردن)",
    "back": "vandalize"
  },
  {
    "id": "dd3c518e-b5e6-4946-8df0-019765cbcd53",
    "front": "**Def**: noun form of vandalize.\n**Farsi**: خرابکاری",
    "back": "vandalism"
  },
  {
    "id": "59928bc8-5c7c-4cdc-8a5d-f5f0689091a0",
    "front": "**Def**: give sth its typical quality or feature. characteristic ADJ.\n**Farsi**: مشخص کردن، ویژگی دادن (کیفیت یا ویژگی معمول خود را به چیزی دادن)",
    "back": "characterize"
  },
  {
    "id": "3ae0f4a7-9c76-4a9c-a4e0-267d1b3f9970",
    "front": "**Def**: adjective form of characterize.\n**Farsi**: مشخصه، ویژگی",
    "back": "characteristic"
  },
  {
    "id": "8c055530-3d35-4639-9f90-969be6459591",
    "front": "**Def**: form a picture of sth in your mind. SYN imagine.\n**Farsi**: تجسم کردن (تصویری از چیزی در ذهن خود ایجاد کردن. مترادف: imagine)",
    "back": "visualize"
  },
  {
    "id": "db4ab990-f3ad-4af3-93bb-5fd1e8d43c01",
    "front": "**Def**: make it greater in strength or degree. SYN heighten sth.\n**Farsi**: تشدید کردن، افزایش دادن (چیزی را از نظر قدرت یا درجه بیشتر کردن. مترادف: heighten)",
    "back": "intensify sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "1fcc809d-75a1-4c51-8787-687ce17c4da3",
    "front": "**Def**: become solid or make sth solid.\n**Farsi**: جامد کردن/شدن (جامد شدن یا چیزی را جامد کردن)",
    "back": "solidify"
  },
  {
    "id": "f8d97aa8-8cfe-454e-bec1-dea7ed60c387",
    "front": "**Def**: remove any dirty substances to make it pure.\n**Farsi**: خالص کردن (هرگونه مواد کثیف را حذف کردن تا خالص شود)",
    "back": "purify sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "8dfbaddc-99bb-4163-a197-08f39d9358a9",
    "front": "**Def**: express sth as an amount or number.\n**Farsi**: کمی‌سازی کردن، مقداردهی کردن (چیزی را به صورت مقدار یا عدد بیان کردن)",
    "back": "quantify"
  },
  {
    "id": "ec44e594-52c2-471a-a8a0-63feaa48e0e2",
    "front": "**Def**: make sb who is angry become quiet and calm. SYN placate sb.\n**Farsi**: آرام کردن (کسی را که عصبانی است، ساکت و آرام کردن. مترادف: placate)",
    "back": "pacify"
  },
  {
    "id": "e33e6161-f931-4f17-a6e1-b556518cd5a3",
    "front": "**Def**: other words ending in -ify.\n**Farsi**: برق‌دار کردن، ساده کردن، شناسایی کردن، مثال زدن، روشن کردن",
    "back": "electrify, simplify, identify, exemplify, clarify"
  },
  {
    "id": "0a469d1f-38ae-4fd8-9455-201d10b88949",
    "front": "**Def**: If sth is foolproof it is so well designed that it cannot go wrong or be used wrongly (a foolproof machine/method).\n**Farsi**: خطاناپذیر، ضد خطا (آنقدر خوب طراحی شده که نمی‌تواند اشتباه کند یا به اشتباه استفاده شود)",
    "back": "foolproof"
  },
  {
    "id": "588ee4a5-6c31-4df6-91bc-91ae03bcf818",
    "front": "**Def**: Tax-free earnings are earnings that you don't have to pay tax on.\n**Farsi**: معاف از مالیات (درآمدی که مجبور به پرداخت مالیات برای آن نیستید)",
    "back": "tax-free"
  },
  {
    "id": "6c4efca6-202e-4fd9-8fc6-e9f17c84f376",
    "front": "**Def**: savings that are safe because they are guaranteed to go up as much as inflation.\n**Farsi**: پس‌انداز ضد تورم (پس‌اندازی که تضمین شده به اندازه تورم افزایش یابد)",
    "back": "inflation-proof savings"
  },
  {
    "id": "40f0be19-9b38-453c-a928-7fb367fb430a",
    "front": "**Def**: able to be used safely inside an oven.\n**Farsi**: مناسب فر، ضد حرارت فر (قابلیت استفاده ایمن داخل فر)",
    "back": "ovenproof"
  },
  {
    "id": "80e2f0c2-b1aa-43ed-b698-ee84f3f0e631",
    "front": "**Def**: a loan that you don't have to pay interest on.\n**Farsi**: اعتبار بدون بهره (وامی که نیازی به پرداخت بهره برای آن نیست)",
    "back": "interest-free credit"
  },
  {
    "id": "86d14b72-8f43-418e-845b-392772e118fe",
    "front": "**Def**: ADJ, magnet N.\n**Farsi**: مغناطیسی",
    "back": "magnetic"
  },
  {
    "id": "429500c4-7827-4eca-8688-efc6060789cf",
    "front": "**Def**: If sth is childproof it is designed so that children cannot open or use it.\n**Farsi**: ضد کودک (طراحی شده به طوری که کودکان نتوانند آن را باز کنند یا استفاده کنند)",
    "back": "childproof"
  },
  {
    "id": "63b545df-6d14-4c29-b61c-9106974dc51a",
    "front": "**Def**: doesn't let water through.\n**Farsi**: ضد آب (اجازه عبور آب را نمی‌دهد)",
    "back": "waterproof"
  },
  {
    "id": "18be6d39-2755-42a4-a3b8-865207838d0e",
    "front": "**Def**: doesn't let sound through.\n**Farsi**: ضد صدا (اجازه عبور صدا را نمی‌دهد)",
    "back": "soundproof"
  },
  {
    "id": "dad4fb67-8547-4cab-9c5c-dd2edc70f900",
    "front": "**Def**: you don't have to pay duty (= tax).\n**Farsi**: معاف از عوارض (نیازی به پرداخت عوارض/مالیات نیست)",
    "back": "duty-free"
  },
  {
    "id": "7e1134e4-26e2-454c-bedf-4129c7b144cb",
    "front": "**Def**: a life without worry or anxiety.\n**Farsi**: زندگی بدون مشکل (زندگی بدون نگرانی یا اضطراب)",
    "back": "trouble-free life"
  },
  {
    "id": "618c90e2-67f5-4b0d-bf51-7fd1a8a32775",
    "front": "**Def**: a short piece taken from a book, piece of music, etc. SYN extract (from a film it is a clip).\n**Farsi**: گزیده‌ای از (یک قطعه کوتاه گرفته شده از کتاب یا موسیقی. مترادف: extract)",
    "back": "excerpt from"
  },
  {
    "id": "81417292-d9f5-4710-8b9b-99b3eb9f6af2",
    "front": "**Def**: 1. a way of dealing with a problem. SYN solution. 2. a treatment to cure an illness, reduce pain, etc.\n**Farsi**: راه چاره برای/درمان برای (۱. راه حلی برای مشکل. ۲. درمان برای بیماری)",
    "back": "remedy for"
  },
  {
    "id": "82c9b205-719c-4de7-9166-4109b060d07a",
    "front": "**Def**: natural skill or ability in doing sth.\n**Farsi**: استعداد برای (مهارت یا توانایی طبیعی در انجام کاری)",
    "back": "aptitude for"
  },
  {
    "id": "a389b4b8-e4bb-4c5f-8cac-474872a047ca",
    "front": "**Def**: a law or rule that limits what you can do, or what can happen.\n**Farsi**: محدودیت بر (قانون یا قاعده‌ای که آنچه می‌توانید انجام دهید را محدود می‌کند)",
    "back": "restriction on"
  },
  {
    "id": "8c8afb0c-9972-4043-918e-bb4b7262b56b",
    "front": "**Def**: different items, especially music or writing, that are brought together in a performance, CD, or book.\n**Farsi**: مجموعه‌ای از (اقلام مختلف، به ویژه موسیقی یا نوشته، که در کنار هم جمع شده‌اند)",
    "back": "compilation of"
  },
  {
    "id": "9c331609-3c57-4a99-8ea3-de059f805822",
    "front": "**Def**: a lack of care or concern about sth (you can also have no regard for sth).\n**Farsi**: بی‌توجهی کامل به (عدم مراقبت یا نگرانی در مورد چیزی)",
    "back": "disregard for"
  },
  {
    "id": "cebe18ee-5eae-4cca-bd0c-c84202e2016f",
    "front": "**Def**: an abnormal worry or concern about sth.\n**Farsi**: عقده، نگرانی غیرعادی در مورد (نگرانی غیرطبیعی در مورد چیزی)",
    "back": "complex about"
  },
  {
    "id": "644236a6-021b-48fa-a04c-f50331b2c8ad",
    "front": "**Def**: a thing that you use or have instead of the one you usually use or have.\n**Farsi**: جایگزین برای (چیزی که به جای چیز دیگری استفاده می‌شود)",
    "back": "substitute for"
  },
  {
    "id": "57ab3dd1-ee63-4023-a1d0-f5ae418dbf91",
    "front": "**Def**: a feeling of dislike for sb because of sth they have done to you.\n**Farsi**: کینه، نفرت نسبت به (احساس ناخوشایندی نسبت به کسی به خاطر کاری که انجام داده)",
    "back": "grudge against"
  },
  {
    "id": "7da07365-3275-48dd-81c7-c97e12b480ec",
    "front": "**Def**: the act of participating in sth.\n**Farsi**: درگیری/مشارکت با (عمل شرکت کردن در چیزی)",
    "back": "involvement with"
  },
  {
    "id": "186f7798-39bf-4f8e-b895-8f8c4eb2c8d1",
    "front": "**Def**: a rule that says sth is not allowed.\n**Farsi**: ممنوعیت بر (قانونی که می‌گوید چیزی مجاز نیست)",
    "back": "ban on"
  },
  {
    "id": "24a0f593-e293-4830-b7ee-a66eaab4f5f7",
    "front": "**Def**: You can gain/keep/lose control of sth/sb. You can also have control over sb/sth.\n**Farsi**: کنترل بر چیزی/کسی",
    "back": "control of/over sth/sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "c9c3cd22-196b-4027-993c-b6f421120113",
    "front": "**Def**: start to do sth new or difficult.\n**Farsi**: شروع به کار جدید یا دشوار کردن",
    "back": "embark on sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "20e10126-c69c-4e6e-8881-d828b0ee2061",
    "front": "**Def**: determined to do sth.\n**Farsi**: مصمم به انجام کاری",
    "back": "intent upon/on sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "1624b91d-7ac3-47fd-8c50-2f37a2ab5cd0",
    "front": "**Def**: likely to be affected by sth, especially sth bad.\n**Farsi**: در معرض چیزی بودن (احتمالاً تحت تأثیر چیزی قرار گرفتن، به ویژه چیز بد)",
    "back": "subject to sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "fc83087e-1ba0-477c-9c80-5a395a892266",
    "front": "**Def**: be the result of sth.\n**Farsi**: ناشی شدن از، نتیجه بودن (نتیجه چیزی بودن)",
    "back": "stem from sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "820d863c-c978-4ea1-9282-3767d8631945",
    "front": "**Def**: able to be used with sth or exist with sb without causing problems.\n**Farsi**: سازگار با (قابل استفاده با چیزی یا موجود بودن با کسی بدون ایجاد مشکل)",
    "back": "compatible with sth/sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "c644810e-8932-4fe5-95ab-9cb01fd13746",
    "front": "**Def**: accept an unpleasant situation.\n**Farsi**: با چیزی کنار آمدن، تحمل کردن (پذیرفتن یک وضعیت ناخوشایند)",
    "back": "live with sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "4084080f-bd74-40a7-9ea3-5bc7818c1292",
    "front": "**Def**: opposed to sth and trying to stop it happening.\n**Farsi**: مقاوم در برابر (مخالف چیزی و تلاش برای جلوگیری از وقوع آن)",
    "back": "resistant to sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "10972651-1631-4070-9bbc-5a51e9045d08",
    "front": "**Def**: typical of a particular group or thing.\n**Farsi**: نماینده، نمونه‌ای از (نمایانگر یک گروه یا چیز خاص)",
    "back": "representative of sth/sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "de43ffa0-4db2-4c3e-b337-d30f4b4faf01",
    "front": "**Def**: always obeying sb and doing what they want.\n**Farsi**: فرمانبردار، مطیع (همیشه از کسی اطاعت کردن و آنچه را می‌خواهند انجام دادن)",
    "back": "subservient to sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "2520f34d-7000-48ef-baf9-93ba7f169589",
    "front": "**Def**: tending to remind people of sth/sb.\n**Farsi**: یادآور چیزی/کسی (تمایل به یادآوری چیزی/کسی داشتن)",
    "back": "reminiscent of sth/sb"
  },
  {
    "id": "e906b6e1-0bd1-4f81-bff5-a6ee0876906c",
    "front": "**Def**: according to how good sb is, and for no other reason.\n**Farsi**: بر اساس شایستگی (مطابق با کیفیت کسی و نه دلیل دیگری)",
    "back": "on merit"
  },
  {
    "id": "88300c73-3c14-49fe-a503-c51093c8865b",
    "front": "**Def**: after considering all the facts. SYN all things considered.\n**Farsi**: با در نظر گرفتن همه جوانب (بعد از بررسی همه حقایق. مترادف: all things considered)",
    "back": "on balance"
  },
  {
    "id": "4179c7c0-ae08-4b52-bd95-2c11d169d6e6",
    "front": "**Def**: after thinking carefully about sth.\n**Farsi**: با تأمل، پس از تفکر (بعد از فکر کردن دقیق در مورد چیزی)",
    "back": "on reflection"
  },
  {
    "id": "d05a402d-cecf-4a21-9481-ee96e53052dd",
    "front": "**Def**: as a thing you have chosen.\n**Farsi**: با انتخاب خود (به عنوان چیزی که شما انتخاب کرده‌اید)",
    "back": "by choice"
  },
  {
    "id": "ac29c843-4f48-4e46-815a-bd4c131bb7dc",
    "front": "**Def**: 1. always. 2. When you tell sb to do sth without fail, you are telling them they must do it (Be home by 10.00 without fail!).\n**Farsi**: ۱. بدون استثنا، همیشه. ۲. به یقین (اطمینان دادن به کسی که باید کاری را انجام دهد)",
    "back": "without fail"
  },
  {
    "id": "ca39273c-9275-496e-ab7d-18c033e8e800",
    "front": "**Def**: with very little warning (also at a moment's notice).\n**Farsi**: با اطلاع قبلی کم، در فرصت کم (با هشدار بسیار کم)",
    "back": "at short notice"
  },
  {
    "id": "9107384f-2351-4f76-8856-a3de678483cb",
    "front": "**Def**: immediately. SYNS right away, straightaway.\n**Farsi**: فوراً، بی‌درنگ (مترادف‌ها: right away, straightaway)",
    "back": "at once"
  },
  {
    "id": "cbfb9ee7-2a26-4297-8fe2-8d41238aa7f2",
    "front": "**Def**: If you give sb sth in exchange for sth, you give them sth and they give you sth of a similar value or type.\n**Farsi**: در ازای، در عوض (مبادله چیزی با چیزی دیگر با ارزش یا نوع مشابه)",
    "back": "in exchange for sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "47bdbe8e-4bcb-407f-a76f-e4af0f114f1a",
    "front": "**Def**: If you say sth in passing, you say it while you are talking about sth else.\n**Farsi**: به طور گذرا، در حین صحبت (چیزی را در حالی که درباره چیز دیگری صحبت می‌کنید، بگویید)",
    "back": "in passing"
  },
  {
    "id": "2028f3a3-eb9a-4a59-84ba-4b97727670cf",
    "front": "**Def**: as an absolute minimum.\n**Farsi**: حداقل، دست‌کم (به عنوان یک حداقل مطلق)",
    "back": "at the very least"
  },
  {
    "id": "b8b5219c-13b2-48c0-b5ec-0f4688e5c653",
    "front": "**Def**: no longer having recent knowledge or information about sth. OPP in touch (also out of luck, out of sight).\n**Farsi**: بی‌اطلاع از (دیگر دانش یا اطلاعات جدیدی در مورد چیزی نداشتن. متضاد: in touch)",
    "back": "out of touch (with sth)"
  },
  {
    "id": "79b549a8-5313-473e-a82b-838341a397f4",
    "front": "**Def**: in order to show respect and admiration for sb or sth.\n**Farsi**: به افتخار، به احترام (به منظور نشان دادن احترام و تحسین برای کسی یا چیزی)",
    "back": "in honour of sb/sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "dba39b0f-5477-4402-822a-927e9be0b13e",
    "front": "**Def**: (of a company) very large and successful.\n**Farsi**: غول پیکر (در مورد یک شرکت، بسیار بزرگ و موفق)",
    "back": "giant"
  },
  {
    "id": "172faefd-35b5-48dc-a28f-e00ba2b92177",
    "front": "**Def**: delayed until a later time or date.\n**Farsi**: در حالت تعلیق، نگه داشته شده (به تعویق افتاده تا زمان یا تاریخ بعدی)",
    "back": "on hold"
  },
  {
    "id": "159266bc-f308-414b-b17d-16f1e4e5d047",
    "front": "**Def**: in honour of, and to remind people of, sb who has died.\n**Farsi**: به یاد، در خاطره (به افتخار و برای یادآوری کسی که مرده است)",
    "back": "in memory of sb/sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "750804c0-5440-42b4-a153-ea1bbec42b99",
    "front": "**Def**: FML having or holding sth.\n**Farsi**: در تملک، دارا بودن (داشتن یا نگه داشتن چیزی)",
    "back": "in possession of sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "58a9ff39-39be-4270-908d-0bf35e40a03d",
    "front": "**Def**: FML with the help of sth.\n**Farsi**: به وسیله، از طریق (با کمک چیزی)",
    "back": "by means of sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "5ba014d6-7ed6-4872-a724-8c3819133241",
    "front": "**Def**: in a position of authority, especially in government (also in power, in danger, in trouble).\n**Farsi**: در مقام، در سِمَت (در موقعیت اقتدار، به ویژه در دولت)",
    "back": "in office"
  },
  {
    "id": "c3aef13d-41f7-4ccf-b2e6-9f075360f5df",
    "front": "**Def**: because of consideration and respect felt for sb.\n**Farsi**: به دلیل احترام (به دلیل توجه و احترامی که برای کسی قائل هستند)",
    "back": "out of respect (for sb)"
  },
  {
    "id": "16146d3b-38ce-440f-bb98-2052aa34edcb",
    "front": "**Def**: If sb is bereaved, a close friend or relative has recently died.\n**Farsi**: داغدار (کسی که یکی از نزدیکانش اخیراً فوت کرده است)",
    "back": "bereaved"
  },
  {
    "id": "5fdf51e2-1867-447e-b197-c6c74d416403",
    "front": "**Def**: unusually good. SYN outstanding.\n**Farsi**: استثنایی (به طور غیرعادی خوب. مترادف: outstanding)",
    "back": "exceptional"
  },
  {
    "id": "18b7d9a1-a65e-4b0f-b775-93d7de3177fe",
    "front": "**Def**: famous and respected, often for being good at a profession.\n**Farsi**: برجسته، سرشناس (مشهور و مورد احترام، اغلب به دلیل خوب بودن در حرفه)",
    "back": "eminent"
  },
  {
    "id": "4ff06512-9e33-45a7-86be-a0c44606edc5",
    "front": "**Def**: confused because you are unable to understand sth. SYNS puzzled, baffled.\n**Farsi**: گیج، متحیر (سردرگم چون قادر به درک چیزی نیست. مترادف‌ها: puzzled, baffled)",
    "back": "perplexed"
  },
  {
    "id": "fc3debcb-8558-4089-9482-98fa1aea0f45",
    "front": "**Def**: very strange and unusual. SYN weird.\n**Farsi**: عجیب و غریب (بسیار عجیب و غیرمعمول. مترادف: weird)",
    "back": "bizarre"
  },
  {
    "id": "176e0b91-0edb-4132-a126-880092e4f4b7",
    "front": "**Def**: not reasonable or likely to be true. OPP plausible. (A convincing story makes you believe it is true. OPP unconvincing.)\n**Farsi**: باورنکردنی، غیرمحتمل (معقول نیست یا احتمال وقوع آن کم است. متضاد: plausible)",
    "back": "implausible"
  },
  {
    "id": "050917d1-4fcf-466e-9600-5e238828fd5d",
    "front": "**Def**: likely to be true.\n**Farsi**: باورپذیر، محتمل",
    "back": "plausible"
  },
  {
    "id": "4f49bd5b-72a2-4dd8-8186-6710801562db",
    "front": "**Def**: able to be imagined or believed; possible. OPP inconceivable.\n**Farsi**: قابل تصور، ممکن (قابل تصور یا باور است. متضاد: inconceivable)",
    "back": "conceivable"
  },
  {
    "id": "9ba88484-1969-4268-a6e2-12499d8cf59e",
    "front": "**Def**: opposite of conceivable.\n**Farsi**: غیرقابل تصور",
    "back": "inconceivable"
  },
  {
    "id": "16f10406-1cba-4acd-94bf-626283265249",
    "front": "**Def**: bad and morally wrong. SYN evil.\n**Farsi**: پلید، شریر (بد و از نظر اخلاقی نادرست. مترادف: evil)",
    "back": "wicked"
  },
  {
    "id": "4546ac39-2ae0-4600-a6c6-4f7d6cf29a2d",
    "front": "**Def**: unhappy and depressed. SYN despondent.\n**Farsi**: افسرده، دل‌شکسته (ناراحت و افسرده. مترادف: despondent)",
    "back": "dejected"
  },
  {
    "id": "12ae3659-06ff-4219-8bb3-3973170b34ed",
    "front": "**Def**: well known for being bad (e.g. a notorious criminal). SYN infamous FML.\n**Farsi**: بدنام، انگشت‌نما (معروف بودن به دلیل بد بودن. مترادف: infamous)",
    "back": "notorious"
  },
  {
    "id": "0aeef11c-016d-4bd3-a91d-218e78e01762",
    "front": "**Def**: (of the final chapter/section of sth) ending.\n**Farsi**: پایانی، اختتامیه (مربوط به فصل/بخش نهایی چیزی)",
    "back": "concluding"
  },
  {
    "id": "4d7187db-c8cb-42de-9369-4b7497a25242",
    "front": "**Def**: showing sth to be definitely true.\n**Farsi**: قطعی، قاطع (نشان دادن اینکه چیزی قطعاً درست است)",
    "back": "conclusive"
  },
  {
    "id": "37708cd0-c89c-4f1e-b45d-6d546a04a0d1",
    "front": "**Def**: (especially of clothes, furniture, etc.) attractive and of good quality.\n**Farsi**: خوش سلیقه، با ذوق (جذاب و با کیفیت خوب، به ویژه در مورد لباس، مبلمان)",
    "back": "tasteful"
  },
  {
    "id": "b1cb703f-9dfa-4019-859c-d2c285eb5147",
    "front": "**Def**: having a pleasant taste (tasteless is the opposite of tasty and tasteful).\n**Farsi**: خوشمزه (دارای طعم دلپذیر)",
    "back": "tasty"
  },
  {
    "id": "169640cc-335e-4bb3-9651-be561c4e5891",
    "front": "**Def**: not wearing clothes.\n**Farsi**: برهنه (لباس نپوشیده)",
    "back": "naked"
  },
  {
    "id": "0783be98-5a13-4b5b-8004-3f7866d973a4",
    "front": "**Def**: used to talk about the naked human form in art (in the nude = naked).\n**Farsi**: عریان (برای صحبت در مورد فرم برهنه انسان در هنر)",
    "back": "nude"
  },
  {
    "id": "1e9afa2f-7509-4d75-b12a-835d2160f2bb",
    "front": "**Def**: (of a part of the body) not covered by clothes (bare head/arms/legs).\n**Farsi**: لخت، بدون پوشش (در مورد بخشی از بدن، پوشیده نشده توسط لباس)",
    "back": "bare"
  },
  {
    "id": "2c3bfe6d-ea7a-4ea2-b573-cdbec8af4d54",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely tired. SYN worn out.\n**Farsi**: خسته و کوفته (بسیار خسته. مترادف: worn out)",
    "back": "exhausted"
  },
  {
    "id": "5c541ce7-de46-4065-a1a5-ee8ea6f15fa3",
    "front": "**Def**: extremely thorough and complete.\n**Farsi**: جامع، کامل (بسیار کامل و جامع)",
    "back": "exhaustive"
  },
  {
    "id": "ec832015-cac7-4be9-bc51-7bb6cee3be4e",
    "front": "**Def**: able to be understood. SYN intelligible. OPP incomprehensible, unintelligible.\n**Farsi**: قابل درک (قابل فهم. مترادف: intelligible. متضاد: incomprehensible, unintelligible)",
    "back": "comprehensible"
  },
  {
    "id": "9bb965eb-c9e9-4f96-9e31-29021d7a45a5",
    "front": "**Def**: very useful or valuable.\n**Farsi**: بسیار با ارزش، گرانبها (بسیار مفید یا با ارزش)",
    "back": "invaluable"
  },
  {
    "id": "2b7bcd54-85f8-4a8a-8c82-0533f3bc72b9",
    "front": "**Def**: having no worth or value. SYN valueless.\n**Farsi**: بی‌ارزش (فاقد ارزش یا قیمت. مترادف: valueless)",
    "back": "worthless"
  },
  {
    "id": "a5ec98c8-b586-4841-b904-f42622f80bfb",
    "front": "**Def**: APPROVING having qualities typical of a child (enthusiasm, innocence).\n**Farsi**: کودکانه (مثبت) (دارای ویژگی‌های معمول یک کودک، مانند معصومیت)",
    "back": "childlike"
  },
  {
    "id": "44926ab9-bb37-477d-a2b0-9d951986b8e9",
    "front": "**Def**: DISAPPROVING behaving in a silly way.\n**Farsi**: بچگانه (منفی) (رفتار احمقانه داشتن)",
    "back": "childish"
  },
  {
    "id": "a4335eee-d02a-4f92-b711-ae50ba7507e9",
    "front": "**Def**: so small as to be of no importance.\n**Farsi**: ناچیز، بی‌اهمیت (آنقدر کوچک که اهمیت ندارد)",
    "back": "negligible"
  },
  {
    "id": "bad442aa-43c9-4f55-b585-cdb0241b30b2",
    "front": "**Def**: according to what you have heard or read. SYN evidently.\n**Farsi**: ظاهراً، بنابر آنچه شنیده شده یا خوانده‌اید. (مترادف: evidently)",
    "back": "apparently"
  },
  {
    "id": "d7290892-e52b-4baf-969f-f8e756978124",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say that you think sth is probably true.\n**Farsi**: احتمالاً، برای بیان اینکه فکر می‌کنید چیزی احتمالاً درست است.",
    "back": "presumably"
  },
  {
    "id": "c79a1ae8-e2bc-4d92-b750-bbd2fb9340a6",
    "front": "**Def**: finally, when everything has been considered.\n**Farsi**: در نهایت، وقتی همه چیز در نظر گرفته شد.",
    "back": "ultimately"
  },
  {
    "id": "1c72fc53-0277-48f8-bf71-b85ec4dc38a7",
    "front": "**Def**: used when giving information that you expect other people to know already or agree with. SYN clearly.\n**Farsi**: بدیهی است، برای ارائه اطلاعاتی که انتظار دارید دیگران از قبل بدانند یا با آن موافق باشند. (مترادف: clearly)",
    "back": "obviously"
  },
  {
    "id": "47cca31a-f3f9-49a7-81a7-eac50604f71c",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say that sth is normal and not surprising. SYN of course.\n**Farsi**: طبیعتاً، برای بیان اینکه چیزی عادی و غیرمنتظره نیست. (مترادف: of course)",
    "back": "naturally"
  },
  {
    "id": "e39255f3-e5b7-4f25-9d69-6acefd8deae7",
    "front": "**Def**: used when giving the most important fact. SYN essentially.\n**Farsi**: اساساً، برای بیان مهم‌ترین واقعیت. (مترادف: essentially)",
    "back": "basically"
  },
  {
    "id": "d25c915b-07be-4713-be41-0d5cae9b9973",
    "front": "**Def**: almost. SYN virtually.\n**Farsi**: عملاً، تقریباً. (مترادف: virtually)",
    "back": "practically"
  },
  {
    "id": "b4993b6a-fe58-47d4-bf76-e2dd8e4bb55f",
    "front": "**Def**: used to show that sth is surprising. SYNS oddly/curiously (enough).\n**Farsi**: به اندازه کافی عجیب، برای نشان دادن اینکه چیزی تعجب‌آور است. (مترادف: oddly, curiously)",
    "back": "strangely (enough)"
  },
  {
    "id": "ad9a1953-7d9a-4940-a0b1-7ee83dbce404",
    "front": "**Def**: = from the point of view of sales or profit. SYN financially.\n**Farsi**: از نظر تجاری، از دیدگاه فروش یا سود. (مترادف: financially)",
    "back": "commercially"
  },
  {
    "id": "0a9dcbb0-29b6-4b35-be98-8168a3f02329",
    "front": "**Def**: = according to past custom.\n**Farsi**: به طور سنتی، مطابق با آداب و رسوم گذشته.",
    "back": "traditionally"
  },
  {
    "id": "e0a514d0-91f2-42b6-866a-9efae3652bbf",
    "front": "**Def**: = if we are to act sensibly and with sound reasons. logical ADJ. logic N.\n**Farsi**: منطقاً، اگر قرار است عاقلانه و با دلایل محکم عمل کنیم.",
    "back": "logically"
  },
  {
    "id": "b4f21b05-c3f5-45a3-b64f-f5170caef9a6",
    "front": "**Def**: = from the point of view of making friends. social ADJ.\n**Farsi**: از نظر اجتماعی، از دیدگاه دوست‌یابی و روابط.",
    "back": "socially"
  },
  {
    "id": "87eaba16-d234-4059-95da-abb1289e7ffc",
    "front": "**Def**: = if we are sensible about what can be achieved, we have to conclude that...\n**Farsi**: واقع‌بینانه، اگر در مورد آنچه می‌توان به دست آورد منطقی باشیم، باید نتیجه بگیریم که...",
    "back": "realistically"
  },
  {
    "id": "416363b2-9e85-4328-92f1-8c773ca0b35a",
    "front": "**Def**: = according to the rules, or what we have been told. opp unofficially.\n**Farsi**: رسماً، طبق قوانین یا آنچه به ما گفته شده است. (متضاد: unofficially)",
    "back": "officially"
  },
  {
    "id": "f079e418-b22a-4bd0-af83-b9a64f22360f",
    "front": "**Def**: = as an additional effect or consequence. opp directly.\n**Farsi**: به طور غیرمستقیم، به عنوان یک اثر یا پیامد اضافی. (متضاد: directly)",
    "back": "indirectly"
  },
  {
    "id": "721c9e1e-3364-4346-8fc0-c1d4753fc562",
    "front": "**Def**: = from the point of view of her technical skill. technical ADJ. technique N.\n**Farsi**: از نظر فنی، از دیدگاه مهارت فنی.",
    "back": "technically"
  },
  {
    "id": "867b462f-d4d4-40e9-a6dc-6ff6d4258a64",
    "front": "**Def**: = considering the effect on the body.\n**Farsi**: از نظر فیزیکی، با در نظر گرفتن اثر بر بدن.",
    "back": "physically"
  },
  {
    "id": "f663e80c-f726-4c03-9274-7b8d427fe531",
    "front": "**Def**: = considering the effect on the mind.\n**Farsi**: از نظر ذهنی/روانی، با در نظر گرفتن اثر بر ذهن.",
    "back": "mentally"
  },
  {
    "id": "3b4da459-1b65-44b1-989e-9fe92198a9cd",
    "front": "**Def**: used to say that sth could possibly happen or be true, but is unlikely.\n**Farsi**: از لحاظ تئوری، برای بیان اینکه چیزی ممکن است اتفاق بیفتد یا درست باشد، اما بعید است.",
    "back": "theoretically"
  },
  {
    "id": "1ba90592-fd81-42db-9ded-a7e4b733ca28",
    "front": "**Def**: used to give facts or an opinion about an aspect of sth.\n**Farsi**: تا آنجا که به فلان چیز مربوط می‌شود، برای ارائه حقایق یا نظری در مورد جنبه‌ای از یک موضوع.",
    "back": "as far as sth is concerned"
  },
  {
    "id": "7dc526a5-6906-445f-8635-09cc8d34fb9e",
    "front": "**Def**: 1 for a short time. 2 in a few words (he explained briefly).\n**Farsi**: ۱. به طور مختصر (برای مدت زمان کوتاه). ۲. در چند کلمه.",
    "back": "briefly"
  },
  {
    "id": "6d2b320f-7cad-4c4d-abee-56aea9aab301",
    "front": "**Def**: for a long time; for all time (nothing lasts forever).\n**Farsi**: برای همیشه، برای مدت طولانی؛ برای تمام زمان‌ها.",
    "back": "forever"
  },
  {
    "id": "32bd6608-9d33-43dd-9cc7-0f804b6e3ff7",
    "front": "**Def**: completely and only (purely by chance). SYN simply.\n**Farsi**: کاملاً و فقط (صرفاً، محض). (مترادف: simply)",
    "back": "purely"
  },
  {
    "id": "a35f91f7-74d4-4ad4-88a8-33dfaf98a0f4",
    "front": "**Def**: just; only (also, absolutely: He was simply brilliant.).\n**Farsi**: فقط؛ صرفاً (همچنین، به طور مطلق: به سادگی درخشان بود).",
    "back": "simply"
  },
  {
    "id": "9a7fe66d-fe9b-46fa-bc50-356ad37af95d",
    "front": "**Def**: exactly and correctly (also used to emphasize that sth is very true or obvious: He's very young: that's precisely why he needs my help.).\n**Farsi**: دقیقاً و درست (همچنین برای تأکید بر اینکه چیزی بسیار درست یا واضح است: دقیقاً).",
    "back": "precisely"
  },
  {
    "id": "29c58f47-c0aa-471f-b914-0a9ae216ff1b",
    "front": "**Def**: sincerely (also used to emphasize a particular quality: a truly remarkable man).\n**Farsi**: واقعاً، صمیمانه (همچنین برای تأکید بر یک کیفیت خاص: یک مرد واقعاً قابل توجه).",
    "back": "truly"
  },
  {
    "id": "f8210db5-46a5-41f9-a368-25341aa8c553",
    "front": "**Def**: used to emphasize that sth is always true or always happens.\n**Farsi**: همیشه، مرتباً، برای تأکید بر اینکه چیزی همیشه درست است یا همیشه اتفاق می‌افتد.",
    "back": "invariably"
  },
  {
    "id": "836904ce-b722-4585-91b4-1e841ff4a1ff",
    "front": "**Def**: mainly. SYNS chiefly, predominantly.\n**Farsi**: عمدتاً، در درجه اول. (مترادف: chiefly, predominantly)",
    "back": "primarily"
  },
  {
    "id": "6a11d385-20fc-408b-8ad7-6f21335ba84d",
    "front": "**Def**: fairly; quite (can be used after a verb or before an adjective).\n**Farsi**: تا حدودی، نسبتاً (می‌تواند بعد از فعل یا قبل از صفت استفاده شود).",
    "back": "somewhat"
  },
  {
    "id": "25acf507-eba2-4677-b073-8bbf197cfe7b",
    "front": "**Def**: to a fairly large degree in comparison with sth else.\n**Farsi**: نسبتاً، تا حد زیادی در مقایسه با چیز دیگری.",
    "back": "relatively"
  },
  {
    "id": "846698b5-420b-4c1c-af0f-1d3351d7c7a3",
    "front": "**Def**: INF (of a person) quite old.\n**Farsi**: سن و سالی ازش گذشته (غیررسمی، برای فرد) نسبتاً پیر.",
    "back": "getting on (a bit)"
  },
  {
    "id": "084271fe-d643-4405-ae95-9c51b4234485",
    "front": "**Def**: having poor eyesight.\n**Farsi**: کم‌بینا، دارای بینایی ضعیف.",
    "back": "visually impaired"
  },
  {
    "id": "9e8c2dc3-b2b0-418a-8e71-a6d0da9384dd",
    "front": "**Def**: unable to hear very well.\n**Farsi**: سنگین‌گوش، کسی که به سختی می‌شنود.",
    "back": "hard of hearing"
  },
  {
    "id": "4ccc2b62-3e6f-41db-b302-adafab6643c9",
    "front": "**Def**: die. SYN pass on.\n**Farsi**: فوت کردن، درگذشتن. (مترادف: pass on)",
    "back": "pass away"
  },
  {
    "id": "6979b063-be24-4717-8604-cabd25ed5f10",
    "front": "**Def**: kill a sick or injured animal with drugs so that it dies without pain. SYN put sth down.\n**Farsi**: حیوان بیمار یا مجروح را خواباندن (کشتن بدون درد).",
    "back": "put sth to sleep"
  },
  {
    "id": "b6abe019-d93c-4e22-a961-c5ca494cff2b",
    "front": "**Def**: the dismissing of employees to reduce costs. downsize v.\n**Farsi**: کاهش نیروی کار (تعدیل نیرو) برای کاهش هزینه‌ها.",
    "back": "downsizing"
  },
  {
    "id": "898b4392-7001-47b9-8caf-507a919e4472",
    "front": "**Def**: dismiss sb or make them redundant.\n**Farsi**: اخراج کردن کسی یا مرخص کردن او (به دلیل کاهش نیرو).",
    "back": "let sb go"
  },
  {
    "id": "aa69c4d0-c6ac-4936-95d6-5d9002a56800",
    "front": "**Def**: a way of saying that sb is unintelligent (also not exactly clever/practical, etc.).\n**Farsi**: خیلی باهوش نیست (روشی غیرمستقیم برای گفتن اینکه کسی کودن است).",
    "back": "not exactly bright"
  },
  {
    "id": "96b515bd-f31a-43f3-8acf-cf2e282d5b6f",
    "front": "**Def**: DISAPPROVING steal sth.\n**Farsi**: دست درازی کردن به چیزی، چیزی را دزدیدن (با لحن ناپسند).",
    "back": "help yourself to sth"
  },
  {
    "id": "644a497d-dbee-45c6-bb04-00d0dbfe3f54",
    "front": "**Def**: If sb is killed or injured by friendly fire, they are hit by a bomb or weapon fired by their own side.\n**Farsi**: آتش خودی، هدف قرار گرفتن توسط بمب یا سلاح شلیک شده توسط نیروهای خودی.",
    "back": "friendly fire"
  },
  {
    "id": "4ceef086-7ff8-4edd-a26c-b32332ded113",
    "front": "**Def**: death or injury to ordinary citizens, and possibly damage to buildings as well, during the course of a war.\n**Farsi**: خسارت جانبی، مرگ یا جراحت شهروندان عادی و آسیب احتمالی به ساختمان‌ها در طول جنگ.",
    "back": "collateral damage"
  },
  {
    "id": "6d0ae1ec-5a4a-4ad6-bdbc-35ad22a4ea58",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective form related to addiction.\n**Farsi**: معتاد",
    "back": "addicted"
  },
  {
    "id": "c87589f8-6e30-4800-8d2f-1c56f564c16e",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun form meaning being dependent on something.\n**Farsi**: اعتیاد",
    "back": "addiction"
  },
  {
    "id": "160f73b1-0b8f-4326-bba3-b0ca24c4c856",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun form meaning an extra thing or person.\n**Farsi**: الحاق، افزوده",
    "back": "addition"
  },
  {
    "id": "f64fbc23-3400-454e-bfca-867107f9ec8e",
    "front": "**Def**: Feeling isolated or estranged.\n**Farsi**: بیگانه شده",
    "back": "alienated"
  },
  {
    "id": "e98c352f-bffb-4b8d-8b9d-c4fe807ccd9a",
    "front": "**Def**: The state of being isolated.\n**Farsi**: بیگانگی",
    "back": "alienation"
  },
  {
    "id": "1b7b6265-f01e-45a8-8b0c-0d4d1c179bec",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning not identified by name.\n**Farsi**: ناشناس",
    "back": "anonymous"
  },
  {
    "id": "7c42e8fd-a9dd-46dd-8628-a75ff09b78e9",
    "front": "**Def**: Having a pleasant and distinctive smell.\n**Farsi**: معطر، خوشبو",
    "back": "aromatic"
  },
  {
    "id": "ee9b3a40-165b-4cdf-b097-a579a212ce9d",
    "front": "**Def**: A distinctive, typically pleasant smell.\n**Farsi**: رایحه، عطر",
    "back": "aroma"
  },
  {
    "id": "5364ca2a-8ccb-4ad6-9770-646bf2176070",
    "front": "**Def**: Paying close attention to something.\n**Farsi**: مواظب، متوجه",
    "back": "attentive"
  },
  {
    "id": "48adbf3e-cde6-4329-884b-81e01fbfc805",
    "front": "**Def**: The act or state of applying the mind to something.\n**Farsi**: توجه",
    "back": "attention"
  },
  {
    "id": "a72677f8-6ff7-4563-96cb-378e24fb96cd",
    "front": "**Def**: The state of being deprived of a loved one by death.\n**Farsi**: داغداری، مصیبت از دست دادن عزیز",
    "back": "bereavement"
  },
  {
    "id": "bfe46d53-4204-4358-94d0-7876daa79f71",
    "front": "**Def**: The quality of being blunt or direct.\n**Farsi**: رک‌گویی، کندی",
    "back": "bluntness"
  },
  {
    "id": "e42aad24-ac0c-4bae-958c-ed65f2eb3135",
    "front": "**Def**: In a state of complete confusion and disorder.\n**Farsi**: آشفته، بی‌نظم",
    "back": "chaotic"
  },
  {
    "id": "d8f096a7-02f6-4921-a089-c2b873e3046e",
    "front": "**Def**: Complete disorder and confusion.\n**Farsi**: هرج و مرج، آشوب",
    "back": "chaos"
  },
  {
    "id": "be40ebe0-6b88-41a2-bdbb-1a2f4f61ad61",
    "front": "**Def**: Able to exist or occur together without conflict.\n**Farsi**: سازگار",
    "back": "compatible"
  },
  {
    "id": "0b81767d-8351-4db5-b753-70471c11699c",
    "front": "**Def**: A state in which two things can exist together.\n**Farsi**: سازگاری",
    "back": "compatibility"
  },
  {
    "id": "6acdd1b6-7633-481d-9c6f-4a246eaca7cb",
    "front": "**Def**: The quality of being concise.\n**Farsi**: ایجاز، اختصار",
    "back": "conciseness"
  },
  {
    "id": "88ad6829-88cb-4a8e-8cc9-bcc7fbb652ac",
    "front": "**Def**: Wilfully causing pain or suffering to others.\n**Farsi**: ظالم، بی‌رحم",
    "back": "cruel"
  },
  {
    "id": "19f6b0de-fe64-4b1e-8585-8b6ccb57c818",
    "front": "**Def**: Cruel behaviour or attitudes.\n**Farsi**: بی‌رحمی، ظلم",
    "back": "cruelty"
  },
  {
    "id": "17bac4a9-63b9-4712-92d3-30d141ea22d1",
    "front": "**Def**: Careful and circumspect in one's speech or actions.\n**Farsi**: بااحتیاط، محتاط",
    "back": "discreet"
  },
  {
    "id": "c74341f3-c78e-4e9e-bf24-f65a2b7b5274",
    "front": "**Def**: The quality of behaving in such a way as to avoid causing offence or revealing private information.\n**Farsi**: احتیاط، بصیرت",
    "back": "discretion"
  },
  {
    "id": "61c24cd7-f933-45b8-b5e8-0c03147cb606",
    "front": "**Def**: Unable to concentrate because one's mind is preoccupied.\n**Farsi**: پرت حواس، گیج",
    "back": "distracted"
  },
  {
    "id": "2a986f8b-bd38-47bf-a9bd-81b276f0a6ad",
    "front": "**Def**: A thing that prevents someone from concentrating.\n**Farsi**: حواس‌پرتی",
    "back": "distraction"
  },
  {
    "id": "03b5769c-6f31-4426-a72b-a3eef9e3d1ce",
    "front": "**Def**: Feeling or expressing overwhelming happiness or joyful excitement.\n**Farsi**: سرمست، به شدت خوشحال",
    "back": "ecstatic"
  },
  {
    "id": "5e9ed073-b1c4-4cfb-ae2e-289d8ebcbf27",
    "front": "**Def**: An overwhelming feeling of great joy or excitement.\n**Farsi**: شادی بی‌حد، وجد",
    "back": "ecstasy"
  },
  {
    "id": "e1a5f13c-cf1c-44c1-a476-4d99ff624156",
    "front": "**Def**: Ecstatically happy.\n**Farsi**: سرحال، شادمان",
    "back": "elated"
  },
  {
    "id": "c1c85656-8050-4f20-b6b3-ceb3ce87e9af",
    "front": "**Def**: Great happiness and exhilaration.\n**Farsi**: شادی زیاد",
    "back": "elation"
  },
  {
    "id": "5e30ac40-e3d3-41ee-b6e2-550cb826d76e",
    "front": "**Def**: Loyal, constant, and steadfast.\n**Farsi**: وفادار",
    "back": "faithful"
  },
  {
    "id": "4105f4ff-0287-4300-a490-68a2326be196",
    "front": "**Def**: Well known from long or close association.\n**Farsi**: آشنا",
    "back": "familiar"
  },
  {
    "id": "e09d8439-4dfd-4e81-917e-ca676b2ce4c7",
    "front": "**Def**: Close acquaintance with or knowledge of something.\n**Farsi**: آشنایی، صمیمیت",
    "back": "familiarity"
  },
  {
    "id": "5241f794-0784-4c6e-9e51-ef5d12acce79",
    "front": "**Def**: Easily set on fire.\n**Farsi**: قابل اشتعال",
    "back": "flammable"
  },
  {
    "id": "03e31d95-c58b-4c26-8c83-13cad9db6eee",
    "front": "**Def**: A hot, glowing body of burning gas.\n**Farsi**: شعله",
    "back": "flame"
  },
  {
    "id": "60f0173a-70bc-48f0-a62f-a064aa90d104",
    "front": "**Def**: Exaggerated or uncontrolled emotion or excitement.\n**Farsi**: جنون، هیجان مفرط",
    "back": "hysteria"
  },
  {
    "id": "ac445bfa-8f0c-4196-9144-46e1f72f2bd7",
    "front": "**Def**: A feeling of great happiness and triumph.\n**Farsi**: شادمانی، سرور",
    "back": "jubilation"
  },
  {
    "id": "c36bb46e-bed8-416d-b92b-22d27cc27272",
    "front": "**Def**: The state of not supporting or helping either side.\n**Farsi**: بی‌طرفی",
    "back": "neutrality"
  },
  {
    "id": "ec7df519-9019-41ba-9ed4-3c99b92a9d0d",
    "front": "**Def**: Conforming to a standard; typical.\n**Farsi**: عادی، نرمال",
    "back": "normal"
  },
  {
    "id": "bc1bd4e0-7eb0-4394-91e2-e424f695d2ca",
    "front": "**Def**: The state of being normal.\n**Farsi**: عادی بودن، وضعیت نرمال",
    "back": "normality"
  },
  {
    "id": "90f7c12e-2bb6-4cc1-835f-3afec46d4a2a",
    "front": "**Def**: The state of being famous or well known for some bad quality.\n**Farsi**: رسوایی، شهرت منفی",
    "back": "notoriety"
  },
  {
    "id": "d8878554-9c85-4c43-ae1e-b6167a595a38",
    "front": "**Def**: The state of being nude.\n**Farsi**: برهنگی",
    "back": "nudity"
  },
  {
    "id": "f3691f63-1075-492b-88b0-5d232b9950b5",
    "front": "**Def**: The quality, condition, or fact of being exact and accurate.\n**Farsi**: دقت",
    "back": "precision"
  },
  {
    "id": "539a4234-eaad-4046-be75-fd8d2826e4b8",
    "front": "**Def**: Corresponding in size or degree.\n**Farsi**: متناسب",
    "back": "proportionate"
  },
  {
    "id": "dea86db8-d541-4808-896f-81e7652b51cf",
    "front": "**Def**: The quality of being ruthless.\n**Farsi**: بی‌رحمی",
    "back": "ruthlessness"
  },
  {
    "id": "90e47482-7b69-4af6-86e7-bc3ea06adcd2",
    "front": "**Def**: Causing public outrage by a perceived offence against morality or law.\n**Farsi**: رسواکننده، مفتضح",
    "back": "scandalous"
  },
  {
    "id": "f3a2d532-2887-41d4-b911-b35f7f6dc134",
    "front": "**Def**: Inclined to conceal feelings and intentions.\n**Farsi**: رازدار، تودار",
    "back": "secretive"
  },
  {
    "id": "b8ef6d2d-bc17-484f-ba6f-131504cb6c54",
    "front": "**Def**: The action of keeping something secret.\n**Farsi**: رازداری، پنهان‌کاری",
    "back": "secrecy"
  },
  {
    "id": "1d8fe28f-9be9-4083-a61e-ab3c44fb2a4a",
    "front": "**Def**: Relating to or characteristic of a snob.\n**Farsi**: متکبر، خودبین",
    "back": "snobbish"
  },
  {
    "id": "f02b30b2-00d7-42a8-9347-fc19ca15c17b",
    "front": "**Def**: The quality of being a snob.\n**Farsi**: تکبر، خودبینی",
    "back": "snobbery"
  },
  {
    "id": "d13f254a-5e27-470f-8b64-19a7ae93f8bb",
    "front": "**Def**: Relating to or affecting the human spirit or soul.\n**Farsi**: معنوی، روحی",
    "back": "spiritual"
  },
  {
    "id": "c607e29f-2919-4204-8e9b-259199904ad1",
    "front": "**Def**: The nonphysical part of a person.\n**Farsi**: روح، روان",
    "back": "spirit"
  },
  {
    "id": "b5c34b6f-5897-48e5-aa33-9c4bba5ffc9b",
    "front": "**Def**: Prepared to obey others unquestioningly.\n**Farsi**: فرمانبردار، مطیع",
    "back": "subservient"
  },
  {
    "id": "73dbf3bb-7aca-4a0d-ab77-a0ee5a7edb8d",
    "front": "**Def**: The state of being subservient.\n**Farsi**: اطاعت محض، فرمانبرداری",
    "back": "subservience"
  },
  {
    "id": "8be1da3e-5233-4749-a68f-04de8efd0c0c",
    "front": "**Def**: The quality or state of being subtle.\n**Farsi**: ظرافت",
    "back": "subtlety"
  },
  {
    "id": "d563c906-13e3-47b2-b321-c504f48dbfd6",
    "front": "**Def**: The condition of being transparent.\n**Farsi**: شفافیت",
    "back": "transparency"
  },
  {
    "id": "c05827da-6c6f-495e-97be-6e028c24e183",
    "front": "**Def**: The quality of being trivial.\n**Farsi**: بی‌اهمیتی، چیز جزئی",
    "back": "triviality"
  },
  {
    "id": "a686a78e-e62c-47f7-8ac7-afbf9836b242",
    "front": "**Def**: Able to be seen.\n**Farsi**: مرئی، قابل رؤیت",
    "back": "visible"
  },
  {
    "id": "4922759d-a659-45d8-99f3-166d1a6ef2b7",
    "front": "**Def**: The state of being visible.\n**Farsi**: دید، قابلیت مشاهده",
    "back": "visibility"
  },
  {
    "id": "6982ff10-4353-442b-9104-24017ebc195d",
    "front": "**Def**: The quality of being wicked.\n**Farsi**: شرارت",
    "back": "wickedness"
  },
  {
    "id": "d76067a8-e001-4a92-a097-1706ba56df5a",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning achieve or complete successfully.\n**Farsi**: به انجام رساندن، محقق کردن",
    "back": "accomplish"
  },
  {
    "id": "cb3dee69-7bd0-4b4f-ac7e-058e58ef9e8e",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning something that has been achieved successfully.\n**Farsi**: دستاورد، موفقیت",
    "back": "accomplishment"
  },
  {
    "id": "093c023a-1288-48f4-955f-f13b545b83d0",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning buy or obtain.\n**Farsi**: به دست آوردن",
    "back": "acquire"
  },
  {
    "id": "c625b093-a591-4c7e-bf66-5089f761827a",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning distribute (resources or duties) for a particular purpose.\n**Farsi**: اختصاص دادن، سهم‌بندی کردن",
    "back": "allocate"
  },
  {
    "id": "ee78b362-e9a8-4e4d-8e3a-ab23d1e1d9ec",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the action or process of allocating.\n**Farsi**: تخصیص، سهم",
    "back": "allocation"
  },
  {
    "id": "e9b42432-cb73-43ac-a363-a25b03908678",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning produce (a list, book, or report) by assembling information.\n**Farsi**: گردآوری کردن، تدوین کردن",
    "back": "compile"
  },
  {
    "id": "76692389-a96d-4869-8623-ddfb341f2453",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the action or process of compiling.\n**Farsi**: مجموعه گردآوری شده",
    "back": "compilation"
  },
  {
    "id": "f844b47b-ffe7-4275-a6ff-3250b15dc9a2",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning meet (someone) face to face with hostile or argumentative intent.\n**Farsi**: مقابله کردن، روبرو شدن",
    "back": "confront"
  },
  {
    "id": "73b1fd52-fe34-4037-9303-4063c9311aed",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning a hostile or argumentative meeting or situation.\n**Farsi**: رویارویی، مقابله",
    "back": "confrontation"
  },
  {
    "id": "b56f801a-53f0-4cbf-82a7-65dec5d29145",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning give (something) in order to help achieve or provide something.\n**Farsi**: مشارکت کردن، کمک کردن",
    "back": "contribute"
  },
  {
    "id": "1cb478e6-07c9-4369-8c6b-ec18f0e7ca12",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning abandon (a person, cause, or country).\n**Farsi**: ترک کردن، رها کردن",
    "back": "desert (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "823ec7bd-ff9f-48d4-b5f8-2469d6f976ea",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the action of abandoning a person, cause, or military duty.\n**Farsi**: ترک خدمت، رهاسازی",
    "back": "desertion"
  },
  {
    "id": "93a9373e-4cbe-490f-a36f-fe6bb0baf946",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning keep (someone) in official custody.\n**Farsi**: بازداشت کردن، متوقف کردن",
    "back": "detain"
  },
  {
    "id": "b1b4cda2-e212-4910-8d60-fb31697e2ab2",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the action of detaining someone or the state of being detained.\n**Farsi**: بازداشت",
    "back": "detention"
  },
  {
    "id": "410fb046-a1f5-413e-85bc-abee18b3ac54",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning discover or identify the presence or existence of (something).\n**Farsi**: شناسایی کردن، کشف کردن",
    "back": "detect"
  },
  {
    "id": "12fe44cc-b801-4025-ae4e-39eff808ce5a",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the action or process of detecting something.\n**Farsi**: کشف",
    "back": "detection"
  },
  {
    "id": "a3ccfd29-8707-4f56-a05c-d0e04251ba97",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning pull or twist out of shape; give a misleading account of.\n**Farsi**: تحریف کردن، کج و معوج کردن",
    "back": "distort"
  },
  {
    "id": "464d55f4-b493-42c9-9fd2-a91878e5858e",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the action of distorting or the state of being distorted.\n**Farsi**: تحریف",
    "back": "distortion"
  },
  {
    "id": "7222e30f-3b68-4690-8eec-aef9ea51b098",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning cause (someone or something) to change course or turn from one direction to another.\n**Farsi**: منحرف کردن، تغییر مسیر دادن",
    "back": "divert"
  },
  {
    "id": "01efc5b5-87a3-43d0-af40-aaba1c494179",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the action of diverting or turning aside.\n**Farsi**: انحراف، سرگرمی",
    "back": "diversion"
  },
  {
    "id": "672c051f-2aa3-4cf9-855d-b5052e5c1679",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning begin (a course of action, especially one that is important or arduous).\n**Farsi**: سوار شدن (کشتی، هواپیما)، آغاز کردن",
    "back": "embark"
  },
  {
    "id": "a5ff499c-6637-43bf-a931-54c2758e2f2f",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the process of embarking.\n**Farsi**: سوار شدن",
    "back": "embarkation"
  },
  {
    "id": "b0ce416b-6638-424c-ac10-4619843f4b48",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning force (a unwelcome duty or tax) on someone.\n**Farsi**: تحمیل کردن، وضع کردن",
    "back": "impose"
  },
  {
    "id": "fa7e993a-a7ed-41b0-91a5-ec1b59404911",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the action of imposing a new rule or requirement.\n**Farsi**: تحمیل",
    "back": "imposition"
  },
  {
    "id": "d9ce4c15-c0a3-4f32-b06c-81bc1b571212",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning allow oneself to enjoy the pleasure of (a particular desire or activity).\n**Farsi**: افراط کردن، لذت بردن",
    "back": "indulge"
  },
  {
    "id": "8767cf1c-5959-49cf-a7bd-c668a6045792",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the action or fact of indulging.\n**Farsi**: عیاشی، لذت‌بری",
    "back": "indulgence"
  },
  {
    "id": "e02b2597-26f8-4432-9391-980b457cb0ed",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning make a photographic copy of (a document).\n**Farsi**: فتوکپی گرفتن",
    "back": "photocopy (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f2f2996d-c50e-442a-ae5b-a2e39b2601e6",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning a machine that makes photocopies.\n**Farsi**: دستگاه فتوکپی",
    "back": "photocopier"
  },
  {
    "id": "cb919e7c-5737-4594-9e96-00213690d73d",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning begin or continue a course of action.\n**Farsi**: ادامه دادن، پیش رفتن",
    "back": "proceed"
  },
  {
    "id": "f678923d-a568-4d9b-b2c4-8e050bc358c4",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning put forward (an idea or plan) for consideration.\n**Farsi**: پیشنهاد دادن",
    "back": "propose"
  },
  {
    "id": "07bb4ac5-a6b3-4aa4-99b6-e91ad62cbdf4",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning a plan or suggestion put forward for consideration.\n**Farsi**: پیشنهاد",
    "back": "proposal"
  },
  {
    "id": "56c7ffdf-a533-4032-bd09-f280c47b15fa",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning follow (someone or something) in order to catch or attain them.\n**Farsi**: تعقیب کردن، دنبال کردن",
    "back": "pursue"
  },
  {
    "id": "5c9b9758-7fe7-49b6-9a51-7c878b269d58",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the action of pursuing someone or something.\n**Farsi**: تعقیب",
    "back": "pursuit"
  },
  {
    "id": "f3c1c0c3-abc5-4d51-b9a3-5a54ab873e2e",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning say or do something to remove the doubts or fears of (someone).\n**Farsi**: اطمینان خاطر دادن، دلگرمی دادن",
    "back": "reassure"
  },
  {
    "id": "0feb6272-708c-4516-8c7d-9ee784de7e09",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the action of reassuring someone.\n**Farsi**: اطمینان خاطر",
    "back": "reassurance"
  },
  {
    "id": "4b2115aa-ebbc-469c-9594-e00f558363a0",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning use or put in the place of (another person or thing).\n**Farsi**: جایگزین کردن",
    "back": "substitute (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b57d2d91-d31b-4e1f-a318-195010c5480c",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning take away (a number or amount) from another.\n**Farsi**: کم کردن، تفریق کردن",
    "back": "subtract"
  },
  {
    "id": "e98256d0-e147-4daf-bd5e-81527bfab8b5",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the process of subtracting one number from another.\n**Farsi**: تفریق",
    "back": "subtraction"
  },
  {
    "id": "574581da-9a04-4275-b30a-994ae7f79d13",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning forcibly put an end to.\n**Farsi**: سرکوب کردن، خفه کردن",
    "back": "suppress"
  },
  {
    "id": "c4a84d4b-6a6e-4a6c-a365-c1f26b3f002c",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the action of suppressing something.\n**Farsi**: سرکوب",
    "back": "suppression"
  },
  {
    "id": "28463ecb-9da1-4b11-a1fe-5fe9409dbb0e",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the gathering together of something.\n**Farsi**: تراکم، انباشت",
    "back": "accumulation"
  },
  {
    "id": "39243a8d-f77a-42fd-8aba-9fd8394cec73",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning gather together or acquire an increasing number or quantity of.\n**Farsi**: انباشته کردن",
    "back": "accumulate"
  },
  {
    "id": "3b872c5f-2bd8-45fd-8031-0d47c380861a",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning increasing or increased in quantity, degree, or force by successive additions.\n**Farsi**: تراکمی، انباشتی",
    "back": "cumulative"
  },
  {
    "id": "f93ad183-7c7d-42fe-a029-292c727b07e4",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning a small alteration or movement made to achieve a desired fit, appearance, or result.\n**Farsi**: تنظیم، تعدیل",
    "back": "adjustment"
  },
  {
    "id": "9f2bd24e-1d86-4626-84b1-c8d89f944252",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning alter or move (something) slightly in order to achieve a desired result.\n**Farsi**: تنظیم کردن",
    "back": "adjust"
  },
  {
    "id": "3448ff22-61b1-4193-88ea-32b69d772e16",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning able to be adjusted.\n**Farsi**: قابل تنظیم",
    "back": "adjustable"
  },
  {
    "id": "0e4273d3-356d-4d56-8bd2-024c8d7e6242",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the recognition and enjoyment of the good qualities of someone or something.\n**Farsi**: قدردانی، درک",
    "back": "appreciation"
  },
  {
    "id": "805bbeac-344e-44e0-a46d-4c7a2c1ed219",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning recognize the full worth of.\n**Farsi**: قدردانی کردن، ارزش قائل شدن",
    "back": "appreciate"
  },
  {
    "id": "0931236b-f430-4bba-972b-1e68d8e2d7c5",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning feeling or showing gratitude or pleasure.\n**Farsi**: قدردان",
    "back": "appreciative"
  },
  {
    "id": "57d7baad-1ea3-45e9-b70e-66886c8d334d",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning a connection or cooperative link between people or organizations.\n**Farsi**: انجمن، ارتباط",
    "back": "association"
  },
  {
    "id": "f84fce32-4fbe-471d-adff-14f58c09c897",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning connect (someone or something) with something else.\n**Farsi**: همراه شدن، مرتبط کردن",
    "back": "associate"
  },
  {
    "id": "899f5afb-bd31-4d4b-a4bb-e5b780d60c09",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the quality of being authentic.\n**Farsi**: اصالت",
    "back": "authenticity"
  },
  {
    "id": "ac23fcf1-575e-4703-9f23-393ae57aa5eb",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning of undisputed origin; genuine.\n**Farsi**: معتبر، اصلی",
    "back": "authentic"
  },
  {
    "id": "576bb0d2-0291-4152-9b3c-1b448a735d8e",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning a curved part of a road, river, etc.\n**Farsi**: پیچ، خم",
    "back": "bend (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "6cbf3219-6254-45d9-8233-8e4722fbda00",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning curved or angled.\n**Farsi**: خمیده",
    "back": "bent (Adj)"
  },
  {
    "id": "30bf6dc3-8538-411e-913b-f43139a56907",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the act or process of comparing two or more people or things.\n**Farsi**: مقایسه",
    "back": "comparison"
  },
  {
    "id": "fd8d8b0b-4263-4b95-a769-fd65f650375e",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning estimate, measure, or note the similarity or dissimilarity between.\n**Farsi**: مقایسه کردن",
    "back": "compare"
  },
  {
    "id": "4175006a-932f-4ba9-a40e-2090b3af2899",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning able to be compared.\n**Farsi**: قابل مقایسه",
    "back": "comparable"
  },
  {
    "id": "fcc2cda7-8465-4996-a83b-8c571c568ca9",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the power to influence or direct people's behaviour or the course of events.\n**Farsi**: کنترل، تسلط",
    "back": "control (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "36d80c3a-ee01-4468-b025-7967969c2cae",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning determine the behaviour or supervise the running of.\n**Farsi**: کنترل کردن",
    "back": "control (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "4e1cfefd-0d52-4081-ab81-623f03b17b3b",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning determined by a particular person or factor.\n**Farsi**: کنترل شده",
    "back": "controlled"
  },
  {
    "id": "8429d4b1-dd95-40cd-8804-1345329a7bb9",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning a spoken or written account of a person, object, or event.\n**Farsi**: توصیف",
    "back": "description"
  },
  {
    "id": "675df223-402d-4443-91c4-ac5a6815c933",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning give a detailed account in words of (someone or something).\n**Farsi**: توصیف کردن",
    "back": "describe"
  },
  {
    "id": "a2049270-8f10-4fb4-9bcd-b4ee17b70162",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning serving to describe something.\n**Farsi**: توصیفی",
    "back": "descriptive"
  },
  {
    "id": "e61c8dba-76b3-429e-819e-c0786de9cf59",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning disturbance or problems which interrupt an event, activity, or process.\n**Farsi**: اختلال",
    "back": "disruption"
  },
  {
    "id": "1983aab2-2844-4c7a-829d-fb0d25dbfa9b",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning interrupt (an event, activity, or process) by causing a disturbance or problem.\n**Farsi**: مختل کردن",
    "back": "disrupt"
  },
  {
    "id": "6d8e3588-2be0-4485-bfd9-82551b235890",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning drain (someone) of their physical or mental resources.\n**Farsi**: خسته کردن، تمام کردن",
    "back": "exhaust"
  },
  {
    "id": "b0a75a44-d4b6-4fbf-a159-845871c04996",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the action of travelling in or through an unfamiliar area in order to learn about it.\n**Farsi**: اکتشاف",
    "back": "exploration"
  },
  {
    "id": "58bfdc27-6772-47f4-95c4-76b619e23379",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning travel through (an unfamiliar area) in order to learn about it.\n**Farsi**: کشف کردن، کاوش کردن",
    "back": "explore"
  },
  {
    "id": "2abc6ddf-6017-493b-b6e4-99e25985d765",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning relating to exploration or investigation.\n**Farsi**: اکتشافی",
    "back": "exploratory"
  },
  {
    "id": "34bacfb8-9648-433e-95bc-db3eefd0b555",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the state of being exposed to contact with something.\n**Farsi**: قرار گرفتن در معرض، افشا",
    "back": "exposure"
  },
  {
    "id": "337a35e7-e873-4c80-b060-d656f85af507",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning make (something) visible by uncovering it.\n**Farsi**: در معرض قرار دادن، افشا کردن",
    "back": "expose"
  },
  {
    "id": "fbc9861f-65c3-48e2-9da9-dbfc5e01b0e6",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning an act of kindness beyond what is due or usual.\n**Farsi**: لطف، مرحمت",
    "back": "favour (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "e6077cd8-499a-495d-a654-1b3495cbb7fb",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning feel or show approval or preference for.\n**Farsi**: طرفداری کردن، ترجیح دادن",
    "back": "favour (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f84405e3-e1b7-452a-8c5c-669c6809b04a",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning expressing approval; advantageous.\n**Farsi**: مطلوب، مساعد",
    "back": "favourable"
  },
  {
    "id": "07f20d6c-3629-410e-a210-142f7a991d15",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning a person who flirts.\n**Farsi**: لاس‌زن",
    "back": "flirt (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "593bc25f-699e-4edc-a135-78ad70db6c6b",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning behave amorously without serious intent.\n**Farsi**: لاس زدن، عشوه آمدن",
    "back": "flirt (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "dd16c933-dc1d-4abf-bb01-bb93ecf59b45",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning behaving in a way that suggests a playful sexual attraction.\n**Farsi**: لاس‌زنانه، عشوه گرانه",
    "back": "flirtatious"
  },
  {
    "id": "13706a34-33e7-4884-ba98-511d19e23cc0",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the action or process of forgiving or being forgiven.\n**Farsi**: بخشش، عفو",
    "back": "forgiveness"
  },
  {
    "id": "c5a10a56-7577-492e-ad7f-6092e9132e87",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning stop feeling angry or resentful towards (someone) for an offence, flaw, or mistake.\n**Farsi**: بخشیدن",
    "back": "forgive"
  },
  {
    "id": "488e7484-1a33-491d-841e-d9935802bc2c",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning able to be forgiven.\n**Farsi**: قابل بخشش",
    "back": "forgivable"
  },
  {
    "id": "364b7f13-20f4-4b07-9d90-02782c6cfee6",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the action or state of being included among others.\n**Farsi**: شمول، دربرگیری",
    "back": "inclusion"
  },
  {
    "id": "0f9891d4-7658-4921-9437-391389bb2898",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning comprise or contain as part of a whole.\n**Farsi**: شامل بودن",
    "back": "include"
  },
  {
    "id": "0007cd6f-6950-4db6-ace9-29d040e1affd",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning including all the services or items normally expected.\n**Farsi**: فراگیر، جامع",
    "back": "inclusive"
  },
  {
    "id": "9d7305d7-a342-49b4-b972-a5aad22153e6",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning a sign or piece of information that indicates something.\n**Farsi**: نشانه، دلالت",
    "back": "indication"
  },
  {
    "id": "fe9d6fe9-82c2-407c-9446-d365783cea04",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning point out; show.\n**Farsi**: نشان دادن، اشاره کردن",
    "back": "indicate"
  },
  {
    "id": "b4ae71ee-5495-48ff-a6e8-607213de09c0",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning serving as a sign or indication of something.\n**Farsi**: نشانگر، حاکی",
    "back": "indicative"
  },
  {
    "id": "ab2246ab-a8cf-410a-9ac9-48424160c3ef",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the action of intruding.\n**Farsi**: مزاحمت، تجاوز",
    "back": "intrusion"
  },
  {
    "id": "71fcaba2-c087-4cfc-8683-af57a4e7460e",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning causing disruption or annoyance through being unwelcome or uninvited.\n**Farsi**: مزاحم",
    "back": "intrusive"
  },
  {
    "id": "de7c3bf2-4f8d-4f18-b7f3-e21bd2b069eb",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the action of showing something to be right or reasonable.\n**Farsi**: توجیه",
    "back": "justification"
  },
  {
    "id": "54fac048-0572-4d0a-89c3-8403cf0eb997",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning show or prove to be right or reasonable.\n**Farsi**: توجیه کردن",
    "back": "justify"
  },
  {
    "id": "9212c189-4fe1-4b9b-8eab-a02a5d11aec2",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning able to be shown to be right or reasonable.\n**Farsi**: قابل توجیه",
    "back": "justifiable"
  },
  {
    "id": "dc28c6c0-1e6e-4a4d-83ae-f1d78226e866",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning a substance consisting of two or more substances mixed together.\n**Farsi**: مخلوط، ترکیب",
    "back": "mixture"
  },
  {
    "id": "a48dcebf-48b7-48e6-9a1a-7ac27c2d6f8b",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning combine or put together to form one substance or mass.\n**Farsi**: مخلوط کردن",
    "back": "mix"
  },
  {
    "id": "acc452d7-46af-4e89-920c-08975e5ea087",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning consisting of various ingredients or elements.\n**Farsi**: مخلوط، ترکیبی",
    "back": "mixed"
  },
  {
    "id": "204d41b5-f85b-48bd-92f1-39cfadcea9c2",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning resistance or dissent, expressed in action or argument.\n**Farsi**: مخالفت، اپوزیسیون",
    "back": "opposition"
  },
  {
    "id": "2149201f-21a5-447c-95c9-4d24f32b5d8c",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning have as belonging to one; own.\n**Farsi**: مالک بودن، داشتن",
    "back": "possess"
  },
  {
    "id": "f4fb9b72-0560-46b3-a25f-5c6f025952b6",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning demanding someone's total attention and love.\n**Farsi**: مالکیت‌طلب",
    "back": "possessive"
  },
  {
    "id": "7b71b1e3-debd-486b-b8e2-2213da8aefd3",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning action or speech that makes someone angry.\n**Farsi**: تحریک",
    "back": "provocation"
  },
  {
    "id": "effa5f31-94b1-4b10-8539-40e0b3069de9",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning stimulate or incite (someone) to do or feel something.\n**Farsi**: تحریک کردن",
    "back": "provoke"
  },
  {
    "id": "98b6141b-a2c3-42fc-a1b9-9487a306d37b",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the process of making something pure.\n**Farsi**: تصفیه",
    "back": "purification"
  },
  {
    "id": "bd9d2d5c-d24d-45a0-a2d4-9504bdd58040",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning remove contaminants from.\n**Farsi**: تصفیه کردن، پاک کردن",
    "back": "purify"
  },
  {
    "id": "f1d256cc-31d4-4852-924f-c7097197039e",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning not mixed or adulterated with any other substance or material.\n**Farsi**: خالص، ناب",
    "back": "pure"
  },
  {
    "id": "82d5e1fc-b810-49d6-86b4-1acd46a11962",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning a game, toy, or problem designed to test ingenuity or knowledge.\n**Farsi**: معما، چیستان",
    "back": "puzzle (N)"
  },
  {
    "id": "5deb3304-71b4-40b9-897a-8d335c1b5edf",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning cause (someone) to feel confused because something is difficult to understand.\n**Farsi**: گیج کردن، به معما تبدیل شدن",
    "back": "puzzle (V)"
  },
  {
    "id": "fe02b95f-9a2f-4ace-96d5-dc12697d3da6",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning feeling or showing confusion.\n**Farsi**: گیج، متحیر",
    "back": "puzzled"
  },
  {
    "id": "ff52304c-c5c2-4303-adab-67c4ced595a5",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the amount or number of a material or abstract thing.\n**Farsi**: مقدار، کمیت",
    "back": "quantity"
  },
  {
    "id": "36a5bec3-27d7-4367-a4f7-ce37349ac2e9",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning able to be quantified.\n**Farsi**: قابل اندازه‌گیری، قابل کمیت سنجی",
    "back": "quantifiable"
  },
  {
    "id": "299894f8-ee6b-470a-916b-0818db30e402",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the action or process of reinforcing or strengthening.\n**Farsi**: تقویت، استحکام",
    "back": "reinforcement"
  },
  {
    "id": "e9371ac9-4516-4395-94d3-5b0537f7a587",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning strengthen or support (an object or substance), especially with additional material.\n**Farsi**: تقویت کردن",
    "back": "reinforce"
  },
  {
    "id": "488ad48d-f9d5-4e1a-bb66-8dd0a2739f58",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning a story told about a past event remembered by the narrator.\n**Farsi**: خاطره‌گویی، یادبود",
    "back": "reminiscence"
  },
  {
    "id": "92285ac3-a608-4ca0-b8e6-da485ed4dee8",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning indulge in enjoyable recollection of past events.\n**Farsi**: خاطره‌بازی کردن",
    "back": "reminisce"
  },
  {
    "id": "45688b8d-acbf-4ace-b7bd-c4d1b11f491e",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning tending to remind one of something.\n**Farsi**: تداعی‌کننده، یادآور",
    "back": "reminiscent"
  },
  {
    "id": "f10b74cb-2475-47ab-a391-f8a817005433",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the action of returning a military attack or counter-attack.\n**Farsi**: تلافی، مقابله به مثل",
    "back": "retaliation"
  },
  {
    "id": "54788ba1-e93b-4ea3-a525-e6a7a16752c8",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning characterized by a desire for revenge.\n**Farsi**: تلافی‌جویانه",
    "back": "retaliatory"
  },
  {
    "id": "35c15931-f021-4bec-8ac1-dc0125ae4ba1",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the action of stimulating someone or something.\n**Farsi**: تحریک، انگیزش",
    "back": "stimulation"
  },
  {
    "id": "58a97c88-06a8-49c5-aea2-644622f2918a",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning encourage interest or activity in (a person or animal).\n**Farsi**: تحریک کردن، ترغیب کردن",
    "back": "stimulate"
  },
  {
    "id": "86af65b8-c8b4-4691-ba3a-c10413ca29eb",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning encouraging or full of new ideas.\n**Farsi**: محرک، هیجان‌انگیز",
    "back": "stimulating"
  },
  {
    "id": "1a77c1a2-9d54-4c78-a082-afebc1b14612",
    "front": "**Def**: Noun meaning the use of symbols to represent ideas or qualities.\n**Farsi**: نمادگرایی",
    "back": "symbolism"
  },
  {
    "id": "f61f8e0f-473d-4b0f-a5d2-05b386662fc9",
    "front": "**Def**: Verb meaning be a symbol of (something).\n**Farsi**: نماد چیزی بودن",
    "back": "symbolize"
  },
  {
    "id": "a5092bc7-a4e0-4739-87b0-e97e1d686169",
    "front": "**Def**: Adjective meaning serving as a symbol.\n**Farsi**: نمادین",
    "back": "symbolic"
  },
  {
    "id": "f004aeee-96d3-428a-b522-e464f5d90f1e",
    "front": "**Def**: To deal with a difficult or unpleasant situation.\n**Farsi**: با (مشکلی) روبرو شدن، پذیرفتن",
    "back": "face up to"
  },
  {
    "id": "d127c26d-7ddd-451c-a6b4-5894ac9015ae",
    "front": "**Def**: To happen or emerge (usually used for problems or opportunities).\n**Farsi**: پیش آمدن، مطرح شدن (مشکل، ایده)",
    "back": "arise/come up"
  },
  {
    "id": "2b850b70-95e3-40bd-b479-994c470ae74f",
    "front": "**Def**: To make a bad situation or problem worse.\n**Farsi**: بدتر کردن، وخیم‌تر کردن",
    "back": "exacerbate"
  },
  {
    "id": "647612c0-f4c1-406b-a73a-841c51449fd4",
    "front": "**Def**: Dealing with a difficult problem or situation directly.\n**Farsi**: مقابله کردن با (مشکل)، مواجه شدن",
    "back": "confronting (a problem)"
  },
  {
    "id": "45e1e798-a846-4b9a-8803-ac6aed33d0c0",
    "front": "**Def**: Making a determined effort to deal with a problem or difficult task.\n**Farsi**: رسیدگی کردن، اقدام کردن برای حل (مشکل)",
    "back": "tackling (a problem)"
  },
  {
    "id": "8de8af27-02ee-4fdc-b9da-cc930cbfa5f7",
    "front": "**Def**: Respect and admiration, typically for a person.\n**Farsi**: احترام، منزلت",
    "back": "esteem"
  },
  {
    "id": "5a215dad-ee90-46b9-aa1c-2b1f40c88aca",
    "front": "**Def**: To make someone feel sad or depressed.\n**Farsi**: افسرده کردن، دلگیر کردن",
    "back": "get her down"
  },
  {
    "id": "b03c7523-fd2b-4da8-972a-dc45ee9cdafa",
    "front": "**Def**: Able to express ideas and feelings clearly in speech or writing.\n**Farsi**: فصیح، شیوا، به خوبی بیان کردن",
    "back": "articulate"
  },
  {
    "id": "002bd435-dfab-4dcf-a4d1-6f858460937a",
    "front": "**Def**: Without considering; despite everything.\n**Farsi**: صرف نظر از، علی‌رغم",
    "back": "regardless"
  },
  {
    "id": "1bed0983-ebd2-4e1d-b3f8-86bae220892c",
    "front": "**Def**: To direct something (like energy or money) towards a particular purpose.\n**Farsi**: هدایت کردن، مسیر دادن",
    "back": "channel"
  },
  {
    "id": "396ecb02-8844-4504-977b-3e8b6552044c",
    "front": "**Def**: Weakened or damaged, often in relation to confidence or pride.\n**Farsi**: تضعیف شده، خدشه‌دار شده",
    "back": "dented (confidence)"
  },
  {
    "id": "8a6a6ee7-ce44-4070-b82e-5e54432428ea",
    "front": "**Def**: To deal with a difficult situation calmly and easily.\n**Farsi**: به راحتی کنار آمدن، خونسردی خود را حفظ کردن",
    "back": "take something in one's stride"
  },
  {
    "id": "ac6523ed-964e-4946-84f3-0177cae48fd4",
    "front": "**Def**: A particular way of regarding something; point of view.\n**Farsi**: دیدگاه، منظر",
    "back": "perspective"
  },
  {
    "id": "7221b938-347c-4aba-adc9-2bb335fb582d",
    "front": "**Def**: Not moving; peaceful or relaxed.\n**Farsi**: در حال استراحت، آرام",
    "back": "at rest"
  },
  {
    "id": "2a830dc4-572a-457f-b4ec-6a60ac19f03e",
    "front": "**Def**: Prefixes meaning extremely or beyond.\n**Farsi**: فرا-، خیلی زیاد",
    "back": "extra-/ultra-"
  },
  {
    "id": "649e2413-4967-4739-8db9-a1c3f77c4896",
    "front": "**Def**: The action or process of causing so much damage that something no longer exists or cannot be repaired.\n**Farsi**: تخریب، ویرانی",
    "back": "destruction"
  },
  {
    "id": "a584086e-b6e3-4a9b-8a96-484a6e1f1c47",
    "front": "**Def**: The action of maintaining something in its original or existing state.\n**Farsi**: حفظ، نگهداری",
    "back": "preservation"
  },
  {
    "id": "76dec86c-261e-4c7d-a3d5-79cb0a24eccb",
    "front": "**Def**: Completely broken or destroyed.\n**Farsi**: ویران، مخروبه",
    "back": "in ruins"
  },
  {
    "id": "e88519ef-b5ef-4294-b908-5ba4c68fb553",
    "front": "**Def**: In the past; before the present time.\n**Farsi**: قبلاً، در گذشته",
    "back": "formerly/previously"
  },
  {
    "id": "1f554f4a-e9a7-4e5a-b09f-45ecf26cbd09",
    "front": "**Def**: To restore (something old, especially a building) to a good state of repair.\n**Farsi**: بازسازی کردن، مرمت کردن",
    "back": "renovate"
  },
  {
    "id": "e6512e5b-ba5c-4b4f-9236-2da2b8d0043b",
    "front": "**Def**: In a state of decay; badly neglected and worn out.\n**Farsi**: فرسوده، مخروبه، در حال ویرانی",
    "back": "run-down/dilapidated/ramshackle"
  },
  {
    "id": "652b4df3-84a7-49bd-a9f9-57e37ba743c7",
    "front": "**Def**: The state of falling to pieces or being badly maintained.\n**Farsi**: پوسیدگی، خرابی",
    "back": "decay/disrepair"
  },
  {
    "id": "c988cc68-c9d8-4a2d-9407-699d4e3ee3cd",
    "front": "**Def**: To maintain (something) in its original or existing state.\n**Farsi**: حفظ کردن، نگه‌داشتن",
    "back": "preserve"
  },
  {
    "id": "d2e71c0d-c38b-42d7-ab28-877fca57e471",
    "front": "**Def**: A mark, object, or sign showing the existence or path of something.\n**Farsi**: اثر، نشانه",
    "back": "trace"
  },
  {
    "id": "0c814e7e-1581-46d6-b28a-397a557f51e2",
    "front": "**Def**: In excellent, brand-new condition.\n**Farsi**: نو، کاملاً سالم، دست نخورده",
    "back": "mint/perfect (condition)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f74804d1-eabb-4a58-9749-6119c1bb2b2a",
    "front": "**Def**: The latest and most advanced stage in development.\n**Farsi**: لبه تکنولوژی، بسیار پیشرفته",
    "back": "cutting edge"
  },
  {
    "id": "41c25f4f-f552-45ba-90a5-a442b22ad1d2",
    "front": "**Def**: A very great and complete victory.\n**Farsi**: پیروزی قاطع و بزرگ",
    "back": "a resounding victory"
  },
  {
    "id": "c1421190-c3c3-480b-bd74-618fd18a662d",
    "front": "**Def**: To fail unexpectedly or badly.\n**Farsi**: با شکست مواجه شدن، ناکام ماندن",
    "back": "come unstuck"
  },
  {
    "id": "f2fbec00-413c-4afa-900a-c10f0b75a5a7",
    "front": "**Def**: To achieve all the success or ability that you are capable of.\n**Farsi**: به پتانسیل خود رسیدن، استعداد خود را شکوفا کردن",
    "back": "fulfil your potential"
  },
  {
    "id": "53872508-3502-4716-8339-0f231516d106",
    "front": "**Def**: To try to make a success of something, often a business or relationship.\n**Farsi**: موفق شدن در یک کار",
    "back": "make a go of it"
  },
  {
    "id": "2357af93-2b55-40f7-9fce-6f5baa2f64ab",
    "front": "**Def**: To be completely unsuccessful; a failure (informal).\n**Farsi**: شکست خوردن، ناموفق بودن",
    "back": "flop"
  },
  {
    "id": "991e3faa-c68f-41bc-aa23-6a2b127e2722",
    "front": "**Def**: Too old or exhausted to be effective or useful (informal).\n**Farsi**: از کار افتاده، پیرتر از آنکه مؤثر باشد",
    "back": "past it"
  },
  {
    "id": "10e997aa-bdf0-48b6-aaac-858261aaf4f2",
    "front": "**Def**: Facing severe difficulties or opposition.\n**Farsi**: با مشکلات جدی روبرو بودن",
    "back": "up against it"
  },
  {
    "id": "f86bc26c-3cca-46f8-b4c6-0983c7fc1915",
    "front": "**Def**: A complete and total failure.\n**Farsi**: فاجعه تمام عیار، شکست مطلق",
    "back": "unmitigated disaster"
  },
  {
    "id": "b68d907d-efbe-423b-a48a-565c4cebe177",
    "front": "**Def**: In a situation that is too difficult for one to handle.\n**Farsi**: در موقعیتی که از پسش برنمی‌آید، ورای توان",
    "back": "way out of one's depth"
  },
  {
    "id": "a290987e-bc01-4d99-a374-8343d1161207",
    "front": "**Def**: At the latest possible moment.\n**Farsi**: در لحظه آخر",
    "back": "at the last minute"
  },
  {
    "id": "4dce9e89-e44d-488a-b428-12cb5dc232b0",
    "front": "**Def**: Thinking about the past now, with the knowledge you have today.\n**Farsi**: با نگاه به گذشته، با توجه به گذشته",
    "back": "in retrospect/with hindsight"
  },
  {
    "id": "3b3fe806-e4f0-440a-b07f-7dc0be369e6c",
    "front": "**Def**: Before I was involved or born.\n**Farsi**: قبل از زمان من، پیش از اینکه من باشم",
    "back": "before my time"
  },
  {
    "id": "e87bd7f2-e3cf-4be7-98aa-bd4f8b7a748f",
    "front": "**Def**: A period of time between two events or points.\n**Farsi**: فاصله، وقفه زمانی",
    "back": "an interval"
  },
  {
    "id": "9403ae8d-4d2d-42e1-b008-753ac7771d58",
    "front": "**Def**: A distinct period in a process of change or development.\n**Farsi**: مرحله، فاز",
    "back": "phase/stage"
  },
  {
    "id": "fa1fdc0d-cba1-4705-bdaf-359d76c5e866",
    "front": "**Def**: To extend the duration of (often reluctantly).\n**Farsi**: طولانی کردن، امتداد دادن",
    "back": "prolong"
  },
  {
    "id": "8bcf118b-3470-4e42-8464-f45f84ee4f5c",
    "front": "**Def**: Time that has finished or expired.\n**Farsi**: سپری شده، گذشته",
    "back": "elapsed/passed/gone by (time)"
  },
  {
    "id": "21ad432a-e458-4d34-8c76-21cdc3900ee2",
    "front": "**Def**: A man (British/American informal).\n**Farsi**: مرد، رفیق (خودمانی)",
    "back": "bloke/guy"
  },
  {
    "id": "f6f378d5-a527-4f17-9354-26270a3cadcb",
    "front": "**Def**: Stolen (informal).\n**Farsi**: دزدیدن، کش رفتن",
    "back": "nicked/pinched"
  },
  {
    "id": "becc2168-bea5-4b72-8dc7-4a23be1fa9d1",
    "front": "**Def**: Complaining in an annoying way (informal).\n**Farsi**: غر زدن، نالیدن",
    "back": "moaning"
  },
  {
    "id": "396cc85d-29dc-4716-85e3-c587308d8175",
    "front": "**Def**: Extremely unpleasant or offensive.\n**Farsi**: زننده، چندش‌آور، نفرت‌انگیز",
    "back": "vile/disgusting"
  },
  {
    "id": "9925da38-ba5d-43b4-a8b9-73412d7e04eb",
    "front": "**Def**: Unwilling to spend money.\n**Farsi**: خسیس، ممسک",
    "back": "tight-fisted/stingy"
  },
  {
    "id": "6256621c-1134-4a87-97f6-008d7a4cd65c",
    "front": "**Def**: One pound sterling (British slang).\n**Farsi**: پوند (اصطلاح عامیانه بریتانیایی)",
    "back": "quid"
  },
  {
    "id": "8b2f15b3-b640-414b-9e36-2a423b6a8156",
    "front": "**Def**: Very poor or bad.\n**Farsi**: افتضاح، مزخرف",
    "back": "lousy"
  },
  {
    "id": "6b2e0383-b269-4767-bc8c-7653b3693498",
    "front": "**Def**: Toilet (British informal).\n**Farsi**: دستشویی (توالت)",
    "back": "loo"
  },
  {
    "id": "ad706843-5512-4936-9af6-8f1d5bbf8da1",
    "front": "**Def**: An annoying person or thing.\n**Farsi**: آدم یا چیز آزاردهنده",
    "back": "pain (in the neck)"
  },
  {
    "id": "77e9291a-7df9-439f-b1a3-58fbbbf17e87",
    "front": "**Def**: A tedious or annoying activity or situation (informal).\n**Farsi**: خسته‌کننده، کسالت‌آور",
    "back": "drag"
  },
  {
    "id": "e127ba75-1907-4325-b224-cb58ced0fc73",
    "front": "**Def**: A fraud or something that is ridiculously overpriced (informal).\n**Farsi**: کلاهبرداری، گران‌فروشی",
    "back": "rip-off"
  },
  {
    "id": "3659263d-85df-4cd7-b771-6588eae89189",
    "front": "**Def**: Impudence or audacity (informal).\n**Farsi**: جسارت، پررویی",
    "back": "cheek/nerve"
  },
  {
    "id": "b122dd52-e12d-4811-a6e9-52ffc8616a74",
    "front": "**Def**: An informal social gathering.\n**Farsi**: دورهمی، مهمانی خودمانی",
    "back": "get-together"
  },
  {
    "id": "6c2191c5-0325-4fc8-815a-2bde0c16b4f9",
    "front": "**Def**: Thank you (informal/slang).\n**Farsi**: ممنون، مرسی (عامیانه)",
    "back": "Cheers = Ta"
  },
  {
    "id": "73a04bdd-2ec8-4d9f-a6ca-38db3688332b",
    "front": "**Def**: A loud, unpleasant, and prolonged noise.\n**Farsi**: سر و صدای زیاد و آزاردهنده",
    "back": "din = racket"
  },
  {
    "id": "0852341f-d1b8-4f71-a440-18ffc21c97ef",
    "front": "**Def**: Severe criticism or opposition.\n**Farsi**: انتقاد شدید، ایراد",
    "back": "stick = flak"
  },
  {
    "id": "aa5e8122-48ce-4086-a7b6-466a09b31c1d",
    "front": "**Def**: Very hungry (hyperbole).\n**Farsi**: خیلی گرسنه (دارم ضعف می‌کنم)",
    "back": "starving = dying for something to eat"
  },
  {
    "id": "e1c43fee-8ffb-48ac-9570-f1c714e859f7",
    "front": "**Def**: Defeated heavily in a game or competition (informal).\n**Farsi**: شکست سخت خوردن، خرد شدن",
    "back": "thrashed = hammered"
  },
  {
    "id": "6ce880a7-1442-41a2-8976-4eeeb745f16b",
    "front": "**Def**: Having no money (informal).\n**Farsi**: بی‌پول، ورشکسته",
    "back": "broke"
  },
  {
    "id": "fab240b0-5ae8-4d2d-b326-6f9167e7b4f6",
    "front": "**Def**: A nap or a short sleep (slang).\n**Farsi**: خواب کوتاه، چرت",
    "back": "kip"
  },
  {
    "id": "5569761b-d6f5-4062-94de-40ab6cb53b9d",
    "front": "**Def**: A mild illness or virus (informal).\n**Farsi**: مریضی یا ویروس خفیف",
    "back": "bug"
  },
  {
    "id": "7d7f1000-3c48-40e9-8923-d50a00f971b5",
    "front": "**Def**: Silly or foolish (informal).\n**Farsi**: احمقانه، دیوانه",
    "back": "daft"
  },
  {
    "id": "1c1d353d-46d1-408d-b05e-9411b9bb8b21",
    "front": "**Def**: To operate perfectly or be extremely successful (simile).\n**Farsi**: عالی کار کردن، بی‌نقص بودن",
    "back": "work like a dream"
  },
  {
    "id": "319a3969-3b00-44f4-a952-4883bd21ad84",
    "front": "**Def**: Extremely pale, usually due to fear or sickness (simile).\n**Farsi**: مثل گچ سفید شدن (از ترس یا بیماری)",
    "back": "white as a sheet"
  },
  {
    "id": "eeb238fc-8a57-4942-85e2-b23d22e0f3f3",
    "front": "**Def**: Dishonest, unreliable, or slightly dangerous (informal).\n**Farsi**: مشکوک، قلابی، غیرقابل اعتماد",
    "back": "dodgy"
  },
  {
    "id": "cdb9ff55-577e-41aa-87de-459a1d820f37",
    "front": "**Def**: Elegant, stylish, or upper-class (informal).\n**Farsi**: شیک، باکلاس، اعیانی",
    "back": "posh"
  },
  {
    "id": "3a0c6763-81c2-42be-936b-655d513cbce1",
    "front": "**Def**: Excessively interested in other people's affairs (informal).\n**Farsi**: فضول",
    "back": "nosy"
  },
  {
    "id": "7f654e28-66d6-4300-9281-b328aeaeb923",
    "front": "**Def**: Worrying about this situation is futile or pointless.\n**Farsi**: فایده‌ای ندارد که نگرانش باشی",
    "back": "It's no good/use worrying about it"
  },
  {
    "id": "f44e0fd2-365a-42c8-b06f-a30cf27ffd78",
    "front": "**Def**: Heard but immediately forgotten.\n**Farsi**: از یک گوش شنیده و از دیگری بیرون کردن (فراموش کردن)",
    "back": "in one ear and out the other"
  },
  {
    "id": "a01e72b5-6fea-44fe-ad63-86a2de804ade",
    "front": "**Def**: Need or would benefit from (informal).\n**Farsi**: نیاز داشتن به، بدش نیامدن از",
    "back": "could do with"
  },
  {
    "id": "7d1fc2f3-8731-4ebe-91b5-803bede9dade",
    "front": "**Def**: I was unable to remember anything or think clearly.\n**Farsi**: مغزم کاملاً خالی شد، چیزی یادم نیامد",
    "back": "My mind went a complete blank"
  },
  {
    "id": "7f1c4adc-94ad-489f-8266-6ad3abca406b",
    "front": "**Def**: Slightly unwell or ill (euphemism).\n**Farsi**: کمی ناخوش، سرماخورده",
    "back": "under the weather"
  },
  {
    "id": "4cc60f9e-0bd3-4d4e-ac01-0f9c8aa4a9e5",
    "front": "**Def**: Expressions used to convey disbelief or surprise.\n**Farsi**: شوخی می‌کنی، جدی نمی‌گویی؟",
    "back": "'re joking/'re kidding/'can't be serious"
  },
  {
    "id": "0b6147e7-5b8b-47b7-98af-e3197df4458c",
    "front": "**Def**: I have no idea; I don't know the answer either.\n**Farsi**: حدس من به اندازه مال تو خوب است (یعنی من هم نمی‌دانم)",
    "back": "is as good as mine"
  },
  {
    "id": "6cafdd87-2f88-49a1-abd9-8c06dbeb6599",
    "front": "**Def**: A result that is certain to happen; inevitable.\n**Farsi**: نتیجه از پیش معلوم، حتمی",
    "back": "foregone conclusion"
  },
  {
    "id": "f35b3309-c780-4a9a-974b-e06a4b105ff5",
    "front": "**Def**: A private imaginary world; someone who is independent and self-contained.\n**Farsi**: در عالم خود بودن، دنیای مخصوص خود را داشتن",
    "back": "a world of her own"
  },
  {
    "id": "0f1bbb19-3fd5-4ede-b89e-6201cdd337df",
    "front": "**Def**: To remain sensible and realistic.\n**Farsi**: واقع‌بین بودن، مغرور نشدن",
    "back": "keep his feet on the ground"
  },
  {
    "id": "ee4cadfc-24b0-4ea6-918b-56783f0bd866",
    "front": "**Def**: So wonderful or positive that it seems unlikely to be real.\n**Farsi**: آنقدر خوب که واقعی به نظر نمی‌رسد",
    "back": "good to be true"
  },
  {
    "id": "f0bc51a0-461d-4ce6-9d4c-498635a3b5be",
    "front": "**Def**: Relaxing and enjoying oneself freely and uninhibitedly.\n**Farsi**: آزاد بودن، خوش گذراندن",
    "back": "letting her hair down"
  },
  {
    "id": "fc4b75c8-37ef-4abf-a919-2d39ee5b04a1",
    "front": "**Def**: Used to ask a question politely, especially when you are unsure if the person knows the answer.\n**Farsi**: اتفاقاً، احیاناً (برای سؤالات مودبانه)",
    "back": "by any chance/happen to know"
  },
  {
    "id": "d0560d2c-6b94-4506-b8e5-24153cabec79",
    "front": "**Def**: A polite preface to an intrusive or personal question.\n**Farsi**: اگر ناراحت نمی‌شوی (که می‌پرسم)",
    "back": "if you don't mind me/my asking"
  },
  {
    "id": "5e84abc8-040b-418d-9c6c-746deade555a",
    "front": "**Def**: Just as (violent as); equally.\n**Farsi**: به همان اندازه، کاملاً",
    "back": "every bit as (violent as)"
  },
  {
    "id": "2f48cc74-0ee6-47bd-bfe8-d1262fe0db9d",
    "front": "**Def**: The chaotic movement of a large crowd.\n**Farsi**: فشار و هل دادن (در جمعیت)",
    "back": "push and shove"
  },
  {
    "id": "4086f1fb-c930-48b5-ae09-8a2c59d9966c",
    "front": "**Def**: Bored, annoyed, or exasperated by something.\n**Farsi**: خسته و عاصی، به ستوه آمده",
    "back": "sick and tired"
  },
  {
    "id": "02457a20-c0b2-4cf7-a910-c016e7e8dfde",
    "front": "**Def**: Noticeably happy and optimistic.\n**Farsi**: شاد و سرزنده",
    "back": "cheerful (bright and)"
  },
  {
    "id": "f63b00e9-e9ab-4e34-9439-8d42fa29a143",
    "front": "**Def**: A process of finding the best way or solution by trying different methods and making mistakes.\n**Farsi**: آزمون و خطا",
    "back": "error (trial and)"
  },
  {
    "id": "9df5fafa-781a-40af-af87-00548dbf8676",
    "front": "**Def**: Completely deaf (simile).\n**Farsi**: کاملاً کر",
    "back": "deaf as a post"
  },
  {
    "id": "5ae6fe6a-4718-4081-a197-3b8d32d09185",
    "front": "**Def**: Completely blind or having very poor eyesight (simile).\n**Farsi**: کور کورانه",
    "back": "blind as a bat"
  },
  {
    "id": "51e9c882-f7aa-42fa-9ccf-a1e25365a907",
    "front": "**Def**: Extremely thin (simile).\n**Farsi**: بسیار لاغر",
    "back": "thin as a rake"
  },
  {
    "id": "a91dd77c-edad-4742-b92e-de2d403fe472",
    "front": "**Def**: Having a red face, usually due to embarrassment or effort (simile).\n**Farsi**: قرمز شدن صورت (از خجالت)",
    "back": "red as a beetroot"
  },
  {
    "id": "4e046698-ca1f-4b76-8274-d04d72d6d63c",
    "front": "**Def**: To confess or admit to doing something wrong (informal).\n**Farsi**: اعتراف کردن",
    "back": "own up to"
  },
  {
    "id": "949bf709-86aa-4cfd-931d-cfb9bf294411",
    "front": "**Def**: To compensate for a loss or mistake.\n**Farsi**: جبران کردن",
    "back": "make up for"
  },
  {
    "id": "5d3e11b8-1890-4ada-a8a1-05be3b987bd2",
    "front": "**Def**: To persuade someone not to do something.\n**Farsi**: کسی را متقاعد کردن به انجام ندادن کاری",
    "back": "talk me out of"
  },
  {
    "id": "47101c6a-7696-441d-ab32-0d766e061100",
    "front": "**Def**: To abolish or dispose of something.\n**Farsi**: حذف کردن، لغو کردن",
    "back": "do away with"
  },
  {
    "id": "dc7e0d88-1dc4-4a2a-bb28-277896a572d2",
    "front": "**Def**: Deceived or tricked (passive).\n**Farsi**: فریب خورده، گول خورده",
    "back": "taken in"
  },
  {
    "id": "b77889fc-5c0f-4a3a-93f2-11124c606896",
    "front": "**Def**: To persuade someone to do something.\n**Farsi**: کسی را متقاعد کردن به انجام کاری",
    "back": "talk him into"
  },
  {
    "id": "991fb4e0-9eca-4bef-8226-f4de9997768d",
    "front": "**Def**: To dismantle or separate into component parts.\n**Farsi**: قطعه قطعه کردن، اوراق کردن",
    "back": "take to pieces/apart"
  },
  {
    "id": "a585528c-e1fb-4034-8c5d-cd85e6b63cdf",
    "front": "**Def**: Reconciled after a quarrel (informal).\n**Farsi**: آشتی کردن، صلح کردن",
    "back": "made up"
  },
  {
    "id": "42189b83-92b6-4c31-a3f9-46fc6cebada6",
    "front": "**Def**: To manage to survive or accomplish something with difficulty or limited means.\n**Farsi**: گذران زندگی کردن، سر کردن",
    "back": "get by"
  },
  {
    "id": "0f81a45d-6544-43d6-b9b0-dc11b7d0c4e9",
    "front": "**Def**: Appeared or occurred unexpectedly.\n**Farsi**: ناگهان ظاهر شدن، پیش آمدن",
    "back": "cropped up"
  },
  {
    "id": "703b48d7-c135-4db6-a03a-e0577822e88f",
    "front": "**Def**: Not experiencing something good or enjoyable.\n**Farsi**: فرصت را از دست دادن، محروم شدن از",
    "back": "missing out on"
  },
  {
    "id": "a78a816f-cb4a-49d9-9f7b-530c9408eb57",
    "front": "**Def**: To meet someone by chance.\n**Farsi**: برخورد کردن با، تصادفی دیدن",
    "back": "bump into"
  },
  {
    "id": "f69bd0dc-0236-487e-a25b-6c6bbc1b9466",
    "front": "**Def**: Arrived or appeared (often unexpectedly or late).\n**Farsi**: حاضر شدن، سر و کله‌اش پیدا شدن",
    "back": "turned up/showed up"
  },
  {
    "id": "14be3e46-c81c-41ad-9862-66e3c8254e54",
    "front": "**Def**: To get rid of an illness, problem, or feeling.\n**Farsi**: خلاص شدن از شر، رفع کردن",
    "back": "shake off"
  },
  {
    "id": "256fe72d-98d2-4e4b-93ef-220594c21a01",
    "front": "**Def**: Was fully understood (usually after a delay).\n**Farsi**: جا افتادن، درک شدن",
    "back": "sank in"
  },
  {
    "id": "f25575a8-48d2-4b97-bfd9-6ec3f807ac6f",
    "front": "**Def**: Become ill with (especially an infectious disease).\n**Farsi**: مریض شدن به، مبتلا شدن به",
    "back": "gone down with"
  },
  {
    "id": "b8c5c000-1658-4a10-b732-9aa96c1fea8b",
    "front": "**Def**: Generally speaking; considering everything.\n**Farsi**: در کل، به طور کلی",
    "back": "on the whole/by and large"
  },
  {
    "id": "aec2f2e2-5aff-451f-8c59-632f3911890a",
    "front": "**Def**: Speaking in a general way; summarizing the main points.\n**Farsi**: به طور کلی، در حالت عمومی",
    "back": "broadly speaking"
  },
  {
    "id": "424f35fa-fc21-4609-8668-c2661ea69d94",
    "front": "**Def**: Nevertheless; despite what has been said.\n**Farsi**: با این حال، به هر حال",
    "back": "all the same"
  },
  {
    "id": "b28778bc-a138-44ff-a5a9-a091a904360e",
    "front": "**Def**: Approximately; roughly.\n**Farsi**: تقریباً، حدوداً",
    "back": "somewhere in the region (of)"
  },
  {
    "id": "b740db8b-86fb-4e58-b2c5-4f27462ed7fa",
    "front": "**Def**: A large quantity of (informal).\n**Farsi**: مقدار زیادی، خروارها (عامیانه)",
    "back": "stacks/tons/loads/bags of"
  },
  {
    "id": "45148510-b708-434b-bb84-b1e1a191192d",
    "front": "**Def**: Approximately; with a small degree of inaccuracy.\n**Farsi**: کم و بیش، با چند دقیقه اختلاف",
    "back": "give or take a few minutes"
  },
  {
    "id": "d7d48e2e-de7f-487b-a7f6-25ca9d4a8fe6",
    "front": "**Def**: Similar to that idea or concept.\n**Farsi**: چیزی در آن حدود، شبیه آن",
    "back": "along those lines"
  },
  {
    "id": "5469497c-6edf-447a-bbfd-ddae1c8cb6f7",
    "front": "**Def**: Approximately; nearly (used especially for numbers and times).\n**Farsi**: حدود، تقریباً",
    "back": "round about"
  },
  {
    "id": "7b4d2a51-5854-4e69-abc4-a2fb5fd9a4e5",
    "front": "**Def**: Somewhat depressed (informal approximation).\n**Farsi**: تا حدودی افسرده",
    "back": "kind of depressed"
  },
  {
    "id": "c4dc4aed-e80a-417a-a2a5-6c60a50a8579",
    "front": "**Def**: Connected with; related to (approximation).\n**Farsi**: مربوط به، ربطی داشتن به",
    "back": "something to do with"
  },
  {
    "id": "7e745a9b-460d-4576-9b8e-b7905fb3b017",
    "front": "**Def**: Approximately fifty people; a little more than fifty.\n**Farsi**: حدود پنجاه نفر، پنجاه و خرده‌ای",
    "back": "fifty-odd people"
  },
  {
    "id": "aa7fc4d3-3b3a-4e79-9c62-3a617e840ef5",
    "front": "**Def**: Approaching 80 years old.\n**Farsi**: نزدیک به ۸۰ سال",
    "back": "getting on for 80"
  },
  {
    "id": "61047c91-2686-411b-951d-40516441971c",
    "front": "**Def**: Approximately; near that number, amount, or time.\n**Farsi**: حدوداً، تقریباً",
    "back": "thereabouts"
  }
]